<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1751</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:30:07Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:30:07Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-07-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-07-13T20:54:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2732</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-07-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murphy, Christopher [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Christopher</firstName>
        <lastName>Murphy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001277</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Blumenthal, Richard [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Blumenthal</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-07-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-10-15T18:31:06Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</strong></p> <p>Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to states, units of local government, and Indian tribes for the development, implementation, and evaluation of handgun purchaser licensing requirements. Directs the Attorney General to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible applicants whose applications are approved to assist them in implementing and improving handgun purchaser licensing programs.</p> <p>Directs a state, local government, or tribe, to be eligible to receive a grant, to submit to the Attorney General an application that meets specified requirements, including a description of: (1) the law that the applicant has enacted to require a license for any purchase of a handgun, including exemptions to such law; and (2) how the applicant will use the grant to carry out or improve its program.</p> <p>Requires an applicant, to be eligible for a grant, to have in effect handgun purchaser licensing laws that:</p> <ul> <li>require an applicant for a handgun license or permit to be at least 21 years old and to be a national or lawful permanent resident of the United States;</li> <li>require such an individual to apply for the license or permit at a law enforcement agency in the state in which he or she resides, to reapply for an issued license after a period not longer than five years, and to submit to a background investigation and a criminal history check;</li> <li>require such an individual to submit fingerprints and photographs in connection with the application and to provide proof that the individual is legally present and lawfully resides in the United States; and</li> <li>bar any individual who is prohibited from possessing a firearm under the federal criminal code from receiving a license or permit. </li> </ul> <p>Requires a grantee to use such grant to improve its handgun purchaser licensing programs.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for a grant program for handgun licensing programs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Handgun Purchaser Licensing Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-07-13T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s1751is/xml/BILLS-114s1751is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-07-13</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
