<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3472</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:59Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:59Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-11-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-11-17T20:26:34Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000577</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lee, Mike [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Lee</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-12-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rubio, Marco [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Marco</firstName>
        <lastName>Rubio</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-12-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001098</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cruz, Ted [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ted</firstName>
        <lastName>Cruz</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-12-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-03-20T19:20:46Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Bureau of the Census, for each of FY2017-FY2027, in order to more accurately determine the extent of poverty in the United States and the anti-poverty effectiveness of federal means-tested benefit and tax programs, to conduct a new survey of income and poverty in the United States and supplement and verify the information obtained using data from the most recent available Current Population Survey (CPS), data furnished by state and federal agencies that administer such benefits, and income tax data. </p> <p>The Bureau shall produce tables and graphs showing for each year the poverty rates and related data calculated using the survey responses and other data collected, including:</p> <ul> <li> the total family income for survey respondents (the sum of all money income and federal means-tested benefits minus state and federal income and payroll taxes of household members); </li> <li> a breakdown of the amount of income taxes and payroll taxes paid by survey respondents; and </li> <li> for 2018 and subsequent years, poverty rates calculated using updated poverty thresholds.</li> </ul> <p>For 2018 and subsequent years, the Bureau shall adjust the poverty thresholds for determining poverty rates by using the personal consumer expenditure price index.</p> <p>The Bureau shall create a database that contains data from the survey, data from the most recent available CPS, and data furnished by administering agencies. The bill applies specified security, disclosure, and confidentiality restrictions to personally identifiable information obtained under this bill and makes data contained in a response to a survey conducted pursuant to this bill inadmissible as evidence in any court or agency proceeding. </p> <p>The bill requires: (1) state administering agencies to report to federal administering agencies on federal means-tested benefits received by each household, (2) the Bureau to provide summary statistics comparing income levels to consumption habits of respondents to the Consumer Expenditure Survey, and (3) the Government Accountability Office to submit a report comparing the income measure created under this bill to the income measure used by the Bureau for calculating the supplemental poverty measure.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Bureau of the Census to conduct a survey to determine income and poverty levels in the United States in a manner that accounts for the receipt of Federal means-tested benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Poverty Measurement Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-11-17T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3472is/xml/BILLS-114s3472is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
