<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3456</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:30Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:30Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-09-28T23:10:35Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>CVE Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2899</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 263.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Community Partnership Act of 2015</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2369</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-08</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Countering Online Recruitment of Violent Extremists Act of 2016</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2418</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-10-27</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 655.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to build partnerships to prevent violence by extremists.</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2522</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-07-11</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 552.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001288</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Booker, Cory A. [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cory</firstName>
        <lastName>Booker</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murphy, Christopher [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Christopher</firstName>
        <lastName>Murphy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-28</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-12-21T22:43:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Empowering Partners to Counter Violent Extremism Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) the Office for Partnerships Against Violent Extremism (OPAVE), to be headed by an Assistant Secretary.</p> <p>The Assistant Secretary shall be responsible for:</p> <ul> <li>leading DHS efforts to counter violent extremism;</li> <li>developing a digital engagement strategy that expands DHS outreach efforts to counter violent extremist messaging;</li> <li>serving as DHS's primary representative in coordinating countering violent extremism efforts with the CVE Task Force and with other federal agencies and nongovernmental organizations;</li> <li>serving as the primary DHS-level representative in coordinating with the Department of State on international countering violent extremism issues;</li> <li>providing guidance to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) regarding the use of grants made under the Urban Area Security Initiative and the State Homeland Security Grant Program to state, local, and tribal governments under the allowable uses guidelines related to countering violent extremism; </li> <li>developing a plan to expand philanthropic support for domestic efforts related to countering violent extremism; and </li> <li>awarding grants to, or entering into cooperative agreements with, state, local, and tribal governments and institutions of higher education to support the efforts of local communities in the United States to counter violent extremism.</li> </ul> <p> DHS's Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties shall conduct an annual review to ensure that OPAVE's activities that relate to countering violent extremism respect the privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties of all persons.</p> <p>DHS shall submit to Congress a comprehensive DHS strategy and an implementation plan to counter violent extremism in the United States.</p> <p>DHS's Under Secretary for Science and Technology, in coordination with the OPAVE, may: (1) establish one or more countering violent extremism labs, and (2) reprioritize grants to centers for homeland security to fund each lab.</p> <p>DHS and the Department of State shall incorporate into their efforts to combat terrorist recruitment and communications the public testimonials of former or estranged violent extremists. </p> <p> The OPAVE may implement a program that facilitates groups of students at institutions of higher education throughout the world in designing, piloting, implementing, and measuring the success of a social or digital initiative, product, or tool that counters the messaging of terrorist organizations communications and narratives.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Empowering Partners to Counter Violent Extremism Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Empowering Partners to Counter Violent Extremism Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish the Office for Partnerships Against Violent Extremism of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Empowering Partners to Counter Violent Extremism Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-09-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3456is/xml/BILLS-114s3456is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
