<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>687</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:26Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-02-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Pages H547-H548]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. GOSAR:H.R. 687.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article IV of the Constitution provides the authority ofCongress over federal property as a general matter. ArticleIV, Sec. 3 refers to the managerial authority over propertyowned by the Federal Government, and provides in relevantpart:The Congress shall have Power to dispose of and make allneedful Rules and Regulations respecting the Territory orother Property belonging to the United States; . . .By virtue of this enumerated power, Congress has governingauthority over the lands, territories, or other property ofthe United States--and with this authority Congress is vestedwith the power accredited to all owners in fee, the power tosell, lease, dispose,[[Page H548]]exchange, transfer, trade, mine, or simply preserve land. Theappropriate acreage to be held under Federal dominance is notthe subject of this bill. Turning to the power of Article IV,Sec. 3, the Supreme Court has described this enumerated grantas one ``without limitation'' Kleppe v. New Mexico, 426 U.S.529, 542-543 (1976) (``And while the furthest reaches of thepower granted by the Property Clause have not yet beendefinitively resolved, we have repeatedly observed that`[t]he power over the public land thus entrusted to Congressis without limitations' '' Citing United States v. SanFrancisco, 310 U.S. 29. The Court in Kleppe further explainedthat ``In short, Congress exercises the powers both of aproprietor and of a legislature over the public domain.'' Id.Like any ``propiretor'' Congress has the power to sell orexchange federal property.It is now generally accepted that the Federal Governmentmay own and manage property in the manner and form mandatedby Congress. United States v. Gratiot, 39 U.S. 526 (1840);Camfield v. United States, 167 U.S. 518 (1897). However, thewisdom of the Federal Government owning large tracts of land,particularly in the Western States, is subject to question onpolicy grounds, and some contend on Constitutional groundsbased on the decision in Pollard's Lessee v. Hagan, 44 U.S.212 (where the Court stated that ``a proper examination ofthis subject will show that the United States never held anymunicipal sovereignty, jurisdiction, or right of soil in andto the territory of which Alabama or any of the new Stateswere formed, except for temporary purposes . . . .''Historically, the early federal government transferredownership of federal property to either private ownership orto state ownership in order to pay off the then crushingRevolutionary War debts and to assist with the development ofinfrastructure. These are still acceptable goals for federalproperty sale or transfer.The land exchange here is one that comports with goodpolicy and constitutional strictures since by exchanging theland set forth in this bill, a large commercial grade coppermine will be able to proceed with the attendant economicbenefits with which such a proposition inures (assumingcompliance with other requirements set forth in the bill),but the Federal Government also gains equally valuable landthat has significance for other purposes.Article 1, Sec. 8, Cl. 17 addresses property ceded by astate and conveys exclusive regulatory federal jurisdictionover these federal properties and enclaves. Section 8, Cl, 17may also provide some guidance here to the extent it grantsCongress the power to ``exercise like Authority over allPlaces purchased by the Consent of the Legislature of theState in which the Same shall be, for the Erection of Forts,Magazines, Arsenals, dock-Yards and other needfulBuildings.'' But it is Article IV that this bill is groundedupon.</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Discharged from</name>
                <date>2013-05-15T19:24:20Z</date>
              </item>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2013-02-21T16:13:12Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii06</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Mineral Resources Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Discharged from</name>
                <date>2013-05-15T19:24:01Z</date>
              </item>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2013-03-21T15:20:10Z</date>
              </item>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2013-02-21T16:13:20Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2013-07-22T23:14:02Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2013-05-15T19:24:55Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-02-14T15:02:00Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 113-167</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>339</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-11-20</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-342.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 687) to facilitate the efficient extraction of mineral resources in southeast Arizona by authorizing and directing an exchange of Federal and non-Federal land, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1526) to restore employment and educational opportunities in, and improve the economic stability of, counties containing National Forest System land, while also reducing Forest Service management costs, by ensuring that such counties have a dependable source of revenue from National Forest System land, to provide a temporary extension of the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3102) to amend the Food and Nutrition Act 2008; and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>351</number>
        <type>HRES</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-09-19</actionDate>
          <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
          <actionTime>15:56:02</actionTime>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:35:50</actionTime>
        <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 687 as unfinished business.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32700</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:35:40</actionTime>
        <text>On motion the the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32341</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:35:14</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Hastings (WA) moved the the Committee now rise.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32340</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:58:58</actionTime>
        <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:57:38</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Napolitano amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Napolitano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:49:12</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Napolitano Part A amendment No. 3.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:48:14</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ben Ray Lujan (NM) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ben Ray Lujan (NM) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:36:20</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ben Ray Lujan (NM) Part A amendment No. 2.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:35:10</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grijalva amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grijalva demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:27:29</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 351, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grijalva Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>13:34:44</actionTime>
        <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 687.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>13:34:29</actionTime>
        <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lee Terry to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32400</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>13:33:42</actionTime>
        <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 351 and Rule XVIII.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32020</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>13:32:43</actionTime>
        <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 687, H.R. 1526 and H.R. 3102. Measures will be considered read.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
        <actionTime>13:32:38</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 351. (consideration: CR H5848-5863; text of an amendment in the nature of a substitute: CR H5854-5856)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-09-18</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:32:26</actionTime>
        <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 351 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 687, H.R. 1526 and H.R. 3102. Measures will be considered read.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H1L210</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 121.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <calendarNumber>
          <calendar>U00121</calendar>
        </calendarNumber>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-167.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-22</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 113-167.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 19.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-03-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii06</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Mineral Resources Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii06</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Mineral Resources Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000565</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Gosar, Paul A. [R-AZ-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>Paul</firstName>
        <lastName>Gosar</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000368</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Kirkpatrick, Ann [D-AZ-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ann</firstName>
        <lastName>Kirkpatrick</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>1</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000018</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Salmon, Matt [R-AZ-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>MATT</firstName>
        <lastName>SALMON</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001183</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Schweikert, David [R-AZ-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Schweikert</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Franks, Trent [R-AZ-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Trent</firstName>
        <lastName>Franks</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Arizona</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historical and cultural resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian lands and resources rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mining</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-02-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-02-27T20:31:16Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013 - Authorizes and directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) (the Secretary), if Resolution Copper Mining, LLC offers to convey specified parcels of non-federal land in Gila, Yavapi, Maricopa, Coconino, Pinal, and/or Santa Cruz Counties, Arizona, that are acceptable to the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, to convey certain federal land in Pinal County, Arizona, to Resolution Copper. </p> <p>Makes the federal lands available to Resolution Copper for use for mining and related activities. </p> <p> Requires the Secretary, if so requested by Resolution Copper, to issue <times> separate special use permits to it <times> to carry out mineral exploration activities: (1) under the Oak Flat Withdrawal Area from existing drill pads outside the Area, if they would not disturb the surface of the area; and (2) within the Withdrawal Area (with the exception of within the Oak Flat Campground), if they are conducted from a single exploratory drill pad which is located to minimize visual and noise impacts on the Campground. </times></times></p> <p>Makes lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act part of the National Forest within which the land is located. </p> <p> Adds certain of the non-federal land acquired by the Secretary of the Interior in Pinal and Santa Cruz Counties to the San Pedro Riparian and Las Cienegas National Conservation Areas, respectively.</p> <p>Instructs Resolution Copper to surrender, without compensation, the rights held by it under mining and other U.S. laws to commercially extract minerals under Apache Leap. <times> </times> </p> <p>Requires Resolution Copper to make value adjustment payments to the United States based upon locatable minerals produced from the federal land in Pinal County, Arizona. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to issue to Resolution Copper special use permits that allow it to carry out underground activities (other than the commercial extraction of minerals) under the surface of Apache Leap that would not disturb the surface. </p> <p>Requires preparation of a management plan for Apache Leap. </p> <p> Directs the Secretary to convey <times> specified lands in Pinal County to the town of Superior, Arizona. </times> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>17</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-07-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-09-19T20:27:25Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013 - (Sec. 4) Authorizes and directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) (the Secretary), if Resolution Copper Mining, LLC offers to convey specified parcels of non-federal land in Gila, Yavapi, Maricopa, Coconino, Pinal, and/or Santa Cruz Counties, Arizona, that are acceptable to the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, to convey certain federal land in Pinal County, Arizona, to Resolution Copper. </p> <p>Instructs the Secretary to engage in government-to-government consultation with affected Indian tribes on issues related to the land exchange. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements for appraisals of the federal and non-federal land. Makes the appraisals of the land to be exchanged available for public review. </p> <p>Requires an appraisal prepared under this Act to include an income capitalization approach analysis of the market value of the federal land, which may be utilized, as appropriate, for determining such land's value, and to be the basis for the calculation of any value adjustment payment under section 6 of this Act. </p> <p>Requires the values of the land to be exchanged under this Act to be equal or equalized, as specified.</p> <p>Makes the federal lands available to Resolution Copper for use for mining and related activities. </p> <p> Requires the Secretary, if so requested by Resolution Copper, to issue <times> separate special use permits to it <times> to carry out mineral exploration activities: (1) under the Oak Flat Withdrawal Area from existing drill pads outside the Area, if they would not disturb the surface of the area; and (2) within the Withdrawal Area (with the exception of within the Oak Flat Campground), if they are conducted from a single exploratory drill pad which is located to minimize visual and noise impacts on the Campground. </times></times></p> <p>Terminates the authorization to undertake such activities in the Oak Flat Withdrawal Area when the Withdrawal Area land is conveyed to Resolution Copper. </p> <p>Requires Resolution Copper to agree to pay, without compensation, costs that are associated with the land exchange and any environmental review document completed pursuant to this section and agreed to by the Secretary. </p> <p>Expresses the intent of Congress that the land exchange under this Act be completed within one year of enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Instructs Resolution Copper to submit a proposed mine plan of operations before starting production in commercial quantities of any valuable mineral from the federal land conveyed under this Act, with the exception of any production from exploration and mine development shafts, adits, and tunnels needed to determine the feasibility and pilot plant testing of production or to access the ore body and tailing deposition areas. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary, within three years of such submission, to complete preparation of an environmental review document in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA), to be used as the basis for all decisions regarding any federal actions or authorizations related to the proposed mine and mine plan, including for the construction of associated power, water, and other ancillary facilities. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires Resolution Copper, upon receipt of title to the federal land, to convey to the Secretary and Secretary of the Interior the non-federal land that was determined to be acceptable to them. </p> <p>Makes lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act part of the National Forest within which the land is located. </p> <p>Adds certain of the non-federal land in Pinal County acquired by the Secretary of the Interior to the San Pedro Riparian National Conservation Area. Requires updating of the Conservation Area's management plan to reflect the management requirements of the acquired land. </p> <p>Requires certain of the non-federal land in Gila and Pinal Counties acquired by the Secretary of the Interior (Dripping Springs) to be managed according to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 and applicable land use plans. </p> <p>Adds certain of the non-federal land in Santa Cruz County acquired by the Secretary of the Interior to the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area. </p> <p>Instructs Resolution Copper to surrender, without compensation, the rights held by it under mining and other U.S. laws to commercially extract minerals under Apache Leap. <times> </times> </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Directs Resolution Copper to file annually with the Secretary of the Interior a report that indicates the quantity of valuable locatable minerals produced in commercial quantities from the federal land. Requires Resolution Copper to make value adjustment payments to the United States based upon locatable minerals produced from such land. Requires such Secretary to make such reports available to the state of Arizona. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in this section from modifying, expanding, diminishing, amending, or otherwise affecting any state law related to the imposition, application, timing, or collection of a state excise or severance tax. </p> <p>Requires funds paid to the United States under this section to be deposited in a special fund established in the Treasury and made available to the Secretaries to be used to maintain, repair, and rehabilitate projects for Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management (BLM) assets. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) Withdraws Apache Leap and land acquired by the United States under this Act from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to manage Apache Leap so as to preserve its natural character and to protect the archaeological and cultural resources located on it. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to issue to Resolution Copper special use permits that allow it to carry out underground activities (other than the commercial extraction of minerals) under the surface of Apache Leap that would not disturb the surface. </p> <p>Requires preparation of a management plan for Apache Leap. </p> <p>Prohibits this section's provisions from imposing additional restrictions on mining activities carried out by Resolution Copper adjacent to, or outside of, the Apache Leap area beyond those otherwise applicable to mining activities on privately owned land. </p> <p> (Sec. 9) Revokes any public land order that withdraws the federal land from appropriation or disposal under a public land law to the extent necessary to permit the disposal of such land. </p> <p>Withdraws from entry and appropriation without further action required by the Secretary the federal land or any federal interest in the non-federal land to be exchanged under section 4 of this Act, if not already withdrawn or segregated from entry and appropriation under a public land law (including mining and mineral leasing laws and the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970). </p> <p>Terminates such withdrawal: (1) upon the completion of the land exchange, or (2) if Resolution Copper notifies the Secretary in writing that it has elected to withdraw from such exchange. </p> <p>Prohibits anything in this Act from interfering with, limiting, or otherwise impairing the unpatented mining claims or rights currently held by Resolution Copper on the federal land or in any way changing, diminishing, qualifying, or otherwise impacting Resolution Copper's rights and ability to conduct activities on such land under such claims and U.S. general mining laws.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To facilitate the efficient extraction of mineral resources in southeast Arizona by authorizing and directing an exchange of Federal and non-Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>478</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>An amendment numbered 3 printed in Part A of House Report 113-215 to protect water quality and water quantity for the people living and working near this proposed mine, given estimates that mining operations will consume the equivalent of the annual water supply for 20,000 homes.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment sought to protect water quality and water quantity for the people living and working near this proposed mine, given estimates that mining operations will consume the equivalent of the annual water supply for 20,000 homes.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:52:17Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the Napolitano amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 217 (Roll no. 490).</text>
          <actionTime>15:35:01</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 490</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll490.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>N000179</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Napolitano, Grace F. [D-CA-32]</fullName>
            <firstName>GRACE</firstName>
            <lastName>NAPOLITANO</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>CA</state>
            <middleName>F.</middleName>
            <district>32</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2013-09-26T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>113</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>687</number>
          <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>8</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:35:01</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the Napolitano amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 217 (Roll no. 490).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>490</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:35:01Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll490.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:49:09</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mrs. Napolitano. (consideration: CR H5860-5862, H5862-5863; text: CR H5860)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:49:09</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mrs. Napolitano.(consideration: CR H5860-5862, H5862-5863; text: CR H5860)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:35:01</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>490</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:35:01Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll490.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:35:01</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Napolitano amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 191 - 217 (Roll no. 490).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>490</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:35:01Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll490.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:35:01</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>77000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>490</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:35:01Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll490.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>477</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 113-215 to require the Secretary to remove Native American sacred and cultural sites from the conveyance in consultation with affected Indian Tribes.</description>
        <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 113-215 to require the Secretary to remove Native American sacred and cultural sites from the conveyance in consultation with affected Indian Tribes.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:52:17Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM). (consideration: CR H5857-5860; text: CR H5857)</text>
          <actionTime>14:36:15</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>H5857</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-159/house-section/page/H5857</url>
            </link>
            <link>
              <name>H5857-5860</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-159/house-section/page/H5857-5860</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>L000570</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Lujan, Ben Ray [D-NM-3]</fullName>
            <firstName>Ben</firstName>
            <lastName>Lujan</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>NM</state>
            <middleName>R.</middleName>
            <district>3</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2013-09-26T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>113</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>687</number>
          <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>House Report 113-215</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/113th-congress/house-report/215</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <actions>
          <count>4</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:36:15</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM). (consideration: CR H5857-5860; text: CR H5857)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:36:15</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Lujan, Ben Ray (NM).(consideration: CR H5857-5860; text: CR H5857)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>476</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 113-215 to guarantee the jobs this mine does create benefit the local community by requirin g that the Remote Operating Center be located in the town of Superior, Arizona or an adjacent mining community.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment sought to require that the Remote Operations Center be located in the town of Superior, Arizona, or adjacent to another mining community within the Copper Triangle.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:52:17Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 227 (Roll no. 489).</text>
          <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 489</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>G000551</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Grijalva, Raúl M. [D-AZ-3]</fullName>
            <firstName>Raúl</firstName>
            <lastName>Grijalva</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>AZ</state>
            <middleName>M.</middleName>
            <district>3</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2013-09-26T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>113</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>687</number>
          <title>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2013</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>9</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 227 (Roll no. 489).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>489</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:26:02Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:26:33</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Grijalva. (consideration: CR H5856-5857, H5862; text: CR H5856)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>14:26:33</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Grijalva.(consideration: CR H5856-5857, H5862; text: CR H5856)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 227 (Roll no. 489).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>489</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:26:02Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>77000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>489</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:26:02Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Grijalva amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 227 (Roll no. 489).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>489</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:26:02Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:26:02</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>489</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>113</congress>
                  <date>2013-09-26T19:26:02Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2013/roll489.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported in House</type>
        <date>2013-07-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr687rh/xml/BILLS-113hr687rh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-02-14T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr687ih/xml/BILLS-113hr687ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-09-26</actionDate>
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 687 as unfinished business.</text>
      <actionTime>15:35:50</actionTime>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
