<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>37</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:26:19Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:26:19Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-01-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2013-07-30T18:27:38Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2014-05-22T20:01:01Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2013-12-19T14:30:00Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-01-22T17:36:18Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-165</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-22</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 391.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-165.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-22</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Landrieu with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 113-165.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-30</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg03</systemCode>
            <name>Public Lands, Forests, and Mining Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 113-85.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-01-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-01-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000243</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Baucus, Max [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>MAX</firstName>
        <lastName>BAUCUS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <middleName>SIEBEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-02-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000818</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Walsh, John E. [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Walsh</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-03-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Montana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Outdoor recreation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Watersheds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-01-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-01-31T14:20:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013 - Establishes the Montana Forest Jobs and Restoration Pilot Initiative under which the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall implement authorized forest and watershed restoration projects and other land management projects on certain eligible lands within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Kootenai National Forests in Montana to achieve the specified purposes of the Initiative and specified performance requirements. </p> <p>Permits the inclusion of the Seeley Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest within the Initiative. </p> <p>Requires the identification of one or more collaborative groups or resource advisory committees for each national forest within the Initiative. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to: (1) annually implement one or more authorized forest and watershed restoration projects on the eligible lands; (2) implement, in one or more certain watershed areas, those projects that provide landscape-scale work in order to minimize watershed entries; and (3) enter into stewardship contracts or agreements to carry out authorized forest and watershed restoration projects. </p> <p>Designates specified lands administered by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Montana as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). </p> <p>Releases: (1) certain BLM wilderness study areas from further study for designation as wilderness, and (2) the Sapphire and West Pioneer Wilderness Study Areas from further study for inclusion as components of the NWPS. </p> <p>Designates specified federal lands in Montana as special management or recreation management areas. </p> <p>Requires a specified all-terrain vehicle study and report. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-05-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-10-06T20:20:22Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013 - <b>Title I: Montana Forest Jobs and Restoration Initiative - </b>(Sec. 103) Establishes the Montana Forest Jobs and Restoration Pilot Initiative to sustain the economic development and recreational use of National Forest System land and other public land in Montana. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Chief of the Forest Service, to implement forest and watershed restoration projects and other land management projects on certain eligible lands within the Beaverhead-Deerlodge and Kootenai National Forests. </p> <p>Establishes performance requirements directing the Secretary to place under contract for treatment of vegetation a specified acreage annually in the Beaverhead-Deerlodge National Forest and the Kootenai National Forest. Requires the treatments to: (1) reduce the density of trees in a project area or reduce hazardous fuels (reducing or modifying living and dead vegetation to protect against the risk of wildfires); (2) be accomplished through the cutting of vegetation with mechanized equipment or by hand with a power saw; and (3) yield products that have a commercial value in local markets. Prohibits the use of prescribed fire to accomplish the qualified treatments of vegetation required. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to seek to meet the majority of the performance requirements for the Kootenai National Forest by placing under contract land within the Three Rivers District. Authorizes the Secretary to place Kootenai National Forest land in the Libby District, the Rexford District, or the Cabinet District under contract to meet performance requirements.</p>  <p> <p>Applies administrative and judicial review provisions from the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to Initiative projects. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to submit compliance and progress reports to Congress. </p> <p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary from diverting funding from a National Forest or grassland located outside of Montana to meet the performance requirements. Permits the Secretary to reprogram funds appropriated for the National Forest System and allocated to be used on eligible land. </p> <p>Permits the Secretary to include the Seeley Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest within the Initiative if specified conditions are met. </p> <p>Terminates the Initiative on the later of 15 years after enactment of this Act or when performance requirements have been achieved. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) Directs the Secretary to annually implement one or more of the projects. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to implement in one or more watershed areas projects providing landscape-scale work with the goal of minimizing entries into the watershed. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary to enter into stewardship contracts or agreements to carry out the projects. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to give priority to carrying out projects in areas: (1) in which the road density exceeds 1.5 miles per square mile, (2) in the wildland-urban interface that are at risk of wildfire that would threaten public infrastructure or private property, (3) in which fish and wildlife habitat connectivity is compromised as a result of past management practices, and (4) that contain forests identified on the National Insect and Disease Risk Map as having a significant risk of tree mortality. </p> <p>Requires an environmental review of projects to be carried out under provisions for hazardous fuel reduction projects set forth in the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003, with specified exceptions. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to develop an aquatic and riparian habitat protection strategy to modify conservation requirements in existing forest plans if the modifications would meet or exceed existing protection requirements. </p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary from constructing permanent roads under this Act unless specified conditions are met. Requires the Secretary to: (1) decommission any temporary road constructed to carry out the land management project, and (2) decommission certain National Forest System roads and unauthorized roads. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to design projects to produce commercial and noncommercial wood products. </p> <p> <p> <p><b>Title II: Designation of Wilderness and Special Management Areas in Montana</b> - (Sec. 203) Designates specified lands administered by the Forest Service or the BLM in Montana as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Transfers jurisdiction over specified public land administered by the BLM to the Secretary of Agriculture and incorporates the land in the East Pioneers Wilderness.</p> <p>Sets forth provisions for the management of the wilderness areas regarding the incorporation of acquired land and interests; fire, insects, and diseases; access to private land; fish and wildlife; livestock grazing; outfitting and guide activities; and water impoundment structures. </p> <p>Withdraws the land designated as wilderness from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. </p> <p>  <p>  <p>Provides for continued motorized access to maintain water infrastructure for cattle to protect fluvial Arctic Grayling and other aquatic species in the Ruby River within the Snowcrest Wilderness Area. Permits the trailing of sheep across the area to reach existing grazing allotments in the Gravelly Mountains. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Releases certain BLM wilderness study areas from further study for designation as wilderness areas, and releases the Sapphire and West Pioneer Wilderness Study Areas from further study for inclusion as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>(Sec. 207) Designates specified federal lands in Montana as special management or recreation management areas. </p>  <p>Withdraws the land from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials. </p> <p>Restricts timber harvesting in the designated areas. </p> <p> <p>Sets forth area-specific management requirements, including requirements related to motorized and mechanized recreational vehicles and campground development, for: (1) the Highland Special Management Area; (2) the Lost Creek, Thunderbolt, and West Pioneers Recreation Management Areas; (3) the Otatsy Recreation Management Area; (4) the Three Rivers and Roderick Special Management Areas; (5) the Snowcrest Special Management Area; (6) Tobacco Roots Recreation Management Area; and (7) the West Big Hole Recreation Management Area. </p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires a study on: (1) the opportunities for expanded all-terrain vehicle roads and trails across the Three Rivers District and adjacent areas on the Kootenai National Forest, (2) the interconnectedness of roads on private or state land, and (3) the opportunities for expanded access points to existing trails. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Forest Jobs and Recreation Act of 2013</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to sustain the economic development and recreational use of National Forest System land and other public land in the State of Montana, to add certain land to the National Wilderness Preservation System, to release certain wilderness study areas, to designate new areas for recreation, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2014-05-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s37rs/xml/BILLS-113s37rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-01-22T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s37is/xml/BILLS-113s37is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-05-22</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 391.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
