<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1098</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:36:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:36:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-05-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-05-11T19:30:28Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-05-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-05-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000444</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Flake, Jeff [R-AZ]</fullName>
        <firstName>JEFF</firstName>
        <lastName>FLAKE</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal procedure and sentencing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Veterans Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee hiring</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee performance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health personnel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' medical care</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-05-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-12-08T22:31:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) from: (1) hiring or transferring to any VA position a person who has been convicted of a state or federal criminal offense that substantially relates to the position and for which the minimum prison term is more than one year; or (2) employing a person in a VA position who, after enactment of this bill, is convicted of such a criminal offense.</p> <p>Such prohibition shall not apply: </p> <ul> <li>to a conviction of a state or federal criminal offense if the records of such conviction have been expunged, </li> <li>to a conviction of a state or federal criminal offense if during the 10-year period beginning on the date of such conviction the person has not been convicted of any other criminal offense for which the minimum prison term is more than one year, or </li> <li>if the person is being hired or transferred as part of a program to help veterans who have been convicted of a state or federal criminal offense for which the minimum prison term is more than one year. </li> </ul> <p>The VA: (1) may not employ, transfer, or hire an individual for specified medical positions who has had a related license or credential revoked or suspended; and (2) shall begin the process of terminating current employees who have had such licenses or credentials revoked or suspended.</p> <p>The Merit Systems Protection Board shall issue a decision on an appeal for termination review within 30 days of an employee's notification of termination.</p> <p>The VA shall provide information about an individual's disciplinary action to the appropriate state medical licensing boards and to the National Practitioner Databank.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from employing individuals who have been convicted of a felony and medical personnel who have had their medical licenses or credentials revoked or suspended, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Clean Up the Department of Veterans Affairs Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-05-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s1098is/xml/BILLS-115s1098is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-05-11</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
