<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>88</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:01Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:01Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HJRES</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-10-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. TERRY:H.J. Res. 88.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:clause 3 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution.____________________[Page H6289]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
        <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-10-04T14:00:39Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
            <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000459</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Terry, Lee [R-NE-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>LEE</firstName>
        <lastName>TERRY</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NE</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense spending</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Defense</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military education and training</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-10-10T18:33:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States Service Academies Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014 - Makes appropriations, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for operations of the U.S. Military, Naval, Air Force, Coast Guard, and Merchant Marine academies for FY2014, and for other purposes, such amounts as may be necessary, at a rate for operations as provided for in the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-6), for projects or activities for the continuing operations of such academies not otherwise specifically provided for in the Pay Our Military Act (P.L. 113-39), that were conducted in FY2013, and for which appropriations, funds, or other authority were made available to the Department of Defense (DOD) by the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013, in the following accounts: </p> <ul> <li>U.S. Military Academy, &quot;Department of Defense--Operation and Maintenance, Army&quot;;</li> <li>U.S. Naval Academy, &quot;Department of Defense--Operation and Maintenance, Navy&quot;;</li> <li>U.S. Air Force Academy, &quot;Department of Defense--Operation and Maintenance, Air Force&quot;;</li> <li> Coast Guard Academy, &quot;Department of Homeland Security--Coast Guard--Operating Expenses&quot;; and</li> <li> U.S. Merchant Marine Academy, &quot;Department of Transportation--Maritime Administration--Operations and Training.&quot;</li> </ul> <p>Requires the rate of operations to be calculated to reflect the full amount of any reduction required in FY2013 pursuant to: (1) the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2013, and (2) the presidential sequestration order dated March 1, 2013, except as attributable to budget authority made available by the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (P.L. 113-2). </p> <p>Makes appropriations and funds made available and authority granted under this joint resolution available until whichever of the following first occurs: (1) enactment into law of an appropriation for any project or activity provided for in this joint resolution, (2) enactment into law of the applicable appropriations Act for FY2014 without any provision for such project or activity, or (3) December 15, 2013. </p> <p>Requires implementation of this joint resolution so that only the most limited funding action be taken in order to provide for continuation of projects and activities.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States Service Academies Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States Service Academies Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Making continuing appropriations for operations of the United States Military Academy, the United States Naval Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, the Coast Guard Academy, and the United States Merchant Marine Academy for fiscal year 2014.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States Service Academies Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2014</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-10-04T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hjres88ih/xml/BILLS-113hjres88ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-10-04</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
