<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4766</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:26:25Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:26:25Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-05-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. GARDNER:H.R. 4766.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8[Page H5023]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsas02</systemCode>
            <name>Military Personnel Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2014-06-20T17:26:51Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-05-29T14:00:42Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr09</systemCode>
            <name>Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2014-06-16T13:59:24Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-05-29T14:00:37Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsas02</systemCode>
            <name>Military Personnel Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr09</systemCode>
            <name>Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-29</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-29</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000562</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Gardner, Cory [R-CO-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cory</firstName>
        <lastName>Gardner</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000470</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Tipton, Scott  R. [R-CO-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>Scott</firstName>
        <lastName>Tipton</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <district>3</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000564</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lamborn, Doug [R-CO-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>Doug</firstName>
        <lastName>Lamborn</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000571</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lummis, Cynthia M. [R-WY-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cynthia</firstName>
        <lastName>Lummis</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>WY</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <district>0</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-05-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Veterans Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability assistance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' pensions and compensation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-05-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-07-18T19:10:26Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Prohibits the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from paying any Senior Executive Service employee an award or bonus until the Secretary certifies to Congress that the backlog of disability claims within the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has been resolved. <p>Establishes a commission or task force within the VA to: (1) study the backlog of veterans' disability compensation claims, including possible improvements to the claims process, and the anticipated increase in appeals of those claims, including possible improvements to the appeals process; (2) submit to the Secretary, the Chairman of the Board of Veteran's Appeals, and the Chief Judge of the U.S. Court of Veterans Claims remedies and solutions to the backlog of such claims and appeals; and (3) submit initial, interim, and final reports to the President and Congress regarding its findings and recommendations. Requires the Secretary, Chairman, or Chief Judge to implement the remedies and solutions he or she deem appropriate. </p> <p> Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress, within 60 days after this Act's enactment and every 120 days thereafter until May 25, 2015, a supplemental report on the VA's implementation of the Strategic Plan to Eliminate the Compensation Claims Backlog, including verification that during the period covered by the report each claim was approved or denied within 125 days with a 98% accuracy rate.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements to ensure that the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration and the Secretary of Defense (DOD) transfer to the VA, within 30 days of the Secretary's request, disability or medical records that the VA Secretary will use to evaluate a disability compensation claim. Requires the VA and Defense Secretaries to submit to Congress and implement a plan to reduce to 30 days the time needed to provide members of the National Guard and the Secretary with the medical records of Guard members.</p> <p> Requires the VA Secretary to establish a two-year training program for newly-hired VA claims processors.</p> <p> Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to report to Congress on the Secretary's progress in improving the timeliness of claims processing and eliminating the claims backlog. Requires the report to include any recommendations the Comptroller General has to improve the Secretary's progress.</p> <p> Directs the Secretary, in processing veterans' disability compensation claims, to provide priority to veterans: </p> <ul> <li> who have attained age 70; </li> <li> who are terminally ill; </li> <li> with life-threatening illnesses; </li> <li> who are homeless; </li> <li> who were awarded the Medal of Honor; </li> <li> who are former prisoners of war; </li> <li> whose claims are being re-reviewed in relation to a previously denied claim relating to military sexual trauma; and </li> <li> whom the Secretary determines, on a case-by-case basis, either are seriously or very seriously injured or should be given priority based on an application for good cause established by the Secretary.</li> </ul> <p> Directs the Secretary to maintain on the VA's website publicly accessible information concerning pending and completed claims of compensation for a veteran's service-connected disability or death, including the number of claims pending and completed, and the average number of days between submission and completion, for certain periods. Requires the information provided to be updated at least every seven days.</p> <p> Directs the Secretary to include in the VA's annual report to Congress on its activities and costs information on: </p> <ul> <li> the automatic processing of veterans disability compensation claims, </li> <li> the performance of any regional office that fails to meet its administrative goals regarding timeliness and accuracy in the processing of such claims, and </li> <li> the timeliness with which the Secretary receives information requested from other federal agencies that the Secretary requires in adjudicating claims for compensation regarding a veteran's service-connected disability or death. </li> </ul> <p> Directs the Secretary to post notices of average times for the processing of veterans' disability compensation claims, as well as the percentage of claims approved, in a conspicuous place in each VA regional office and claims intake facility and on the VA's website. Requires the Secretary to notify each person submitting a claim of such information and of the person's eligibility to receive up to an extra year of benefit payments upon filing an original claim that is fully developed. Requires the notice information to be updated at least quarterly. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from paying bonuses to certain employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs until the backlog of disability claims is resolved, to establish a commission to evaluate such backlog, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from paying bonuses to certain employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs until the backlog of disability claims is resolved, to establish a commission to evaluate such backlog, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from paying bonuses to certain employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs until the backlog of disability claims is resolved, to establish a commission to evaluate such backlog, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2014-05-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr4766ih/xml/BILLS-113hr4766ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-06-20</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
