<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1161</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:40Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:40Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-06-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-06-13T17:28:19Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Conservation Act of 2013</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>3099</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-12-04</actionDate>
          <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>SHARE Act of 2013</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>3197</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-10-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000550</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Landrieu, Mary L. [D-LA]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARY</firstName>
        <lastName>LANDRIEU</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000437</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wicker, Roger F. [R-MS]</fullName>
        <firstName>Roger</firstName>
        <lastName>Wicker</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MS</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-06-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alabama</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fishes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Florida</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gulf of Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Louisiana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and inland water transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mississippi</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Texas</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-06-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-08-26T21:09:22Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Conservation Act of 2013 - Directs the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission to prepare, adopt, and submit to the Secretary of Commerce a fishery management plan providing for the conservation and management of Gulf of Mexico red snapper and specifying the requirements necessary for Gulf coastal states (Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas) to comply with such plan. </p> <p>Requires the Commission to ensure an opportunity for public participation in the preparation of the plan. </p> <p>Prohibits such plan, for a three-year period, from reducing the overall quota of Gulf of Mexico red snapper apportioned to commercial fishing, except in the event of a reduction in stock in which case the quota shall be reduced to ensure a sustainable harvest. Permits an increase in quota based on stock assessments. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to determine whether the plan includes fishery management measures compatible with the national standards in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act and to certify whether the plan properly conserves and manages Gulf of Mexico red snapper. </p> <p>Requires each Gulf coastal state to submit to the Commission appropriate management measures to ensure compliance with the conservation objectives of the fishery management plan. Directs the Commission, upon certifying that the states have submitted sufficient measures, to certify to the Secretary to revoke federal management of Gulf of Mexico red snapper. Directs the states to manage the Gulf of Mexico red snapper in the adjacent coastal waters consistent with the fishery management plan.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary, upon receiving the management measures certification from the Commission, to publish notice in the Federal Register revoking regulations and portions of the federal fishery management plan for the Reef Fish Resources of the Gulf of Mexico that conflict with the plan for Gulf of Mexico red snapper, including the deletion of the species from the management unit. </p> <p>Directs the Commission to determine at least annually whether state enforcement is satisfactory and to notify the Secretary of each negative determination. </p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to close the fishery within federal waters adjacent to such a state upon receiving notice of a negative determination or a report that the state has not implemented any necessary measures to end overfishing, rebuild fisheries, or provide for data collection to monitor harvests. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to report biennially to Congress on the economic impacts and benefits for the local, regional, and national economy of the Gulf of Mexico red snapper fishery. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Conservation Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Conservation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the development of a fishery management plan for the Gulf of Mexico red snapper, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Gulf of Mexico Red Snapper Conservation Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-06-13T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1161is/xml/BILLS-113s1161is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-06-13</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
