<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3357</number>
    <updateDate>2022-09-03T17:24:54Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-09-03T17:24:54Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2020-02-27</introducedDate>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2020-02-27T18:48:49Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-02-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-02-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sherrod</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Child health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Food assistance and relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immunology and vaccination</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nutrition and diet</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Poverty and welfare assistance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women's health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2020-02-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-03-22T17:05:32Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>WIC Enrollment Collaboration Act of 2020</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to report on the extent to which pregnant women, postpartum women (not more than one year postpartum), infants, and young children receiving benefits under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) or Medicaid benefits are certified to participate in the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, Children (WIC). </p> <p>The report must include for each state (1) the monthly average of participants that received benefits under SNAP or Medicaid in the preceding year and for Medicaid purposes are a member of a family whose income was less than maximum income limit for free and reduced price meals, and (2) the percentage of participants that received benefits under SNAP or Medicaid who were certified to receive WIC.</p> <p>Additionally, each state must implement an annual cross-enrollment plan that includes (1) goals for increasing the percentage of participants that received benefits under SNAP or Medicaid who were certified to receive WIC in the preceding year; (2) measures the state will carry out to achieve those goals, including by making improvements or modifications to information systems, data matching, or enhancing referrals; and (3) a time line for the state to implement such measures.</p> <p>USDA must award competitive grants to states to implement a cross-enrollment plan in the state or to increase the percentage of such participants who were certified to receive WIC. Additionally, USDA must provide technical or training assistance to the states to increase the percentage.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>WIC Enrollment Collaboration Act of 2020</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>WIC Enrollment Collaboration Act of 2020</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>WIC Enrollment Collaboration Act of 2020</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to enhance State efforts to cross-enroll participants to improve nutritional outcomes for pregnant women, postpartum women, and young children, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2020-02-27T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116s3357is/xml/BILLS-116s3357is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2020-02-27</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
