<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1873</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:23:32Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:23:32Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-12-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-12-19T23:14:26Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Protect Student Borrowers Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>5565</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-11-17</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9062-9063)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reed, Jack [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Reed</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000563</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Durbin, Richard J. [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Durbin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-12-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000817</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warren, Elizabeth [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Elizabeth</firstName>
        <lastName>Warren</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-12-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murphy, Christopher [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Christopher</firstName>
        <lastName>Murphy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-04-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-03-13T21:49:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Protect Student Borrowers Act of 2013 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) participating in the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan program to accept specified risk-sharing requirements.</p> <p>Requires an IHE, for any fiscal year in which at least 25% of the IHE's student body is participating in the Direct Loan program, to remit, at such times as the Secretary of Education specifies, a risk-sharing payment set at: </p> <ul> <li> 20% of the total amount of its defaulted Direct loans if its cohort default rate is 30% or higher, </li> <li> 15% of the total amount of its defaulted Direct loans if its cohort default rate is lower than 30% but not lower than 25%, </li> <li> 10% of the total amount of its defaulted Direct loans if its cohort default rate is lower than 25% but not lower than 20%, and </li> <li> 5% of the total amount of its defaulted Direct loans if its cohort default rate is lower than 20% but not lower than 15%.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary to make specified modifications to such risk-sharing requirements if an IHE develops and implements a student loan management plan that is approved by the Secretary. Requires that plan to include individualized financial aid counseling for students and strategies to minimize student loan default and delinquency.</p> <p>Allows the Secretary to waive or reduce an IHE's risk-sharing payments in certain other instances.</p> <p>Prohibits IHEs from denying admission or financial aid to a student based on a perception that the student may be at risk for defaulting on a Direct loan.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts or cooperative agreements for: (1) statewide or institutionally-based programs for the prevention of federal student loan delinquency and default at IHEs that have a high cohort default rate or serve large numbers or percentages of students who have a higher risk of defaulting on student loans under title IV, and (2) increasing the number of borrowers who successfully rehabilitate defaulted loans</p> <p>Establishes a separate account in the Treasury for the deposit of the risk-sharing payments, of which: (1) up to 50% are to be used by the Secretary to enter into the contracts or cooperative agreements for delinquency and default prevention or rehabilitation, and (2) the remainder are to be used to offset any future shortfalls in funding under the Federal Pell Grant program.</p> <p>Makes an IHE's ability to meet its obligation to make risk-sharing payments part of the determination of its eligibility to participate in title IV programs.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Protect Student Borrowers Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Protect Student Borrowers Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for institutional risk-sharing in the Federal student loan programs.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Protect Student Borrowers Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-12-19T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1873is/xml/BILLS-113s1873is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-12-19</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
