<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1595</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:30:41Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:30:41Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-06-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-06-17T19:01:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>3962</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-04</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S4251-4252)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <lastName>Wyden</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001041</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Heller, Dean [R-NV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Dean</firstName>
        <lastName>Heller</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-06-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Aviation and airports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-06-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-07-24T19:59:09Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</b></p> <p>Prohibits a federal entity from using unmanned aircraft&nbsp;or other mobile aerial-view devices (MAVDs) to: (1)&nbsp;surveil property, persons, or their effects; or&nbsp;(2) gather evidence pertaining to known or suspected criminal conduct, or conduct that violates a statute or regulation.</p> <p>Sets forth exceptions that allow MAVDs to be used by federal entities to:</p> <ul> <li>surveil national borders to prevent or deter illegal entry of persons or illegal substances; </li> <li>prevent imminent danger of death or serious bodily harm to a specific individual, counter an imminent risk of a terrorist attack by a specific individual or organization, prevent imminent destruction of evidence, or counter an imminent or actual escape of a criminal or terrorist suspect; </li> <li>monitor or research environmental, geologic, or weather-related damage and events, including forest fires, erosion, floods, wildlife, habitats, or illegal vegetation on public lands; or </li> <li>acquire information about an individual who consents to the use of an MAVD. </li></ul> <p>Allows law enforcement parties to use an MAVD to surveil specific property, persons, or their effects pursuant to a search and seizure warrant. </p> <p>Prohibits a federal entity actor from making an intentional effort to identify an individual from, or associate an individual with, the information collected under certain exceptions to the prohibition on the use of MAVDs. Bars disclosure of collected information except to another federal entity or state, tribal, or local government agency that agrees to be bound by the restrictions in this Act.</p> <p>Prohibits federal entities from: (1) soliciting or awarding contracts to surveil by MAVD for a federal entity, unless the federal entity has existing authority for such surveillance; or (2) purchasing information obtained from MAVD surveillance by a nonfederal entity if such information contains personal information, except with the consent of the affected persons.</p> <p>Prohibits this Act from being construed to preempt any state law regarding the use of MAVDs exclusively within the borders of that state.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to describe the authority under which Federal entities may use mobile aerial-view devices to surveil, protect individual and collective privacy against warrantless governmental intrusion through the use of mobile aerial-view devices, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Protecting Individuals From Mass Aerial Surveillance Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-06-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s1595is/xml/BILLS-114s1595is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-06-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S4251-4252)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
