<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2996</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:30:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:30:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-07-09</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 161, Number 106 (Thursday, July 9, 2015)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. HARDY:H.R. 2996.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8 of the United States Constitution,specifically Clause 1 (relating to providing for the commondefense and general welfare of the United States) and Clause18 (relating to the power to make all laws necessary andproper for carrying out the powers vested in Congress) andArticle I, Section 10, Clause 3 (relating to interstatecompacts).[Page H5030]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
        <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
            <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2015-07-10T16:39:59Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-07-09T14:01:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Emergency Wildfire and Forest Management Act of 2016</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2647</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 634.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hspw13</systemCode>
            <name>Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hspw00</systemCode>
            <name>Transportation and Infrastructure Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001070</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Hardy, Cresent [R-NV-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cresent</firstName>
        <lastName>Hardy</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-09</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-10-15T17:39:23Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to define a "major disaster for wildfire on federal lands" as any wildfire that, in the determination of the President, warrants assistance under this Act to supplement the efforts and resources of the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture: (1) on federal lands, or (2) on non-federal lands pursuant to a fire protection agreement or cooperative agreement.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to submit a request to the President for a declaration that such a major disaster exists. Requires such a request to: </p> <ul> <li>certify that the amount appropriated in the current fiscal year for wildfire suppression operations of the federal land management agencies under the jurisdiction of the respective Secretary, net of any concurrently enacted rescissions of wildfire suppression funds, increases the total unobligated balance of amounts available for wildfire suppression by an amount equal to or greater than the average total costs incurred by such agencies per year for wildfire suppression operations over the previous 10 fiscal years; </li> <li>certify that the amount available for wildfire suppression operations of the federal land management agencies under the jurisdiction of the respective Secretary will be obligated not later than 30 days after such Secretary notifies the President that wildfire suppression funds will be exhausted to fund ongoing and anticipated wildfire suppression operations related to the wildfire on which such request is based; and </li> <li>specify the amount required in the current fiscal year to fund wildfire suppression operations related to the wildfire on which such request is based. </li></ul> <p>Authorizes the President to: (1) declare that such a major disaster exists based on such a request, (2) establish a specific account for assistance pursuant to such a declaration, and (3) transfer funds from such account to the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct wildfire suppression operations on such lands. Requires the respective Secretary to secure reimbursement of transferred amounts used for wildfire suppression operations on non-federal land.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish wildfire on Federal lands as a major disaster.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish wildfire on Federal lands as a major disaster.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish wildfire on Federal lands as a major disaster.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2015-07-09T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr2996ih/xml/BILLS-114hr2996ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-07-10</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
