<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5791</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 114 (Thursday, July 14, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. PRICE of North Carolina:H.R. 5791.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 1 of the Constitution providesCongress with the authority to ``make all Laws which shall benecessary and proper'' to provide for the ``general Welfare''of Americans. In the Department of Education Organization Act(P.L. 96-88), Congress declared that ``the establishment of aDepartment of Education is in the public interest, willpromote the general welfare of the United States, will helpensure that education issues receive proper treatment at theFederal level, and will enable the Federal Government tocoordinate its education activities more effectively.'' TheDepartment of Education's mission is to ``promote studentachievement and preparation for global competitiveness byfostering educational excellence and ensuring equal access[Page H5012]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed13</systemCode>
            <name>Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2016-09-19T14:42:00Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-07-14T13:10:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed13</systemCode>
            <name>Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
            <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000523</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Price, David E. [D-NC-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>DAVID</firstName>
        <lastName>PRICE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Athletes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School athletics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sports and recreation facilities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-04-12T14:40:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Standardization of Collegiate Oversight of Revenues and Expenditures Act or the SCORE Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require each coeducational institution of higher education (IHE) that is participating in a title IV program and has an intercollegiate athletic program to include in its annual report on its intercollegiate athletic program: (1) the amount of revenue generated by each item on a list of categorized sources, disaggregated by each sports team; and (2) the expenses attributable to each item on a list of categorized activities or obligations, disaggregated by each sports team.</p> <p>The bill prohibits an IHE from being a member of any intercollegiate athletic association or participating in any national intercollegiate athletics competition organized by any person, unless the association or person annually reports and disaggregates by sport, athletic event, or contract, as applicable: (1) the total generated revenue and amount of revenue generated by each item on a list of categorized sources, (2) the amount of expenses attributable to each item on a list of categorized activities or obligations, and (3) executive compensation schedules.</p> <p>The Department of Education (ED) must: (1) define the categories of information that must be reported; and (2) biannually review and, as necessary, update each definition in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles or significant changes in the national system of intercollegiate athletics. </p> <p>ED must: (1) appoint a task force made up of representatives from division I, II, and III schools in the National Collegiate Athletic Association, and (2) consult with the task force when reviewing or updating the definitions.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>SCORE Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>SCORE Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>SCORE Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Standardization of Collegiate Oversight of Revenues and Expenditures Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to report revenue generated by each sports team, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5791ih/xml/BILLS-114hr5791ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
