<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2299</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:38:53Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:38:53Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2018-01-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2018-01-11T19:07:39Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-01-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-01-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000039</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Tom [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2018-01-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2018-01-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2018-11-15T22:03:27Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Wildfire Regulatory Relief Act of 2018</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Department of Agriculture to allow harvesting, grazing, or other commercial use of the forage on conservation reserve program lands when a governor declares a state of emergency.</p> <p>The bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act) to require the President, in evaluating a major disaster declaration request, to consider any impacts of the disaster that: (1) will impede the recovery efforts of affected individuals or the community; and (2) may not be addressed under disaster programs administered by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) but are addressed by other disaster programs.</p> <p>The bill amends the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to require FEMA to include within the emergency management performance grants program grants supporting joint interagency cooperation between state agencies responsible for responding to wildfires.</p> <p>Not later than 15 days after the President declares a major disaster under the Stafford Act, or after a state of emergency is declared by a governor, the appropriate federal banking agencies and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall issue guidance to depository institutions located in the disaster area for reducing regulatory burdens for borrowers and communities to facilitate recovery from the disaster.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Wildfire Regulatory Relief Act of 2018</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Wildfire Regulatory Relief Act of 2018</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to provide wildfire regulatory relief, to modify the evaluation of a major disaster declaration request, to provide regulatory relief for banks during major disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Wildfire Regulatory Relief Act of 2018</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2018-01-11T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s2299is/xml/BILLS-115s2299is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2018-01-11</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
