<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1831</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:33:54Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:33:54Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-05-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. BENTIVOLIO:H.R. 1831.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:(1) Article I, section 5, clauses 2 and 3 to determine therules and to keep a journal of its proceedings, respectively;(2) Article I, section 7, clause 2 to ensure that billsthat become law have been actually passed by, not just passedthrough, each House of Congress; and(3) Article I, section 8, clause 18, which authorizesCongress to make all laws that are necessary and proper forcarrying into execution the rules of each House.Furthermore, the provision of this Act under which anyperson who is aggrieved by the enforcement of any law enactedeither in violation of the rules of proceedings of eitherHouse of Congress, or by the suspension of such rules, asprescribed herein, shall have standing in a court of law, ispursuant to article III, section 2 of the Constitution of theUnited States.[Page H2437]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju10</systemCode>
            <name>Constitution and Limited Government Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2013-06-14T17:01:47Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-05-06T16:00:17Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
        <name>Rules Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-05-06T16:00:22Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Read the Bills Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1665</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-11-07</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju10</systemCode>
            <name>Constitution and Limited Government Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
            <name>Rules Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2409)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001280</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Bentivolio, Kerry L. [R-MI-11]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kerry</firstName>
        <lastName>Bentivolio</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>11</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000937</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Stockman, Steve [R-TX-36]</fullName>
        <firstName>STEVE</firstName>
        <lastName>STOCKMAN</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>36</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-05-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Constitution and constitutional amendments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>House of Representatives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-05-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-06-03T19:53:34Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Read the Bills Act - Requires any bill or resolution introduced in either chamber of Congress to contain a provision citing the specific powers granted to Congress in the Constitution to enact the proposed measure, including all of its provisions.</p> <p>Requires any measure introduced in either chamber, designed to amend or modify the effect of, or which would have such an effect, any current provision of law, including its expiration date, to set forth: (1) the amendments being proposed by the bill; and (2) the current section of law as it would read as modified by such amendments, showing deleted text struck through and inserted text underlined.</p> <p>Prohibits the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate from accepting legislation if it is noncompliant with these requirements.</p> <p>Applies such requirements to any legislation presented for consideration on the floor of either chamber.</p> <p>Prohibits any noncompliant measure from being submitted for a vote on final passage.</p> <p>Prohibits either chamber of Congress jointly from waiving or modifying these requirements.</p> <p>Requires any amendment to a measure introduced in either chamber to set forth the current section of the legislation as it would read as modified by the amendment, showing deleted text struck through and inserted text underlined.</p> <p>Sets forth the same requirements and/or prohibitions for such amendments as those specified in this Act regarding the text of legislation setting forth current law. </p> <p>Bars a vote on final passage of a measure (except private bills) from occurring in either chamber, unless: (1) the full text of the measure, or original language and all adopted amendments to the same effect, is published at least seven days before the vote on the official public Internet website of the Office of the Clerk or the Office of the Secretary, as appropriate; and (2) public notice of the specific calendar week during which the vote is scheduled to take place is posted on the respective website within six days before the Monday of such week.</p> <p>Requires a roll call vote on final passage of a measure (except a private bill) in either chamber.</p> <p>Excludes from these requirements any measure which constitutes a declaration of war.</p> <p>Declares that an Act of Congress noncompliant with this Act shall have no force or effect. Bars any legal, equitable, regulatory, civil, or criminal action from being brought under such Act.</p> <p>Grants the following aggrieved individuals the right to bring an action against the United States to seek appropriate relief, including an injunction against the enforcement of any law, the passage of which did not conform to this Act: (1) persons aggrieved by an action of any federal officer or employee, and (2) Members of Congress.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Read the Bills Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Read the Bills Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Read the Bills Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To preserve the constitutional authority of Congress and ensure accountability and transparency in legislation.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-05-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr1831ih/xml/BILLS-113hr1831ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-06-14</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
