<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3482</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:59Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:59Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-11-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
        <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Other</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-11-17T23:15:37Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian claims</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian lands and resources rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Utah</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water resources funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use and supply</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Native Americans</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-10-05T19:17:26Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill (1) ratifies the Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Agreement negotiated between the Navajo Nation, the United States, and Utah; and (2) satisfies the claims of the tribe for water rights and injury to water rights under all laws with respect to the Navajo Nation Reservation.</p> <p>The bill enumerates Navajo Nation's right to use water from water sources located within Utah and adjacent to or encompassed within the the boundaries of the reservation resulting in depletion of no more than 81,500 acre-feet annually.</p> <p>The Bureau of Reclamation (Reclamation) must plan, design, and construct the water diversion, delivery, and conservation features of the Navajo water development projects. Reclamation must convey title to those Navajo water development projects described as water supply and water distribution systems once they are complete, in operation, and if applicable, delivering potable water.</p> <p>The Department of the Interior must facilitate the formation of a project management committee to review cost factors and budgets and improve management of the Navajo water development projects.</p> <p>The bill establishes: (1) the Navajo Operation, Maintenance, and Replacement (OM&amp;R) Trust Account for the operation, maintenance, and replacement of the Navajo water development projects authorized to be constructed and described in the agreement as water supply systems and water distribution systems; and (2) the Navajo Water Development Fund to plan, design, and construct the Navajo water development projects.</p> <p>The bill outlines waivers, releases, and retentions of claims by the Navajo Nation and the United States under the agreement.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to approve the settlement of the water rights claims of the Navajo Nation in Utah, to authorize construction of projects in connection therewith, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-11-17T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3482is/xml/BILLS-114s3482is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-11-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
