<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2278</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:32:34Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:32:34Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-11-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-11-10T22:36:57Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-11-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-11-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal Communications Commission (FCC)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-11-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-03-31T21:59:19Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015 </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to ensure that spectrum allocation and assignment produces a balance between radio frequency bands available for: (1) exclusive licensing through an auction, and (2) unlicensed operations on a nonexclusive basis without the expectation of protection from interference. </p> <p>The FCC must consider whether to adopt rules that permit unlicensed operations in spectrum assigned by auction until the licensee brings the spectrum into use by initiating commercial service. </p> <p>The bill declares that it is the policy of the United States to:</p> <ul> <li> maximize the utility of the spectrum resources of the United States,</li> <li>advance innovation and investment in wireless broadband services, and </li> <li>promote a balanced spectrum policy that makes adequate spectrum resources available for both licensed and unlicensed technologies.</li> </ul> <p>The FCC must consult with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to develop a national strategy for making additional radio frequency bands available for unlicensed operations. The strategy must: (1) identify proposed radio frequency bands to be cleared of incumbent users; (2) ensure that consumers have access to additional low-, mid-, and high-band frequencies for unlicensed operations; and (3) consider rules and other ways to promote spectrum sharing and improve spectrum utilization.</p> <p>The NTIA, in conjunction with the FCC and the Office of Management and Budget, must submit to Congress a report on the steps necessary to designate additional radio frequency bands used by federal entities for unlicensed operations without causing harmful interference to government operations. The report must consider the impact on homeland security or national security communications and include recommendations to ensure the solvency of the Spectrum Relocation Fund. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote the availability of additional unlicensed spectrum for innovation and investment, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Promoting Unlicensed Spectrum Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-11-10T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2278is/xml/BILLS-114s2278is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-11-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
