<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>626</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:34:57Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:34:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-03-20</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-03-20T21:39:52Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-03-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-03-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000033</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Sanders, Bernard [I-VT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bernard</firstName>
        <lastName>Sanders</lastName>
        <party>I</party>
        <state>VT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug therapy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>HIV/AIDS</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care costs and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Insurance industry and regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intellectual property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marketing and advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prescription drugs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>User charges and fees</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-03-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-05-28T19:56:58Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS Act - Denies any person the exclusive right to manufacture, distribute, sell, or use in interstate commerce a qualifying treatment for HIV/AIDS, or to a manufacturing process for such a treatment, including the exclusive right to rely on health registration data or the 30-month stay-of-effectiveness period for Orange Book patents. Prescribes remuneration, in the form of prize payments from a Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS, in lieu of such market exclusivity.</p> <p>Exempts from this elimination of exclusive rights any dual use product that is a qualifying treatment for HIV/AIDS which also has a significant use for other diseases, but only with respect to its use for other diseases. Applies the elimination of exclusive rights with respect to a qualifying HIV/AIDS treatment even in a dual use product.</p> <p>Establishes the Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to designate a Prize Fund Director to administer the Fund.</p> <p>Directs the Prize Fund Director to award prize payments for medical innovation relating to a qualifying treatment for HIV/AIDS, or a new manufacturing process for such a treatment, to: (1) the first person to receive market clearance with respect to the drug or biological product; (2) the holder of the patent with respect to a manufacturing process; or (3) persons or communities that as an open source contribution openly shared knowledge, data, materials, and technology on a royalty-free and nondiscriminatory basis.</p> <p>Allows the Prize Fund Director to authorize multiple nonprofit intermediaries to manage Fund payments to reward projects for: (1) interim research and development of new qualifying treatments for HIV/AIDS, or (2) open source dividend prizes.</p>  <p>Establishes an annual fee for health insurers to fund this Act.</p> <p>Establishes the Donor Innovation Prize Fund to enable the Secretary to reward owners and developers of products that permit open competition for low-cost generic drugs for the treatment of HIV/AIDS in developing countries.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Prize Fund for HIV/AIDS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to de-link research and development incentives from drug prices for new medicines to treat HIV/AIDS and to stimulate greater sharing of scientific knowledge.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-03-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s626is/xml/BILLS-113s626is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-03-20</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
