<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1439</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:23:24Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:23:24Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-08-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-08-01T20:02:43Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000055</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Isakson, Johnny [R-GA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Johnny</firstName>
        <lastName>Isakson</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-08-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aging</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Cancer</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Digestive and metabolic diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and health-based discrimination</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health facilities and institutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Home and outpatient care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Neurological disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nursing</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-11-12T20:18:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Care Planning Act of 2013 - Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to cover advanced illness planning and coordination services furnished to an eligible individual with progressive illness, including Alzheimer's disease, by a hospice or other provider through an interdisciplinary team.</p> <p>Amends SSA title XI with respect to the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation and its selection for Phase I testing of innovative payment and service delivery models to reduce Medicare and Medicaid expenditures while preserving or enhancing the quality of care. Adds a model for payments to providers that furnish advanced illness care coordination services to eligible individuals who are entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under Medicare part A (Hospital Insurance) and enrolled under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance), but not enrolled under Medicare part C (Medicare+Choice).</p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), in awarding grants, contracts, or agreements under provisions for quality measure development, to give priority to the development of quality measures that allow the assessment of various specified factors including the effectiveness, patient-centeredness (and, where relevant, family caregiver-centeredness), and accuracy of care plans, including documentation of individual goals, preferences, and values.</p> <p>Amends SSA title XVIII (Medicare) to require inclusion of information on advanced care planning materials in the &quot;Medicare and You Handbook.&quot;</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a Care Planning Advisory Board.</p> <p>Revises requirements for the use under Medicare and Medicaid of advanced directives, portable treatment orders, and other treatment directions from an individual or legally authorized representative.</p> <p>Amends the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 with respect to advanced directives.</p> <p>Establishes additional requirements under Medicare for hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, home health agencies, and hospice programs with respect to completion before discharge of care plan documentation.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to certain entities to: (1) develop online training modules, decision support tools, and instructional materials for individuals, family caregivers, and health care providers; (2) establish a website and telephone hotline to disseminate such resources and any materials designed by the HHS Center for Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships for faith communities; and (3) conduct a national public education campaign to raise public awareness of advance care planning and advanced illness care. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to study state and regional activities with respect to storing completed advance directives and portable treatment orders.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General (GAO) to study the provisions of, and amendments made by, this Act, including the quality associated with them.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Care Planning Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Care Planning Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for advanced illness care coordination services for Medicare beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Care Planning Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-08-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1439is/xml/BILLS-113s1439is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
