<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>329</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:28:25Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:28:25Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-02-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2015-06-10T18:08:34Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2015-12-16T18:05:07Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2015-11-19T14:30:00Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-02-02T21:38:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 114-182</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>646</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-03-16</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 327.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment. With written report No. 114-182.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment. With written report No. 114-182.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg04</systemCode>
            <name>National Parks Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-338.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-02-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-02-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001169</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murphy, Christopher [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Christopher</firstName>
        <lastName>Murphy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001277</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Blumenthal, Richard [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Blumenthal</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-02-02</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-01-19T16:26:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 329, Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/51150</url>
        <description>As reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on December 16,&amp;nbsp;2015</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Connecticut</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lakes and rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-02-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-05-19T18:12:02Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage: (1) the river segments in accordance with the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Management Plan, dated June 2011; and (2) coordinate the management responsibilities of the Secretary under this Act <times/> relating to such segments with the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic Committee. </p> <p>Makes the provisions of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act prohibiting federal acquisition of lands by condemnation applicable to the designated segments. Limits the authority of the Secretary to acquire lands for the purposes of such segments to acquisition by donation or with the owner's consent and subject to additional management plan criteria. </p> <p>Prohibits the designation made by this Act from being construed as: (1) prohibiting, pre-empting, or abridging the potential future licensing of the Rainbow Dam and Reservoir (including any and all aspects of its facilities, operations, and transmission lines) by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) as a federally licensed hydroelectric generation project; or (2) affecting the operation of, or imposing any flow or release requirements on, the unlicensed hydroelectric facility at the Dam and Reservoir. </p> <p>Bars the Lower Farmington River from being administered as part of the National Park System or being subject to System regulations.</p> <p>Revises the description of a specified designated segment of the Farmington River in Connecticut.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-01-13T20:10:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Department of the Interior shall manage: (1) the river segments according to the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Management Plan, dated June 2011; and (2) coordinate the management responsibilities of Interior under this Act <times/> relating to such segments with the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic Committee. </p> <p>Authorizes Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with: (1) the state of Connecticut; (2) the towns of Avon, Bloomfield, Burlington, East Granby, Farmington, Granby, Hartland, Simsbury, and Windsor in Connecticut; and (3) appropriate local planning and environmental organizations. </p>  <p>For purposes of the segments designated by this Act, the zoning ordinances adopted by the towns, including provisions for the conservation of floodplains, wetlands, and watercourses associated with such segments, shall be deemed to satisfy the Act's standards and requirements limiting or prohibiting federal acquisition of lands by condemnation. </p> <p> The authority of Interior to acquire lands for the purposes of such segments shall be limited to acquisition by donation or with the owner's consent and shall be subject to additional management plan criteria. </p> <p> The designation made by this Act shall not be construed to prohibit, pre-empt, or abridge the potential future licensing or re-licensing of the Rainbow Dam and Reservoir (including any and all aspects of its facilities, operations, and transmission lines) by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) as a federally licensed hydroelectric generation project, provided that FERC may, in its discretion and consistent with this Act, establish any terms and conditions in a hydropower license for the Dam as necessary to reduce impacts that invade or unreasonably diminish the scenic, recreational, and fish and wildlife values of the designated segments. Neither shall the designation affect the operation of, or impose any flow or release requirements on, the unlicensed hydroelectric facility at the Dam and Reservoir. </p> <p> The Lower Farmington River shall not be administered as part of the National Park System or be subject to System regulations.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill also revises the description of a specified designated segment of the Farmington River in Connecticut.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Farmington River and Salmon Brook in the State of Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2015-12-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s329rs/xml/BILLS-114s329rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-02-02T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s329is/xml/BILLS-114s329is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 327.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
