<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6497</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:54Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:54Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-12-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 177 (Thursday, December 8, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. CARTER of Georgia:H.R. 6497.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18The Congress shall have Power to make all Laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by theConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.[Page H7570]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-12-08T14:06:15Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001103</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Carter, Earl L. "Buddy" [R-GA-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Earl</firstName>
        <lastName>Carter</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <middleName>L. "Buddy"</middleName>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-12-27T21:19:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>TSA Screening Transparency and Accountability Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), consistent with the General Accountability Office's November 2015 report on the Screening Partnership Program (SPP), to update its cost estimating methodology for federal cost estimates and cost comparisons to conform to certain minimum leading cost estimating best practices, including by:</p> <ul> <li>incorporating a cost estimate that reflects the total cost to the federal government, including costs incurred by federal agencies other than TSA;</li> <li>ensuring all TSA cost estimates are adjusted for inflation over the duration of the contract;</li> <li>updating all cost estimates when circumstances at a SPP airport result in a significant change to a contract's value;</li> <li>including an analysis that identifies which variables have the greatest effect on cost estimates; and </li> <li>reflecting the inherent uncertainty associated with the cost estimate and identifying the elements of the estimate that present the most risk.</li> </ul> <p> TSA shall make the update available to the public.</p> <p> TSA shall develop a streamlined method and standard protocol for documenting, tracking, and resolving customer complaints for both federal and SPP airport checkpoints.</p> <p>TSA shall make available to airport directors, managers, and other individuals in similar positions cleared to handle sensitive security information an assessment of each airport's security screening performance compared to the mean average performance for all equivalent airports.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>TSA Screening Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>TSA Screening Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To require screening transparency and accountability of the TSA, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>TSA Screening Transparency and Accountability Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-12-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr6497ih/xml/BILLS-114hr6497ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
