<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2808</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:29Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:29Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-07-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. MATHESON:H.R. 2808.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article IV, Section 3, Clause 2 of the U.S. Constitution[Page H5051]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2013-07-29T13:06:57Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-07-24T14:01:05Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii10</systemCode>
            <name>Federal Lands Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001142</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Matheson, Jim [D-UT-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>JIM</firstName>
        <lastName>MATHESON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Outdoor recreation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Utah</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use and supply</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-07-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-09-27T21:45:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Wasatch Wilderness and Watershed Protection Act - Designates specified federal lands in the vicinity of the Lone Peak Wilderness and the Mount Olympus Wilderness, and specified federal lands comprising the Wayne Owens Grandeur Peaks/Mount Aire Wilderness within the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forests in Salt Lake County, Utah, as wilderness and as either a new component or as an addition to an existing component of the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p> <p>Establishes specified federal lands within the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forests as the Mt. Aire, Mt. Olympus, Twin Peaks, and Lone Peak Special Management Areas. </p> <p>Requires the Special Management Areas to be managed to maintain their presently existing wilderness character and potential for inclusion in the System.</p> <p> Allows the commercial helicopter-assisted skiing and snowboarding activities (known as heliskiing) that have been authorized on the federal lands included within the Special Management Areas to continue. Permits the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), except as provided below, upon the expiration of such an authorization that was in effect for heliskiing, to reissue such authorizations in accordance with Forest Service procedures. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, within one year from the time in which all heliskiing activities within any special management area are no longer authorized or have otherwise been terminated, to publish a notice in the Federal Register to that effect. Designates the federal lands included within such an Area for which such a notice has been published as wilderness and adds them <times> to the System as described in this Act. <times> </times></times></p> <p>Requires a land exchange involving certain federal and non-federal lands concerning the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forests. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Wasatch Wilderness and Watershed Protection Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Wasatch Wilderness and Watershed Protection Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To designate certain National Forest System land in the Uinta-Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Salt Lake County, Utah, as wilderness, to facilitate a land exchange involving certain land in such National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Wasatch Wilderness and Watershed Protection Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-07-24T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr2808ih/xml/BILLS-113hr2808ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-07-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Public Lands and Environmental Regulation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
