<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5015</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:43:48Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:43:48Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2020-12-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2020-12-15T21:13:36Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-12-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-12-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001267</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bennet, Michael F. [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Bennet</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2020-12-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-04-25T19:12:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Outdoor Restoration Force Act of 2020</b> </p> <p>This bill establishes an Outdoor Restoration Fund to carry out restoration and resilience projects. </p> <p>The bill establishes the Restoration Fund Advisory Council. The council shall (1) disburse amounts for the restoration and resilience project grant program established by this bill; and (2) gather public input and provide recommendations to the Department of the Interior, the Department of Agriculture (USDA), and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for the use of the fund for the restoration and resilience partnership established by this bill.</p> <p>The council shall coordinate with at least one existing regional entity, or a regional entity established by the council, in a specific geographic region to assist with the grant program. </p> <p>Amounts in the fund shall be made available to Interior, USDA, and the EPA to supplement their existing budgets for efforts that (1) enhance forest and watershed health through fuel reduction, forest restoration, fire mitigation, and road and trail maintenance; (2) support state, private, and Tribal forestry; (3) remediate or reclaim abandoned oil and gas wells, coal mines, and hardrock mines; (4) mitigate, or eradicate, invasive species on public, private, and Tribal land; or (5) enhance carbon sequestration, water resources, and improve wildlife habitats.</p> <p>Until FY2026, the council shall annually perform outreach efforts and solicit public comments on the use of the fund by Interior, USDA, and the EPA for the restoration and resilience partnership.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Outdoor Restoration Force Act of 2020</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Outdoor Restoration Force Act of 2020</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Outdoor Restoration Force Act of 2020</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish an Outdoor Restoration Fund for restoration and resilience projects, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2020-12-15T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116s5015is/xml/BILLS-116s5015is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2020-12-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
