<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>199</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:34:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:34:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-01-31</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-01-31T21:40:18Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-01-31</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S442-443)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-01-31</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S442)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-01-31</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Energy</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic and polar regions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Budget deficits and national debt</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy revenues and royalties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sales and excise taxes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local finance</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Energy</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-01-31</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-02-22T21:24:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to direct the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) require oil produced from federal leases in certain Arctic waters, except in preproduction phases (including explorations), to be transported by pipeline to onshore facilities; and (2) provide for, and issue appropriate permits for, the transportation of oil from such leases in preproduction phases (including exploration) by means other than pipeline. </p> <p>Requires that the state of Alaska receive 37.5% of all revenues derived from all rentals, royalties, bonus bids and other sums payable to the United States from energy development in any area of the Alaska Adjacent Zone, including from all sources of renewable energy leased, developed, or produced in such Zone.</p> <p>Sets forth an allocation scheme under which the Secretary of the Interior is directed to pay: (1) 25% of any allocable state share directly to coastal political subdivisions, (2) 25% of any allocable state share to certain Regional Corporations, and (3) 10% of any allocable state share directly to Indian tribes.</p> <p>Instructs the Secretary to distribute: (1) 15% of certain federal royalty revenues into a specified land and water conservation fund to provide financial assistance to states, and (2) 7.5% of certain federal royalty revenues into direct federal deficit reduction.</p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on bitumen transported into the United States.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Alaska Adjacent Zone Safe Oil Transport and Revenue Sharing Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require that oil produced from Federal leases in certain Arctic waters be transported by pipeline to onshore facilities and to provide for the sharing of certain outer Continental Shelf revenues from areas in the Alaska Adjacent Zone.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-01-31T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s199is/xml/BILLS-113s199is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-01-31</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S442-443)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
