<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1221</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:31:12Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:31:12Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-05-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2015-06-09T14:08:34Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-05-06T22:07:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-06-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-05-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Energy</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electric power generation and transmission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public utilities and utility rates</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Energy</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-05-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-06-16T13:51:39Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Bulk-Power System Reliability Impact Statement Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act to require reliability coordinators registered with the Electric Reliability Organization (ERO) to report to certain congressional committees and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) regarding: </p> <ul> <li> the state of and prospects for the reliability and affordability of electricity within their respective geographic areas, and </li> <li> the most significant risks to the reliability of the bulk-power system that might arise or need to be monitored within such geographic areas, including risks from proposed or final federal regulations.</li> </ul> <p>FERC must: </p> <ul> <li> solicit a reliability impact statement from the affected reliability coordinator within 15 days after a federal agency proposes a major rule that may significantly affect the reliable operation of the bulk-power system, and </li> <li> transmit the coordinator's reliability impact statement to the head of the federal agency for inclusion in the public record. </li> </ul> <p>A reliability coordinator may also submit voluntarily a reliability impact statement for any proposed major federal rule that the coordinator determines would significantly affect the reliable operation of the bulk-power system within the coordinator's jurisdiction.</p> <p>If a proposed rule subject to a reliability impact statement affects an area broader than the jurisdiction of a single reliability coordinator, the ERO must convene a committee of the affected reliability coordinators in order to produce a single statement that demonstrates for each affected area the reliability impact of the proposed rule. </p> <p>When issuing a proposed major rule subject to a reliability impact statement, the head of the federal agency must: </p> <ul> <li> consider the reliability impact statement in issuing the proposed rule, and</li> <li> include in the final rule a detailed response to the reliability impact statement.</li> </ul>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Bulk-Power System Reliability Impact Statement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Bulk-Power System Reliability Impact Statement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to require periodic reports on electricity reliability and reliability impact statements for rules affecting the reliable operation of the bulk-power system.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Bulk-Power System Reliability Impact Statement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-05-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s1221is/xml/BILLS-114s1221is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-06-09</actionDate>
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
