<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1651</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:35:18Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:35:18Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-04-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. PEARCE:H.R. 1651.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 4, Section 3, Clause 2 of the Constitution of theUnited States grants Congress the power to enact this law.[Page H2160]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2013-04-29T20:31:10Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-04-18T14:04:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>284</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-06-27</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 110.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-18</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-04-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000588</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Pearce, Stevan [R-NM-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Stevan</firstName>
        <lastName>Pearce</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water resources funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use and supply</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Water Resources Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-04-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-05-21T20:42:04Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Fort Sumner Irrigation District, located in De Baca County, New Mexico, all works, land, and facilities of the Fort Sumner reclamation project in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement between the United States and the Fort Sumner Irrigation District Concerning Principles and Elements of Proposed Transfer of Title to Fort Sumner Irrigation District Facilities. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary, before carrying out such conveyance, to assure compliance with all applicable requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, the Endangered Species Act of 1973, and any other law applicable to the property conveyed. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress if such conveyance isn't completed within two years after such requirements are met. </p> <p>Terminates, on the date of such conveyance: (1) U.S. interest in and responsibility for the project and liability relating to the conveyed property; (2) a specified repayment contract between the United States and the District dated November 5, 1948; and (3) a specified payment obligation of the United States under the contract between the United States and the District for the forbearance of exercising priority water rights, dated August 21, 2009. Provides that all other terms of such forbearance agreement shall remain in effect for not less than 10 years after this Act's enactment.</p> <p>Provides that after conveyance of title under this Act: (1) the conveyed property shall not be considered to be a part of a federal reclamation project; and (2) the entity to which the property is conveyed shall not be eligible to receive any benefits, including federal project power, with respect to the conveyed property, except for benefits that would be available to a similarly situated entity with respect to property that is not part of a federal reclamation project.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Fort Sumner Project Title Conveyance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To transfer certain facilities, easements, and rights-of-way to Fort Sumner Irrigation District, New Mexico.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-04-18T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr1651ih/xml/BILLS-113hr1651ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-04-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
