<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3479</number>
    <updateDate>2023-03-22T19:51:03Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-03-22T19:51:03Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2018-09-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 115-251.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 115-251.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:02:25</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:02:23</actionTime>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H8754-8758)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:02:23</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H8754-8758)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:54:47</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3479.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:54:45</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H8754-8759)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:54:21</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Arrington moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-24</actionDate>
        <actionTime>11:19:10</actionTime>
        <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H15000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-24</actionDate>
        <actionTime>10:32:24</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-18</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote. (consideration: CR S6254-6258; text: CR S6254-6258)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.(consideration: CR S6254-6258; text: CR S6254-6258)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000055</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Isakson, Johnny [R-GA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Johnny</firstName>
        <lastName>Isakson</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2018-09-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2018-09-19T17:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3479, Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/54482</url>
        <description>As passed by the Senate on September 18, 2018</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <laws>
      <item>
        <type>Public Law</type>
        <number>115-251</number>
      </item>
    </laws>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>49</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2019-09-06T14:34:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p /><b>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</b> <p />This bill extends and otherwise revises specified Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) programs and services, including those related to health care, benefits, and homeless veteran reintegration. <p />TITLE I--EXTENSIONS OF AUTHORITY <p />Subtitle A--Health Care Matters <p />(Sec. 101) The bill extends through FY2020 copayment guidelines for hospital care and nursing home care. <p />(Sec. 102) The bill extends through FY2020 VA authority to provide nursing home care to certain veterans with service-connected disabilities. <p />(Sec. 103) The bill removes appropriations limitations on family caregiver assistance for veterans. <p />(Sec. 104) The bill makes permanent the authority of the VA to recover from a third party the costs of care for a non-service-connected disability. <p />(Sec. 105) VA authority to transfer real property is extended through FY2020. <p />(Sec. 106) The bill extends through FY2020 a pilot program for providing child care for veterans receiving health care. <p />(Sec. 107) The bill extends through FY2020 the VA's grant authority for programs related to rural veteran transportation in connection with the provision of medical care. <p />(Sec. 108) The bill extends through FY2020 a pilot program related to reintegration and counseling in retreat settings for women veterans. <p />(Sec. 109) The bill extends through FY2019 an initiative to assess the feasibility of paying actual travel expenses in connection with veterans receiving care from VA centers. <p />Subtitle B--Benefits Matters <p />(Sec. 121) The bill makes permanent the authority of the VA to assist certain veterans with difficulty ambulating in acquiring and adapting housing with special features. <p />(Sec. 122) The bill extends through FY2020 grants to encourage the development of new assistive technologies for specially adapted housing. <p />(Sec. 123) The bill makes permanent the authority of the VA to guarantee certain mortgage-backed securities. <p />(Sec. 124) The bill makes permanent provisions related to calculating the value of foreclosed property. <p />(Sec. 125) The bill extends through FY2019 the VA's authority regarding property management. <p />(Sec. 126) The bill makes permanent the authority of the VA to provide rehabilitation and vocational benefits for members and former members of the armed services with severe injuries or illnesses. <p />(Sec. 127) The bill extends through FY2020 the agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to research associations between diseases and certain chemical compounds in herbicides. <p />Subtitle C--Homeless Veterans Matters <p />(Sec. 141) The bill extends through FY2020 a program for homeless veteran reintegration. <p />(Sec. 142) The bill extends through FY2020 a reintegration program for homeless women veterans and homeless veterans with children. <p />(Sec. 143) This bill extends through FY2020 referral and counseling services for veterans at risk for homelessness transitioning from institutional living. <p />(Sec. 144) This bill extends through FY2020 programs providing outreach services and other assistance to homeless veterans and veterans with severe mental illness. <p />(Sec. 145) The bill increases the amounts authorized to be appropriated in FY2018 and FY2019 for financial assistance for entities that support very low-income veteran families in permanent housing. <p />(Sec. 146) The bill extends through FY2020 grant programs for homeless veterans with special needs. <p />(Sec. 147) The bill extends through FY2022 the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans. <p />Subtitle D--Other Matters <p />(Sec. 161) The bill extends through FY2020 the authority to transport individuals to and from VA facilities. <p />(Sec. 162) The bill extends through FY2019 the authority for operation of the VA's regional office in Manila, Philippines. <p />(Sec. 163) The bill extends through FY2020 authorization of appropriations for the VA to provide monthly assistance allowances to specified veterans participating in Olympic programs. <p />(Sec. 164) The bill extends through 2020 the VA's reporting requirement regarding equitable relief. <p />(Sec. 165) The bill extends through FY2020 the authorization of appropriations for the Adaptive Sports Program for disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces. <p />(Sec. 166) The bill: (1) extends through FY2022 the Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans, and (2) requires the committee to report on relevant VA activities every other year rather than every year. <p />TITLE II--IMPROVEMENT OF HEALTH CARE FROM DEPARTMENT OF VETERANS AFFAIRS <p />(Sec. 201) The bill provides that modifications to contracts under the Veterans Community Care Program are not subject to specified bid requirements. <p />(Sec. 203) Veterans Care Agreement coverage is expanded to any individual eligible for services through the VA. (The Veterans Care Agreement is a program that provides third-party health care if health care is not feasibly available from a VA facility.) <p />(Sec. 204) The VA is allowed (currently, required) to deduct overpayments from payments owed to a health care entity. The VA may also use other means to collect overpayments. <p />(Sec. 205) The bill expands eligibility for specified mental health services to veterans eligible for, but not enrolled in, VA health care. <p /> (Sec. 206) The bill expands the network of prescription drug monitoring programs accessible to VA health care providers to include state and regional programs not a part of the national network. <p />(Sec. 207) The bill eliminates reporting requirements related to activities contracted out by the VA. <p />(Sec. 208) The VA must complete additional reporting regarding the availability of opioid receptor antagonists (e.g., naloxone). <p />(Sec. 209) The bill expands certain health care assessment reports to include the U.S. Virgin Islands and Puerto Rico. <p />(Sec. 210) The bill authorizes a specified medical facility project in West Los Angeles, California. <p />(Sec. 211) The bill extends a veterans medical school scholarship program to the entering class of 2020. <p />TITLE III--OTHER MATTERS <p />(Sec. 301) An educational institution providing educational benefits to veterans must charge in-state tuition rates for certain veterans entitled to rehabilitation as a condition of the institution's participation in certain VA education benefit programs. <p />(Sec. 302) The bill revises conflict of interest restrictions for VA employees related to educational institutions. Specifically, the bill removes advance notice and hearing requirements regarding conflict waivers, limits the restrictions to those VA employees working on education benefit programs, and reduces the punishment for such activity. <p />(Sec. 303) The bill revises VA authority to enter into certain leases at the West Los Angeles, California, campus. Specifically, in the case of previous mismanagement, the VA may not enter into a new lease or land-sharing agreement until the VA certifies compliance with certain audit reports or evaluations.<p /> <p />]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Enacted</titleType>
        <title>Department of Veterans Affairs Expiring Authorities Act of 2018</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend certain expiring provisions of law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Enrolled Bill</type>
        <date/>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s3479enr/xml/BILLS-115s3479enr.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2018-09-18T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s3479es/xml/BILLS-115s3479es.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Considered and Passed Senate</type>
        <date>2018-09-18T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s3479cps/xml/BILLS-115s3479cps.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date>2018-09-30T03:59:59Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PLAW-115publ251/uslm/PLAW-115publ251.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Public Law</type>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2018-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-251.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
