<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3176</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:15Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:15Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-07-13T16:21:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sherrod</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug therapy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health facilities and institutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infectious and parasitic diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prescription drugs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-07-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-05-10T14:06:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Strategies to Address Antibiotic Resistance Act or the STAAR Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions regarding the Antimicrobial Resistance Task Force.</p> <p>The Presidential Advisory Council on Combating Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria must provide advice, information, and recommendations to the Department of Health and Human Services.</p> <p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must carry out activities to collect data on antibiotic resistance, including assessing conditions and outcomes related to antibacterial resistance and working with others to obtain human antibiotic drug consumption data.</p> <p>The CDC must establish Antibiotic Resistance Surveillance and Laboratory Network sites, including to monitor antibiotic-resistant bacteria, describe and respond to outbreaks, and evaluate resistance testing methods.</p> <p>The National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases must maintain: (1) a Clinical Trials Network on Antibacterial Resistance, and (2) a leadership group to advance a clinical research agenda to address antibacterial resistance.</p> <p>The CDC must work with state and local health departments to support efforts by groups of health care facilities to prevent the spread of antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</p> The CDC and the epicenters participating in the Prevention Epicenters Program must work with others to: (1) evaluate prevention programs and interventions to limit infections in health care facilities, and (2) facilitate research on the prevention and control of resistant organisms. The CDC must use research from the epicenters to create and disseminate educational materials for use in health care facilities.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>STAAR Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>STAAR Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>STAAR Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Strategies to Address Antibiotic Resistance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance efforts to address antibiotic resistance, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-07-13T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3176is/xml/BILLS-114s3176is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-07-13</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
