<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>428</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:34:31Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:34:31Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-02-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-02-28T22:49:02Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic and polar regions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Army Corps of Engineers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coast guard</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Defense</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government trust funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Navigation, waterways, harbors</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-03-18T15:37:03Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Arctic Deep Water Ports Enhancement Act of 2013 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to enter into partnership agreements with certain developers to: (1) plan, survey, design, construct, maintain, or operate Arctic deepwater ports; (2) provide technical assistance for such activities; and (3) receive funds from federal, nonfederal, and private entities, including developers of Arctic deepwater ports that have an agreement with the Secretary for such activity.</p> <p> Defines &quot;Arctic deepwater port&quot; as any port facility, in a water depth of at least 30 feet, located in waters: (1) north of 60 degrees latitude north and west of 162 degrees longitude west, or (2) north of 63 degrees latitude north.</p> <p>Defines &quot;developer&quot; as any private entity, state, municipal, or borough government, Alaska Native corporation created by the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, or the western Alaska community development quota program created by the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act that is seeking to develop an Arctic deepwater port.</p> <p>Establishes the Arctic Port Infrastructure Development Fund within the U.S. Treasury. </p> <p>Permits the Secretary, within a 30-year period and subject to specified limitations, to issue federal guarantee instruments with respect to loans and other debt obligations for such ports. Requires the loan or debt obligation guaranteed by such instruments to be issued by an eligible nonfederal qualified institutional buyer. </p> <p>Designates the Secretary as the lead for purposes of complying with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for the development of an Arctic deepwater port, regardless of the U.S. agency taking the action that requires compliance with such Act. </p> <p>Establishes the Office of the Federal Arctic Deepwater Port Coordinator as an independent office in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works of the Department of the Army.</p> <p>Makes infrastructure finance funding available to assist developers of Arctic deepwater ports.</p> <p>Authorizes the Commandant of the Coast Guard to: (1) enter into long-term leases for moorage, warehousing, hangar space, and logistical support with Arctic deep water port developers; and (2) convey any property deemed surplus to the Coast Guard's needs in Alaska to any Alaskan borough, municipality, or native corporation seeking to develop such ports. </p> <p>Expands the definition of &quot;deepwater port&quot; under the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 to include the use of such structures for general handling of cargo, ship service or repair, logistical support for government and private sector activities at sea, or service as a harbor of refuge.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Arctic Deep Water Ports Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Arctic Deep Water Ports Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Arctic Deep Water Ports Enhancement Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to expedite the development of Arctic deepwater ports and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-02-28T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s428is/xml/BILLS-113s428is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
