<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>532</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:36:20Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:36:20Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-03-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-03-06T20:37:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Stop Arming Terrorists Act</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>608</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-01-23</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000603</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Paul, Rand [R-KY]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rand</firstName>
        <lastName>Paul</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Iraq</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Middle East</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military assistance, sales, and agreements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military education and training</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Political movements and philosophies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Syria</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-03-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-03-18T15:35:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Stop Arming Terrorists Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of federal agency funds to provide covered assistance to: (1) Al Qaeda, Jabhat Fateh al-Sham, the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL), or any individual or group that is affiliated with, associated with, cooperating with, or adherents to such groups; or (2) the government of any country that the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) determines has, within the most recent 12 months, provided covered assistance to such a group or individual.</p> <p>&quot;Covered assistance&quot; is defined as:</p> <ul> <li>defense articles, defense services, training or logistical support, or any other military assistance provided by grant, loan, credit, transfer, or cash sales; </li> <li> intelligence sharing; or </li> <li> cash assistance. </li> </ul> <p>The ODNI shall:</p> <ul> <li> make, within 90 days after this bill's enactment, initial determinations about such countries and about whether an individual or group is, or has been within the most recent 12 months, affiliated with, associated with, cooperating with, or an adherent to Al Qaeda, Jabhat Fateh al-Sham, or ISIL;</li> <li>review and make subsequent determinations regarding such countries, groups, or individuals every 6 months in consultation with specified congressional committees; </li> <li> brief such committees on each determination; and</li> <li> brief such committees on any other country, individual, or group that the ODNI considered but did not make a determination that the the country provided covered assistance to, or that the group or individual is affiliated with, associated with, cooperating with, or an adherent to, Al Qaeda, Jabhat Fateh al-Sham, or ISIL.</li> </ul>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Stop Arming Terrorists Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Stop Arming Terrorists Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to prohibit the use of United States Government funds to provide assistance to Al Qaeda, Jabhat Fateh al-Sham, and the Islamic State of Iraq and the Levant (ISIL) and to countries supporting those organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Stop Arming Terrorists Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-03-06T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s532is/xml/BILLS-115s532is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-03-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
