<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6490</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:54Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:54Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-12-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 177 (Thursday, December 8, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. SMITH of Texas:H.R. 6490.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18:The Congress shall have power to make all Laws which shallbe necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department of Officer thereof.[Page H7570]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-12-08T14:05:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-12-08T14:05:15Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
        <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-12-08T14:05:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act of 2016</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>6414</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-11-30</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>American Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>3084</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-01-06</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 114-329.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
            <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
            <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>21</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-02-15T19:06:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>American Innovation and Competitiveness Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to maintain the intellectual merit and broader impacts criteria as the basis for evaluating grant proposals in the merit review process. </p> <p>The NSF shall issue and periodically update policy guidance for both NSF staff and other NSF merit review process participants on the importance of transparency and accountability to the outcomes made through the merit review process. </p> <p>The bill renames the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research as the Established Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR) and revises program requirements. </p> <p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) shall research information systems for future cybersecurity needs. </p> <p>The bill renames the National High Performance Computing Program as the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program and revises program requirements.</p> <p>The National Science and Technology Council (NSTC) shall continue to coordinate federal research in high-energy physics, radiation biology, and fusion energy sciences. </p> <p>NIST shall implement a comprehensive strategic plan for laboratory programs expanding interactions with academia, international researchers, and industry, and commercial and industrial applications.</p> <p>The NSF shall: </p> <ul> <li>evaluate the existing and future needs, across all NSF-supported disciplines, for mid-scale projects; </li> <li> strengthen oversight and accountability over the full life-cycle of major multi-user research facility projects; and</li> <li>continue to review its efforts to sustain scientific efforts in the face of logistical challenges for the U.S. Antarctic Program. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of Commerce Office of Security shall directly manage NIST's law enforcement and site security programs through an assigned Director of Security for NIST. </p>  <p>The Office of Management and Budget shall establish an interagency working group to reduce administrative burdens of federally funded researchers while protecting the public's interest in the transparency of, and accountability for, federally funded activities. </p> <p>The Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) shall establish a body under the NSTC to identify and coordinate international science and technology cooperation in order to strengthen U.S. science and technology enterprise, improve economic and national security, and support U.S. foreign policy goals. </p> <p>The NSF, the Department of Education, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall establish the STEM Education Advisory Panel to advise the NSTC Committee on STEM Education on matters related to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM). The NSF shall award grants to increase the participation of underrepresented populations in STEM fields. </p> <p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology Act is amended to revise requirements for the NIST post-doctoral fellowship program<tt>,</tt> and the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership.</p> <p>Federal science agencies may use crowdsourcing and voluntary, collaborative citizen science to advance their missions.</p> <p>The OSTP shall establish an interagency working group to: (1) summarize available research and best practices on how to promote diversity and inclusions in STEM fields, and (2) examine whether barriers exist to promoting diversity and inclusion within federal agencies employing scientists and engineers.</p> <p>Each federal agency shall recommend to the President how it could expand research opportunities for undergraduate students attending institutions of higher education.</p> <p>The NSF shall award grants for: </p> <ul> <li>research on computer science education and computational thinking; and </li> <li>Innovation Corps entrepreneurship and commercialization education, training, and mentoring. </li> </ul>  <p>The OSTP shall arrange with the National Research Council to study technologies employed at institutions of higher education to provide notifications to students, faculty, and other personnel during emergencies. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>American Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>American Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To invest in innovation through research and development, and to improve the competitiveness of the United States.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Manufacturing Extension Partnership Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Science Prize Competition Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Research and Development Efficiency Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>International Science and Technology Cooperation Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>United States Chief Technology Officer Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Modernization Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>American Innovation and Competitiveness Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-12-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr6490ih/xml/BILLS-114hr6490ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-12-08</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
