<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>7397</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:40:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:40:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2018-12-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. HOYER:H.R. 7397.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The Congress shall have power . . . To make all laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into executionforegoing powers, and all other powers vested by thisConstitution in the government of the United States, or inany department or officer thereof.[Page H10593]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsbu00</systemCode>
        <name>Budget Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2018-12-22T17:00:39Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
        <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2018-12-22T17:00:34Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2018</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>695</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2019-01-02</actionDate>
          <text>Considered by Senate (Message from the House considered). (consideration: CR S8051)</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsbu00</systemCode>
            <name>Budget Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsap00</systemCode>
            <name>Appropriations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000874</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Hoyer, Steny H. [D-MD-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>STENY</firstName>
        <lastName>HOYER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <district>5</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Chemical and biological weapons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Competition and antitrust</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency medical services and trauma care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Freedom of information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Home and outpatient care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Industrial facilities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marriage and family status</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear weapons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Product development and innovation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2018-12-28T16:53:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>DIVISION A--FURTHER ADDITIONAL CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2019 </p> <p><i>Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019 </i></p> <p>(Sec. 101) This division amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019 to provide continuing FY2019 appropriations to several federal agencies through the earlier of February 8, 2019 (December 21, 2018, under current law), or the enactment of the applicable appropriations legislation.</p> <p> It is known as a continuing resolution (CR) and ends the partial government shutdown that began when the existing CR expired because seven of the remaining FY2019 appropriations bills have not been enacted. </p> <p>(Five of the FY2019 appropriations bills were enacted earlier this year, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2019; </li> <li> the Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019; </li> <li> the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019; </li> <li> the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2019; and </li> <li> the Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2019.) </li> </ul> <p>The CR extends through February 8, 2019: </p> <ul> <li> the Department of Homeland Security Chemical Facility Anti-Terrorism Standards Program; </li> <li> the authority for the Department of Health and Human Services Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority to withhold from public disclosure certain technical data or scientific information that reveals vulnerabilities of existing medical or public health defenses against biological, chemical, nuclear, or radiological threats; and </li> <li> an exemption from antitrust laws for meetings and consultations to discuss the development of certain vaccines and drugs related to public health threats such as bioterrorism, pandemics, or epidemics. </li> </ul> <p>Additionally, the CR has the effect of extending through February 8, 2019, several authorities and programs that were extended in prior CRs, including: </p> <ul> <li>the National Flood Insurance Program, </li> <li>the Violence Against Women Act, </li> <li> the authority for the Environmental Protection Agency to collect and spend certain fees related to pesticides, </li> <li> the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) program, and </li> <li> several authorities related to immigration. </li> </ul> <p>The CR also delays the release of required Congressional Budget Office and Office of Management and Budget sequestration reports. </p> <p>DIVISION B--MEDICAID EXTENDERS </p> <p>(Sec. 101) The division amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to make appropriations for FY2019, and otherwise revise, the Money Follows the Person Rebalancing Demonstration Program (Under this program, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must award grants to state Medicaid programs to assist states in increasing the use of home and community care for long-term care and decreasing the use of institutional care.) </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Additionally, the division temporarily extends the applicability of Medicaid eligibility criteria that protect against spousal impoverishment for recipients of home and community-based services.</p> <p> (Sec. 103) The division also reduces the federal medical assistance percentage (i.e., federal matching rate) for states that have not implemented asset-verification programs for determining Medicaid eligibility.</p> <p>(Sec. 104) The division reduces funding available to the Medicaid Improvement Fund beginning in FY2021.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) This section exempts the budgetary effects of this division from: (1) the Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) rules established by the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 and the FY2018 congressional budget resolution, and (2) certain budget scorekeeping guidelines.</p> <p> It also requires any debits on the statutory PAYGO scorecard for 2019 to be transferred to the 2020 scorecard. (The Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 prohibits certain legislation from increasing the budget deficit. PAYGO scorecards are used to enforce the requirements and determine whether a sequestration order implementing spending cuts is necessary.) </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To provide further additional continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To provide further additional continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide further additional continuing appropriations for fiscal year 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2019</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2018-12-22T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115hr7397ih/xml/BILLS-115hr7397ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2018-12-22</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
