<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1264</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:37Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:37Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-06-27</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-06-27T22:00:16Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-06-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001070</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Casey, Robert P., Jr. [D-PA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bob</firstName>
        <lastName>Casey</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commuting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor fuels</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-06-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-10-28T22:04:54Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Clean Vehicle Corridors Act - Requires the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to: (1) designate at least five Clean Vehicle Corridors along federal highways, interstates, or other contiguous highways after consulting with specified agencies; and (2) encourage the addition of cleaner alternative fuel options and other supporting infrastructure along the corridors and the inclusion of existing and private facilities in the corridor.</p> <p>Defines &quot;cleaner alternative fuels&quot; to include: (1) compressed natural gas, (2) liquefied natural gas, (3) liquefied petroleum gas (also known as propane), (4) plug-in electric, (5) advanced biofuels, and (6) hydrogen.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to provide waivers of statutory restrictions for cleaner alternative fuel projects and vehicles along Clean Vehicle Corridors.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to: (1) maintain a publicly accessible website containing information and resources for corridors, (2) identify best practices and case studies of communities and complementary programs that have successfully promoted cleaner alternative fuel use in consultation with federal agencies, tribes, states, and Clean Cities, (3) identify all existing technical and financial mechanisms available to promote the development of cleaner alternative fuel infrastructure, and (4) collaborate with the Secretary of Energy (DOE) and all relevant Clean Vehicle Corridor stakeholders to collect data on cleaner alternative fueling station usage patterns. <p>Authorizes: (1) two or more contiguous states to enter into an interstate compact to establish Clean Vehicle Corridor partnerships to facilitate planning for and siting of necessary facilities within those states; and (2) the Secretary, in consultation with the DOE Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to provide technical assistance to interstate compact partnerships.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Clean Vehicle Corridors Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Clean Vehicle Corridors Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to foster market development of clean energy fueling facilities by steering infrastructure installation toward designated Clean Vehicle Corridors.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Clean Vehicle Corridors Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-06-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1264is/xml/BILLS-113s1264is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-06-27</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
