<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3243</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:12Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:12Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-07-14T18:46:08Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Philanthropic Facilitation Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2313</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-11-19</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000562</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gardner, Cory [R-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Cory</firstName>
        <lastName>Gardner</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-03-29T19:46:18Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016 </b></p> <p>This bill modifies: (1) tax and regulatory policies that affect certain rural communities, and (2) tax rules that apply to private foundations. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to program-related investments made by private foundations for a charitable purpose, to: </p> <ul> <li> modify the definition of and requirements for program-related investments; </li> <li>allow a declaratory judgment remedy to determine whether investments in any entity are program-related investments; </li> <li> expand reporting requirements for for-profit entities that receive program-related investments; and </li> <li> allow public inspection of petitions seeking a determination of program-related investment status and annual information returns. </li> </ul> <p>The bill also includes several tax provisions that apply to rural renewal communities, which are low-income communities that: (1) have a population of at least 200 people but not more than 25,000 people, and are not located in a metropolitan area which has a population of 200,000 or more; or (2) are entirely within an Indian reservation.</p> <p>With respect to such communities, the bill: </p> <ul> <li>allows tax credits for a portion of the costs of reducing lead, radon, or asbestos hazards in rural commercial structures;</li> <li> expands the new markets tax credit; </li> <li>allows expensing of certain depreciable business assets; </li> <li> reduces payroll taxes; and </li> <li> allows tax-preferred rural renewal community business start-up savings accounts. </li> </ul> <p><i>Reducing Excessive Government in Rural America Act of 2016 </i></p> <p>Congress must consider legislation to reduce the regulatory cost to rural America by at least 10% over 10 years by repealing certain regulations. The legislation must be considered using expedited legislative procedures specified in the bill. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Rebuilding and Renewing Rural America Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to help rebuild and renew rural communities, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3243is/xml/BILLS-114s3243is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
