<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2511</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:31:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:31:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-02-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2016-04-05T20:33:44Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2016-02-09T15:08:34Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-02-08T21:03:27Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-05</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 418.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-05</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-02-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-02-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-02-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000360</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Alexander, Lamar [R-TN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lamar</firstName>
        <lastName>Alexander</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001075</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cassidy, Bill [R-LA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bill</firstName>
        <lastName>Cassidy</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000802</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Whitehouse, Sheldon [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sheldon</firstName>
        <lastName>Whitehouse</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001267</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bennet, Michael F. [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Bennet</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-02-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2016-12-02T21:01:49Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 2511, Improving Health Information Technology Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/52314</url>
        <description>As reported by the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions on April 5,&amp;nbsp;2016</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health personnel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health technology, devices, supplies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-02-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-12-05T13:44:48Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Improving Health Information Technology Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to: (1) reduce regulatory burdens relating to electronic health records (EHR), (2) publish statistics for the Medicare and Medicaid EHR Incentive Programs, and (3) establish an index of digital contact information to encourage exchange of health information.</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) to: (1) encourage, keep, or recognize the certification of health information technology (IT) for use in medical specialties; and (2) issue guidance and convene stakeholders regarding the secure exchange of electronic health information. </p> <p>HHS must develop a rating system for health IT. Health IT with a low rating must be improved by the developer or decertified. A provider whose adopted health IT is decertified is exempt from certain penalties. </p> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for health IT, certification criteria, and health IT developers. Developers of health IT and providers may be penalized for engaging in information blocking.</p> <p>The ONC, in coordination with the HHS Office for Civil Rights, must: (1) encourage partnerships between health information exchanges and others to offer patients access to their electronic health information; (2) educate providers on health information exchanges; (3) issue guidance to health information exchanges on best practices, and (4) ensure patient access to health information in a convenient form.</p> <p>HHS, in consultation with the ONC, must promote policies to facilitate patient communication with providers.</p> The HHS Office for Civil Rights must assist individuals and health care providers in understanding a patient's rights regarding their health information.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-04-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-01-25T20:46:09Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Improving Health Information Technology Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a goal, develop a strategy, and make recommendations to reduce regulatory or administrative burdens relating to the use of electronic health records (EHR).</p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) to encourage, keep, or recognize the certification of health information technology (IT) for use in medical specialties. HHS must adopt certification criteria to support health IT for pediatrics.</p> <p>HHS must publish attestation statistics for the Medicare and Medicaid EHR Meaningful Use Incentive programs. (Health care providers in these programs must attest to meaningful use of EHR to avoid a penalty.)</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The ONC may publish information demonstrating how health IT meets certification criteria or other requirements. Certification criteria must include meeting security requirements, incorporating user-centered design, and achieving interoperability. For health IT to be certified, the developer must: (1) not engage in information blocking, which is preventing, discouraging, or interfering with the access, exchange, or use of information; (2) permit unimpeded communication among health IT users and with certification bodies, the ONC, and others; (3) allow information from the health IT to be exchanged, accessed, and used; and (4) report on HHS criteria regarding the features and functionality of the health IT.</p> <p>HHS must develop a rating system for health IT. Health IT with a low rating must be improved by the developer or decertified. A provider whose adopted health IT is decertified is exempted from penalties under the Medicare EHR Meaningful Use Incentive program.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Developers of health IT and providers may be penalized for engaging in information blocking.</p> <p>The ONC must issue guidance on the secure exchange of electronic health information.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The ONC must convene stakeholders to develop a framework and agreement for the secure exchange of health information between networks and provide for testing of the framework and agreement. The ONC must publish a list of networks that have adopted the agreement.</p> <p>HHS must establish an index of digital contact information for health professionals, health facilities, and others to encourage the exchange of health information.</p> <p>In adopting standards for exchange of electronic health information, HHS must give deference to standards published by certain standards bodies.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) To be certified, health IT must be capable of transmitting to and receiving from data registries certified by the ONC.</p> <p>HHS must report on best practices and current trends provided by patient safety organizations to improve the integration of health IT into clinical practice.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The ONC, in coordination with the HHS Office for Civil Rights, must: (1) encourage partnerships between health information exchanges and others to offer patients access to their electronic health information, (2) educate providers on health information exchanges, (3) issue guidance to health information exchanges on best practices, and (4) ensure patient access to health information in a convenient form.</p> <p>HHS, in consultation with the ONC, must promote policies to facilitate patient communication with providers.</p> <p>The HHS Office for Civil Rights must assist individuals and health care providers in understanding a patient's rights to access and protect their personal health information.</p> <p>The ONC must direct health IT certification programs to require health IT to support usability features.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Government Accountability Office must review the policies and activities of the ONC and stakeholders to ensure correct matching of a patient to electronic health information.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Improving Health Information Technology Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Improving Health Information Technology Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve Federal requirements relating to the development and use of electronic health records technology.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Improving Health Information Technology Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Improving Health Information Technology Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2016-04-05T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2511rs/xml/BILLS-114s2511rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-02-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2511is/xml/BILLS-114s2511is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-04-05</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 418.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
