<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3452</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:23:27Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:23:27Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-11-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. HIGGINS:H.R. 3452.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 3[Page H6998]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2014-01-09T18:34:26Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-11-12T19:01:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>FANS Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1721</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-12-04</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-847.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-14</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7062)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-12</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-11-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001038</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Higgins, Brian [D-NY-26]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Higgins</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <district>26</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Sports and Recreation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Competition and antitrust</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Professional sports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Television and film</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Sports and Recreation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-01-24T22:36:14Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Furthering Access and Networks for Sports Act or the FANS Act - Amends the Sports Broadcasting Act of 1961 to deny the antitrust exemption for joint agreements covering the telecasting of sports contests to any league of clubs participating in professional football, baseball, basketball, or hockey contests that does not: (1) expressly prohibit sponsored telecast licensees of such league, and any agreement with any video licensee, from intentionally removing the live content of such league from a multichannel video programming distributor when such removal occurs during, or is related to a negotiation regarding, carriage of the league's games by such distributor; or (2) make a sponsored telecast of a game that is played in the home territory of a member club available to consumers, using an Internet platform, in any territory in which the game is not available for private viewing through a local television broadcast station or any available multichannel video programming distributor. Repeals the exception that allows the antitrust exemption for such a joint agreement that prohibits televising games within the home territory of a member club on a day when such club is playing at home.</p> <p>Amends the Clayton Act to: (1) subject the conduct, acts, practices, or agreements of persons in the business of organized professional major league baseball (currently, only such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements directly relating to or affecting employment of major league baseball players at the major league level) to the antitrust laws to the same extent that such conduct, acts, practices, or agreements engaged in by persons in any other professional sports business affecting interstate commerce are subject to such laws; and (2) repeal provisions granting only a major league baseball player standing to sue. Eliminates provisions specifying that such Act does not create, permit, or imply a cause of action by which to challenge under the antitrust laws: (1) the relationship between the Office of the Commissioner and franchise owners, the marketing or sales of the entertainment product of organized professional baseball, and the licensing of intellectual property rights owned or held by organized professional baseball teams; or (2) any conduct, acts, practices, or agreements protected by the Sports Broadcasting Act of 1961.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>FANS Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>FANS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To decrease the frequency of sports blackouts, to require the application of the antitrust laws to Major League Baseball, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>FANS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Furthering Access and Networks for Sports Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-11-12T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr3452ih/xml/BILLS-113hr3452ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-01-09</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
