<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5282</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:01Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:01Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-05-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 80 (Thursday, May 19, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Ms. MAXINE WATERS of California:H.R. 5282.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8 of the United States Constitution[Page H2880]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-05-19T13:00:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Equal Employment for All Act of 2015</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>3524</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-09-16</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-19</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
            <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-05-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000187</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Waters, Maxine [D-CA-43]</fullName>
        <firstName>MAXINE</firstName>
        <lastName>WATERS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>43</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000147</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Del. Norton, Eleanor Holmes [D-DC-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>ELEANOR</firstName>
        <lastName>NORTON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DC</state>
        <middleName>HOLMES</middleName>
        <district>0</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000822</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Watson Coleman, Bonnie [D-NJ-12]</fullName>
        <firstName>Bonnie</firstName>
        <lastName>Watson Coleman</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <district>12</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000455</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Fudge, Marcia L. [D-OH-11]</fullName>
        <firstName>Marcia</firstName>
        <lastName>Fudge</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>11</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000053</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rangel, Charles B. [D-NY-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>CHARLES</firstName>
        <lastName>RANGEL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
        <district>13</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001061</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Cleaver, Emanuel [D-MO-5]</fullName>
        <firstName>Emanuel</firstName>
        <lastName>Cleaver</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MO</state>
        <district>5</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000553</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Green, Al [D-TX-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>Al</firstName>
        <lastName>Green</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>9</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000472</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Takano, Mark [D-CA-41]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Takano</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>41</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000179</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Napolitano, Grace F. [D-CA-32]</fullName>
        <firstName>GRACE</firstName>
        <lastName>NAPOLITANO</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <district>32</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-07-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Contracts and agency</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime victims</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign language and bilingual programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marketing and advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public participation and lobbying</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-05-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-09-23T21:01:20Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to revise requirements for reinvestigations of disputed information by a consumer reporting agency (CRA), establishing a new right to appeal, free of charge, completed disputes adverse to the consumer.</p> <p>The bill prescribes requirements for:</p> <ul> <li>dispute procedures for furnishers of information and CRAs, as well as meaningful disclosures to consumers about investigations and reinvestigations; and</li> <li>CRA action when notified of inaccurate or incomplete information from furnishers.</li></ul> <p>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) shall issue a final rule establishing reasonable procedures CRAs must maintain to ensure maximum possible accuracy and completeness of the information concerning the individual to whom a consumer report relates.</p> <p>Any CRA that furnishes a consumer report containing public record data shall include its source.</p> <p>Courts may award injunctive relief to consumers against any person found liable for either willful or negligent noncompliance with the requirements of the Act.</p> <p>The bill limits the circumstances in which a CRA may furnish a consumer report for employment purposes.</p> <p>No CRA may furnish a consumer report containing any adverse item of information relating to:</p> <ul> <li>a delinquent or defaulted private education loan of a borrower who has rehabilitated his or her credit regarding the loan by making 9 on-time monthly loan payments over 10 consecutive months after the delinquency or default occurred, or</li> <li>a covered residential mortgage loan if the action or inaction to which the item of information relates resulted from specified predatory lending practices.</li> </ul> <p>The bill shortens the respective time periods that specified adverse credit information remains on consumer reports, and gives deadlines for removing from them fully paid or settled medical debt.</p> <p>A CRA must remove from a consumer report any adverse information about:</p> <ul> <li>a private education loan regarding a proprietary educational institution or career education program which the consumer alleges engaged in fraudulent, discriminatory, or illegal practices; and</li> <li>a consumer who is the victim of intentionally abusive or harmful financial behavior by an acquaintance or family member.</li> </ul> <p>No CRAs may treat credit restoration or rehabilitation as adverse information.</p> <p>The CFPB shall issue final regulations for development of credit snoring models. </p> <p>CRAs must disclose prominently on their websites the differences between and limitations of credit scores, including educational credit scores, before a consumer obtains such scores.</p> <p>CRAs shall disclose, upon request and in certain circumstances automatically, free credit scores to consumers with their free annual consumer reports.</p> <p>Private educational lenders, motor vehicle or indirect auto lenders, and residential mortgage lenders shall give consumers free copies of any consumer reports and credit scores they used for underwriting before consumers sign the respective loan agreements.</p> <p>The bill prohibits:</p> <ul> <li>automatic renewals for consumer reporting and credit scoring products and services offered under promotional terms, and </li> <li>misleading and deceptive marketing related to the provision of such products and services.</li> </ul> <p>The CFPB may set a fair and reasonable maximum fee for such a product or service, except where a maximum fee is otherwise posed by the Act.</p> <p>The CFPB shall issue a rule to require CRAs and furnishers of information to:</p> <ul> <li> provide information, disclosures, or other communication with consumers in each of the 10 most commonly spoken non-English languages in the United States, and in formats accessible to individuals with hearing or vision impairments; </li> <li>ensure that at least one among their customer service representatives is fluent in each of these 10 languages; and </li> <li>ensure that all their customer service representatives are highly familiar with the requirements of the Act, and are available both during and outside of regular business hours.</li> </ul> <p>The CFPB shall also establish a nationwide CRA registry.</p> <p> CRAs must, upon consumer request, place credit freezes on the consumer's file, including free credit freezes for consumers with a good faith suspicion they have been or are about to become a victim of identity theft, fraud, or a related crime. </p> <p>The bill transfers from the Federal Trade Commission to the CFPB the mandate to set procedures for reporting identity theft, fraud, and other related crime.</p> <p>CRAs must provide the consumer with credit monitoring and identity theft protection services within one business day upon direct consumer request, and without charge if the consumer meets specified criteria.</p> <p>Consumer reports shall exclude any information about inquiries resulting from identity theft, fraud, or other related crime.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to improve the consumer reporting system, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-05-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5282ih/xml/BILLS-114hr5282ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-05-19</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
