<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4328</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:32:18Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:32:18Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-01-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 3 (Wednesday, January 6, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. BRIDENSTINE:H.R. 4328.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 1--All legislative Powers herein grantedshall be vested in a Congress of the United States, whichshall consist of a Senate and House of Representatives.Article 1, Section 5, clause 2--Each House may determinethe Rules of its Proceedings . . .Article 1, Section 8, clause 18--To make all Laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States or in anyDepartment or Officer thereof[Page H101]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
        <name>Rules Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-01-06T15:01:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-01-06</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsru00</systemCode>
            <name>Rules Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-01-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-01-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001283</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Bridenstine, Jim [R-OK-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Bridenstine</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001184</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Massie, Thomas [R-KY-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Massie</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-01-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional operations and organization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-01-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-04-25T19:08:37Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Read the Bill Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits consideration of any bill or resolution in the House of Representatives or the Senate unless its text is published on an official website of the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate at least the applicable minimum number of hours (excluding those in which the chamber is not in session) before consideration of the bill or resolution, namely: </p> <ul> <li>72 hours, for text of 300 or fewer pages; or</li> <li>for text of more than 300 pages, the sum of 72 hours plus 24 hours for each additional increment of text of 100 or fewer pages. </li> </ul> <p>Whenever a House or Senate Committee reports a bill or joint resolution proposing to repeal or amend all or part of a statute, it must include in its report or in an accompanying document:</p> <ul> <li>the entire text of each section of the statute proposed to be repealed or amended, and </li> <li>a comparative print of each amendment to the section of the statute that the bill or joint resolution proposes to make. </li> </ul> <p>Neither chamber, nor Congress jointly, may dispense with or otherwise waive or modify the requirements of this Act. </p> <p>Any Act of Congress that was considered as a bill or resolution in the House or Senate in violation of this Act shall have no force or effect, and no legal, equitable, regulatory, civil, or criminal action may be brought under it.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Read the Bill Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Read the Bill Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To prohibit the consideration in the House of Representatives or Senate of the text of any legislation which has not been published online at least 72 hours prior to its consideration, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Read the Bill Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-01-06T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr4328ih/xml/BILLS-114hr4328ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-01-06</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
