<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1793</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:38:35Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:38:35Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-09-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-09-12T14:46:23Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require electronic filing of the annual returns of exempt organizations and provide for making such returns available for public inspection.</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>5443</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2018-04-18</actionDate>
          <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 831, H.R. 5443 is laid on the table.</text>
          <actionTime>18:24:27</actionTime>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Protecting Taxpayer Confidentiality Through Safeguards Act</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>5376</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2018-03-21</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-09-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S5219)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-09-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Grassley, Chuck [R-IA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Charles</firstName>
        <lastName>Grassley</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IA</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000250</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Thune, John [R-SD]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Thune</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>SD</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-09-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-09-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2018-04-03T20:47:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Taxpayer Bill of Rights Enhancement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the&nbsp;Internal Revenue Code, with respect to provisions affecting taxpayer rights, to: </p> <ul> <li>increase penalties for unauthorized disclosure or inspection&nbsp;of taxpayer information and allow punitive damages for willful unauthorized inspection or disclosure; </li> <li>prohibit the disclosure of taxpayer information to any contractor or other agent of a governmental entity without confidentiality safeguards; </li> <li>increase the limit on civil damages for unauthorized collection actions by Internal Revenue Service (IRS) employees and allow punitive damages for reckless or intentional actions; </li> <li>extend to two years the time limit for contesting a tax levy or for seeking a return of wrongfully levied property; </li> <li>waive user fees for taxpayers who agree to automated installment payments; </li> <li>allow amounts that have been wrongfully levied from retirement accounts to be recontributed without regard to contribution limits; </li> <li>modify the requirements and exceptions that apply to payments of estimated taxes;</li> <li>require the disclosure of collection activities relating to a joint account upon the oral request of either spouse (currently, a written request is required); and</li> <li>require tax-exempt organizations to file their tax returns in electronic form.</li> </ul> <p>The IRS must maintain a program that provides free tax preparation and electronic filing services to low-income and elderly taxpayers.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998 to require at least one IRS appeals officer and one settlement officer to be located and permanently available in each state, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Taxpayer Bill of Rights Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Taxpayer Bill of Rights Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Taxpayer Bill of Rights Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance taxpayer rights, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-09-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s1793is/xml/BILLS-115s1793is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-09-12</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S5219)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
