<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>75</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:34:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:34:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-01-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 163, Number 1 (Tuesday, January 3, 2017)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. RATCLIFFE:H.R. 75.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 1 of the United States Constitution, inthat the legislation concerns the exercise of legislativepowers generally granted to Congress by that section,including the exercise of those powers when delegated byCongress to the Executive; Article I, Section 8 of the UnitedStates Constitution, in that the legislation concerns theexercise of specific legislative powers granted to Congressby that section, including the exercise of those powers whendelegated by Congress to the Executive; and, Article I,Section 8, Clause 18 of the United States Constitution, inthat the legislation exercises legislative power granted toCongress by that clause ``to make all laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into execution theforegoing powers, and all other powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.''[Page H48]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2017-01-05T18:59:31Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-01-03T17:07:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-01-03T17:07:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2017</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>5</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-03-29</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-21.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100-A</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000601</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Ratcliffe, John [R-TX-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Ratcliffe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000289</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Goodlatte, Bob [R-VA-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>ROBERT</firstName>
        <lastName>GOODLATTE</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>W.</middleName>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-01-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001179</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Marino, Tom [R-PA-10]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <lastName>Marino</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <district>10</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-01-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001282</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Barr, Andy [R-KY-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>Andy</firstName>
        <lastName>Barr</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KY</state>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-01-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001065</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Holding, George [R-NC-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>Holding</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <district>13</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-01-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-01-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-02-07T22:21:20Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2017 or the ALERT Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires each federal agency to submit a monthly report to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) for each rule such agency expects to propose or finalize during the following year. The reports must include: (1) a summary of the nature of the rule, (2) the objectives of and legal basis for issuance of the rule, (3) the stage of the rulemaking as of the date of submission, and (4) whether the rule is subject to periodic review as a rule with a significant economic impact. </p> <p>Each agency must submit a monthly report for any rule expected to be finalized during the following year for which the agency has issued a general notice of proposed rulemaking. The reports must include an approximate schedule for completing action on the rule and an estimate of its cost and economic effects. </p> <p>OIRA must make such monthly reports publicly available on the Internet. </p> <p>OIRA must publish, not later than October 1 of each year, in the Federal Register: (1) information that OIRA receives from each agency under this bill; (2) the number of rules and a list of each such rule that was proposed by each agency and each rule that was finalized by each agency; (3) the number of agency actions that repealed a rule, reduced the scope or cost of a rule, or accelerated the expiration date of a rule; (4) the total cost of all rules proposed or finalized; and (5) the number of rules for which an estimate of the cost of the rule was not available. </p> <p>OIRA must make publicly available on the Internet, not later than October 1 of each year: (1) the analysis of the costs or benefits of each proposed or final rule issued by an agency for the preceding year, (2) the docket number and regulation identifier number for each such rule, (3) the number of rules reviewed by OMB for the preceding year, (4) the number of rules for which a review by the head of an agency was completed, (5) the number of rules submitted to the Government Accountability Office, and (6) the number of rules for which a resolution of disapproval was introduced in Congress. </p> <p>The bill prohibits a rule from taking effect until the information required by this bill is posted on the Internet for not less than six months, unless: (1) the agency proposing the rule claims a &quot;good cause&quot; exemption from notice-and-comment rulemaking procedures under the Administrative Procedure Act; or (2) the President determines by executive order that such rule is necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency, for the enforcement of criminal laws, for national security, or to implement an international trade agreement. Such requirement becomes effective eight months after enactment of this bill. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>ALERT Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>ALERT Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend title 5, united States Code, to provide for the publication, by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, of information relating to rulemakings, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>ALERT Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2017-01-03T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115hr75ih/xml/BILLS-115hr75ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-01-05</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
