<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3210</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:14Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-07-14</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-07-14T14:50:07Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S5161-5163)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000141</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cardin, Benjamin L. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ben</firstName>
        <lastName>Cardin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000612</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Perdue, David [R-GA]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Perdue</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <middleName>Alfred</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Business ethics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Corporate finance and management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign and international corporations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military assistance, sales, and agreements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-11-10T20:16:00Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Combating Global Corruption and Ensuring Accountability Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the the Department of State to: (1) submit an annual report describing the status of corruption in foreign countries and assessing each country's anti-corruption efforts; and (2) annually publish on a publicly accessible website a four-tiered ranking based upon a government's efforts to comply with the minimum anti-corruption standards prescribed in the bill.</p> <p>The bill states that a government is complying with such standards if it: </p> <ul> <li>has enacted and judicially enforces laws, and has established structures and practices, that prohibit corruption; </li> <li>prescribes punishment for grand corruption that is commensurate with the punishment for serious crimes; </li> <li>prescribes punishment for petty corruption that provides a sufficient deterrent and reflects the nature of the offense; and </li> <li>is making sustained anti-corruption efforts.</li> </ul> <p>The State Department shall, prior to the obligation of any foreign assistance (except acute humanitarian and disaster assistance) to a tier 3 or tier 4 country: </p> <ul> <li>conduct a corruption risk assessment and create a corruption mitigation strategy for all foreign assistance programs to that country, </li> <li>require the inclusion of anti-corruption clauses for all foreign assistance contracts and grants, </li> <li>require disclosure of the beneficial ownership of all entities receiving foreign assistance funding, and </li> <li>establish a mechanism for investigating allegations of misappropriated foreign assistance funds or equipment. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development shall consolidate existing reports with anti-corruption components into one online, public platform.</p> <p>The State Department and the Department of Defense shall submit a strategy that details (1) how the U.S. government will incorporate corruption risk assessments during security sector assistance with foreign security forces, and (2) how security sector assistance will improve security sector governance. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) identifying the true beneficial owners of companies formed in the United States or abroad and the property that has been removed from a country in connection with corrupt activities is an important part of combating corruption; and (2) the President should develop a comprehensive approach to requiring such beneficial ownership information for companies formed in the United States or abroad.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Combating Global Corruption and Ensuring Accountability Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Combating Global Corruption and Ensuring Accountability Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Combating Global Corruption and Ensuring Accountability Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to identify and combat corruption in countries, to establish a tiered system of countries with respect to levels of corruption by their governments and their efforts to combat such corruption, and to assess United States assistance to designated countries in order to advance anti-corruption efforts in those countries and better serve United States taxpayers.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-07-14T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3210is/xml/BILLS-114s3210is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-07-14</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations. (Sponsor introductory remarks on measure: CR S5161-5163)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
