<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1831</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:23:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:23:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-12-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-12-16T22:34:51Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001183</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Manchin, Joe, III [D-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Joseph</firstName>
        <lastName>Manchin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Census and government statistics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency medical services and trauma care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>First responders and emergency personnel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement officers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-12-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-03-11T20:53:14Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>National Yellow Dot Program Act - Directs the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) of the Department of Transportation (DOT) to: (1) establish a national Yellow Dot Program to assist law enforcement and emergency services personnel to efficiently gather relevant medical information in the event of a motor vehicle accident or other medical emergency involving motor vehicles, and (2) designate a DOT employee to serve as the national coordinator of the Program (Coordinator).</p> <p>Directs the Coordinator to: (1) provide information, training, and materials for the Program to assist the state officials designated in the implementation of the Program; (2) compile national statistics on Program participation rates; and (3) collaborate with states that have similar programs to improve national consistency in training materials, participant forms and information, and data collection methods.</p> <p>Requires each state that elects to participate in the Program to notify the Coordinator and designate a state official to oversee the Program throughout the state. Requires each participating state to: (1) work with local law enforcement and emergency services agencies to publicize the Program; (2) distribute to Program participants a yellow sticker and a yellow folder for each motor vehicle the participant anticipates driving or riding in regularly and a blank form on which to enter medical conditions, prescriptions, and other vital information for each driver or passenger; (3) instruct local law enforcement and emergency services personnel about Program purposes and requirements; and (4) report annually to the Coordinator on Program participants.</p> <p>Requires each participant to: (1) place the sticker in the bottom left corner of the rear window of each vehicle the participant anticipates driving or riding in regularly, (2) place the completed form in the folder, and (3) place the folder in the glove compartment of each vehicle.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>National Yellow Dot Program Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Yellow Dot Program Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish a national Yellow Dot Program to alert law enforcement and emergency services personnel to the medical conditions, prescriptions, and other vital information necessary to treat drivers and passengers in motor vehicles in emergency circumstances.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Yellow Dot Program Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-12-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1831is/xml/BILLS-113s1831is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
