<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1474</number>
    <updateDate>2023-03-22T18:49:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-03-22T18:49:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-08-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
        <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Other</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2014-08-26T16:22:48Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2014-05-21T18:30:00Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2014-04-02T18:30:00Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-08-01T22:43:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-260</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 113-275.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 113-275.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-15</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-15</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:59:15</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:59:13</actionTime>
        <text>On passage Passed without objection. (text: CR H9294)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:59:13</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed without objection.(text: CR H9294)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:58:45</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Goodlatte asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:58:45</actionTime>
        <text>Considered by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR H9294)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-10</actionDate>
        <actionTime>18:24:43</actionTime>
        <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H15000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-10</actionDate>
        <actionTime>11:19:00</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-10</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The committee reported substitute was withdrawn by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S6416)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR S6414-6416; text of measure as reported in Senate: CR S6414-6416)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-260.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>By Senator Tester from Committee on Indian Affairs filed written report. Report No. 113-260.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14900</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-08-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 534.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-08-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-08-26</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Tester under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/05/2014 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-04-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 113-324.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-08-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <laws>
      <item>
        <type>Public Law</type>
        <number>113-275</number>
      </item>
    </laws>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judicial procedure and administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Native Americans</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-10-24T21:45:14Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2013 - Directs the Attorney General to establish the Alaska Safe Families and Villages Self Governance Program in the Office of Tribal Justice Programs to make grants to Indian tribes to implement intergovernmental agreements with Alaska that allow Indian tribes in Alaska to enforce certain state laws.</p> <p>Requires each Indian tribe that is selected to participate in the Project to carry out a specified planning phase.</p> <p>Provides that the intergovernmental agreements may describe the duties of Alaska and the applicable Indian tribe regarding:</p> <ul> <li>the employment of law enforcement, probation, and parole officers;</li> <li>state appointment and deputization of tribal law enforcement officers as special officers to assist in the enforcement of the state's criminal laws;</li> <li>the enforcement of punishments imposed by the Indian tribe under tribal law;</li> <li>the transfer of enforcement duties for state drug- and alcohol-related misdemeanor offenses to the Indian tribe; </li> <li>the Indian tribe's adjudication of those offenses;</li> <li>the transfer of information and evidence between tribal law enforcement entities and the state's court system;</li> <li>offender detention;</li> <li>searches and seizures of alcohol and drugs at municipal and state airports; and</li> <li>jurisdictional or financial matters.</li> </ul> <p>Absolves Alaska, including its political subdivisions, of liability for any act or omission of a participating Indian tribe in carrying out this Act.</p> <p>Makes participating Indian tribes eligible for the same tribal court and law enforcement programs and level of funding from the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) and the Department of Justice (DOJ) as are available to other Indian tribes.</p> <p>Amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal the limitation, within Alaska, of that Act's extension of tribal jurisdiction over domestic violence crimes and the issuance and enforcement of protection orders. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-08-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-11-13T22:53:31Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014 - (Sec. 4) Directs the Attorney General to establish the Alaska Safe Families and Villages Self Governance Intergovernmental Grant Program to make grants to Indian tribes to implement intergovernmental agreements with Alaska related to tribal enforcement of certain state laws. </p> <p>Requires each tribe selected to participate in the Program to request participation by resolution or other official tribal action and meet specified criteria. </p> <p>Requires tribes to use the grants to carry out a planning phase and activities in accordance with an intergovernmental agreement with Alaska. </p> <p>Provides that the intergovernmental agreements may describe the duties of Alaska and the Indian tribe regarding: </p> <ul> <li> employment of law enforcement, probation, and parole officers; </li> <li> appointment of tribal law enforcement officers as special officers to assist in the enforcement of the state's criminal laws; </li> <li> enforcement of punishments imposed under tribal law; </li> <li> transfer of enforcement duties for state drug- and alcohol-related misdemeanor offenses to the Indian tribe and the tribe's adjudication of those offenses;</li> <li> transfer of information and evidence between tribal law enforcement entities and the state's court system; </li> <li>offender detention; </li> <li>searches and seizures of alcohol and drugs at municipal and state airports; and </li> <li>jurisdictional or financial matters. </li> </ul> <p>Permits the intergovernmental agreements to include remedies imposed by the tribe, including: restorative justice, community service, fines, forfeitures, commitments for treatment, restraining orders, emergency detentions, and any other remedies agreed to by the state and the tribe. </p> <p>Requires the Attorney General to submit an annual report to Congress including grants awarded, an assessment of the program, and any recommendations related to the program. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Directs the Attorney General to establish the Alaska Safe Families and Villages Self Governance Tribal Law Project to make grants to assist Indian tribes in exercising concurrent civil jurisdiction on matters related to child abuse and neglect, domestic violence, and drug and alcohol related offenses. </p> <p>Requires each Indian tribe selected to participate in the Project to request participation by resolution or other official tribal action, meet specified criteria, and complete a planning phase certified by the Attorney General. </p> <p>Permits the participating tribe to exercise civil jurisdiction, concurrent with Alaska, over: (1) any member of or person eligible for membership in the tribe, and (2) any nonmember of the tribe that resides or is located in the remote Alaska Native village in which the tribe operates. Permits the tribe to exercise concurrent jurisdiction unless an intergovernmental agreement applies. </p> <p>Permits a participating tribe to impose civil sanctions, including: restorative justice, community service, fines, forfeitures, commitments for treatment, restraining orders, emergency detentions, and any other remedies the tribal court determines are appropriate. </p> <p>Prohibits a participating tribe exercising jurisdiction under this Act from incarcerating an individual absent an intergovernmental agreement. </p> <p>Requires the Attorney General to report to Congress annually on activities related to the program.</p> <p> (Sec. 6) Absolves Alaska, including its political subdivisions, of liability for any act or omission of a participating Indian tribe in carrying out this Act. </p> <p>Makes participating Indian tribes eligible for the same tribal court and law enforcement programs and level of funding from the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) as are available to other Indian tribes. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) Permits the Attorney General to enter into contracts with Indian tribes in Alaska to provide technical assistance related to tribal court development and the proper transfer of evidence and information. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) Permits the Attorney General to use amounts made available for the Office of Justice Programs to carry out this Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 9) Amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal a provision prohibiting Alaska tribes other than the Metlakatla Indian Community from issuing and enforcing domestic violence protective orders against non-member Alaska Natives and non-Natives. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>35</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed Senate amended</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-01-08T15:54:55Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal a provision prohibiting Alaska tribes other than the Metlakatla Indian Community from issuing and enforcing domestic violence protective orders against non-member Alaska Natives and non-Natives. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>81</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-12-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed House without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-01-08T15:55:05Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 9, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p> Amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal a provision prohibiting Alaska tribes other than the Metlakatla Indian Community from issuing and enforcing domestic violence protective orders against non-member Alaska Natives and non-Natives. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>49</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-01-08T15:55:12Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on December 9, 2014. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</b></p> <p> Amends the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal a provision prohibiting Alaska tribes other than the Metlakatla Indian Community from issuing and enforcing domestic violence protective orders against non-member Alaska Natives and non-Natives. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to encourage the State of Alaska to enter into intergovernmental agreements with Indian tribes in the State relating to the enforcement of certain State laws by Indian tribes, to improve the quality of life in rural Alaska, to reduce alcohol and drug abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Titles as Amended by Senate</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 to repeal a special rule for the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2013</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>3982</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <purpose>To amend the title.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:47:27Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment SA 3982 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>SA 3982</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/113th-congress/senate-amendment/3982</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
            <firstName>Mark</firstName>
            <lastName>Begich</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>AK</state>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <proposedDate>2014-12-09T05:00:00Z</proposedDate>
        <submittedDate>2014-12-09T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>113</congress>
          <type>S</type>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <number>1474</number>
          <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-03-22T18:49:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>6</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3982 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3982 proposed by Senator Begich. (consideration: CR S6416; text: CR S6416) To amend the title.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3982 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>94000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3982 proposed by Senator Begich.(consideration: CR S6416; text: CR S6416)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>93000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>3981</number>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <purpose>In the nature of a substitute.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:47:27Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment SA 3981 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>SA 3981</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/113th-congress/senate-amendment/3981</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
            <firstName>Mark</firstName>
            <lastName>Begich</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>AK</state>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <proposedDate>2014-12-09T05:00:00Z</proposedDate>
        <submittedDate>2014-12-09T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>113</congress>
          <type>S</type>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <number>1474</number>
          <title>Alaska Safe Families and Villages Act of 2014</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-03-22T18:49:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>6</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3981 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3981 proposed by Senator Begich. (consideration: CR S6416; text: CR S6416) In the nature of a substitute.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3981 proposed by Senator Begich.(consideration: CR S6416; text: CR S6416)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>93000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3981 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>94000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2014-12-09</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Enrolled Bill</type>
        <date/>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1474enr/xml/BILLS-113s1474enr.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-12-09T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1474es/xml/BILLS-113s1474es.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2014-08-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1474rs/xml/BILLS-113s1474rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-08-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1474is/xml/BILLS-113s1474is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date>2014-12-19T04:59:59Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PLAW-113publ275/uslm/PLAW-113publ275.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
        <type>Public Law</type>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-12-18</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 113-275.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
