<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5641</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:25:32Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:25:32Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-09-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. PRICE of North Carolina:H.R. 5641.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Congressional power to provide for public financing ofcampaigns arises under the General Welfare Clause, Art. I,Sec. 8, of the Constitution.In Buckley v. Valeo, 424 U.S. 1, 91 (1976), the SupremeCourt upheld the congressional power to enact publicfinancing of presidential elections under this Clause. TheSupreme Court stated with regard to the provisions in theFederal Election Campaign Act Amendments of 1974 establishinga presidential public financing system, ``In this case,Congress was legislating for the `general welfare'--to reducethe deleterious influence of large contributions on ourpolitical process, to facilitate communication by candidateswith the electorate, and to free candidates from the rigorsof fundraising.''[Page H7891]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
        <name>Committee on House Administration</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-09-18T13:10:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Empowering Citizens Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>270</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-01-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
            <name>Committee on House Administration</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000523</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Price, David E. [D-NC-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>DAVID</firstName>
        <lastName>PRICE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>V000128</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Van Hollen, Chris [D-MD-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Chris</firstName>
        <lastName>Van Hollen</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-09-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional elections</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elections, voting, political campaign regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Political advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax-exempt organizations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-10-29T14:40:33Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to treat as a campaign contribution any payment made by any person (other than a candidate, an authorized committee of a candidate, or a political committee of a political party) for a coordinated expenditure which is not otherwise treated as a contribution.</p> <p>Repeals the prohibition against contributions by minors.</p> <p>Sets forth rules governing payments for coordinated expenditures, including special rule for payments by coordinated spenders for covered communications.</p> <p>Defines &quot;covered communication&quot; as a public communication which: (1) promotes or supports the candidate, or attacks or opposes an opponent of the candidate (regardless of whether the communication expressly advocates the election or defeat of a candidate or contains the functional equivalent of express advocacy); or (2) refers to the candidate or an opponent of the candidate in other ways, but only if the communication is disseminated during the applicable election period.</p> <p>Prohibits candidates or individuals holding federal office, their agents, and certain related entities from soliciting, receiving, directing, or transferring funds to or on behalf of any political committee which accepts donations or contributions that do not comply with FECA limitations, prohibitions, and reporting requirements, or to or on behalf of any 527 organization which accepts such donations or contributions (other than a committee of a state or local political party or a candidate for election for state or local office).</p> <p>(A 527 organization, tax-exempt in certain circumstances under Section 527 of the Internal Revenue Code, is created primarily to influence the selection, nomination, election, appointment or defeat of candidates to federal, state or local public office.)</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to clarify the treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions to candidates, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to clarify the treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions to candidates, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to clarify the treatment of coordinated expenditures as contributions to candidates, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2014-09-18T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr5641ih/xml/BILLS-113hr5641ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-09-18</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
