<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3460</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:30Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:30Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-09-29T14:36:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6269)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000618</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Daines, Steve [R-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Steve</firstName>
        <lastName>Daines</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-11-10T21:28:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Local Community and Sportsmen Input in Monuments Act</b></p> <p>This bill makes the designation of a national monument by the President subject to the following consultation and approval requirements. </p> <p>No national monuments may be designated by the President unless:</p> <ul> <li>each county, borough, parish, or equivalent unit of local government within and adjacent to the boundaries of which the proposed monument is to be located has been consulted respecting the designation and has approved it; and</li> <li>the governor and the legislature of each state within the boundaries of which such monument is to be located has approved it. </li> </ul> <p>Any national monument that is designated subject to such requirements shall be open to hunting, fishing, other forms of recreation, grazing, and historic or traditional uses, unless the Department of the Interior, the Department of Agriculture (USDA), or the Department of the Army closes all or a portion of the monument to one or more of such uses in accordance with the purposes of federal law relating to monuments, ruins, sites, and objects of antiquity. </p> <p>Interior shall not impose any restrictions on hunting, fishing, grazing, wildlife management, or other historic or traditional uses at a national monument that is designated subject to this bill until the end of an appropriate review period which provides for, respecting the proposed restriction, concurrence by the applicable state wildlife management agencies, public input, and approval by Congress.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Local Community and Sportsmen Input in Monuments Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Local Community and Sportsmen Input in Monuments Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 54, United States Code, to provide certain limitations on the designation and use of national monuments.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Local Community and Sportsmen Input in Monuments Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-09-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3460is/xml/BILLS-114s3460is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6269)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
