<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2027</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:38:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:38:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-10-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-10-26T19:02:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>938</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-02-10</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>3921</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-10-23</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 263.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-10-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-10-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000449</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Portman, Rob [R-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rob</firstName>
        <lastName>Portman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-10-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2018-02-21T18:04:41Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</strong></p> <p>This bill alters provisions related to third-party liability for medical assistance paid under the Medicaid program. Specifically, with respect to such liability, the bill:</p> <ul> <li>expands the&nbsp;definition of "responsible third party"&nbsp;to include, among other health insurers,&nbsp;the TRICARE program; </li> <li>eliminates special rules with respect to certain services provided to children; </li> <li>requires the inclusion, in a contract between a state Medicaid program and a health insurer, of&nbsp;certain information regarding whether the state is delegating or transferring to the&nbsp;insurer a right of&nbsp;third-party recovery;&nbsp; </li> <li>provides for the treatment as overpayment of reimbursements made by a responsible third party to a health insurer; </li> <li>disallows a responsible third party from denying a state's claim solely on the basis of a failure to obtain a prior authorization;&nbsp; </li> <li>imposes a timeline for a responsible third party to respond to a state's inquiry regarding a claim for payment; </li> <li>provides for reductions to a state Medicaid program's federal matching rate&nbsp;if the state&nbsp;fails to comply with third-party insurance requirements; and </li> <li>modifies other provisions related to third-party liability under the Medicaid program.</li></ul> <p>Third-party liability requirements applicable&nbsp;under Medicaid&nbsp;shall also apply&nbsp;under the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).</p> <p>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services&nbsp;must:</p> <ul> <li>publish on its website, and annually update, best practices for assessing third-party liability; </li> <li>monitor and analyze efforts to assess that liability; </li> <li>in consultation with states, develop and make available a model uniform reporting field for identifying information related to responsible third parties; and </li> <li>provide other specified information and guidance to states.</li></ul>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Medicaid Third Party Liability Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide clarification with respect to the liability of third party payers for medical assistance paid under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-10-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s2027is/xml/BILLS-115s2027is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-10-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
