<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>639</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:34:41Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:34:41Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-03-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-03-21T16:32:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Online Communications and Geolocation Protection Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>983</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-04-08</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>GPS Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1312</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-04-15</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, And Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-03-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-03-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000779</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Wyden, Ron [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ron</firstName>
        <lastName>Wyden</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000360</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kirk, Mark Steven [R-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>KIRK</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>STEVEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-03-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computers and information technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal procedure and sentencing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone and wireless communication</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-03-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-04-15T22:02:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act or the GPS Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit intentionally: (1) intercepting geolocation information pertaining to another person; (2) disclosing to any other person such information pertaining to another, knowing that the information was obtained in violation of this Act; (3) using geolocation information, knowing that the information was obtained in violation of this Act; or (4) disclosing to any other person the geolocation information pertaining to another person intercepted by means authorized under this Act, knowing that the information was obtained in connection with a criminal investigation, having obtained or received information in connection with a criminal investigation, with intent to improperly obstruct, impede, or interfere with a duly authorized criminal investigation. Sets penalties for violations.</p> <p>Makes specified exceptions for interceptions involving: (1) information acquired by a provider of a covered service (electronic communication service, remote computing service, or geolocation information service) in the normal course of business; (2) federal officers, employees, or agents conducting foreign intelligence surveillance; (3) persons having given prior consent; (4) public information; (5) emergency information; (6) theft; and (7) a warrant.</p><p>Prohibits: (1) a person providing a covered service from intentionally divulging geolocation information pertaining to another person, with exceptions; and (2) the use of such information, and evidence derived from it, as evidence. Authorizes: (1) the use of geolocation information by investigative or law enforcement officers, or by a state's principal prosecuting attorney, to intercept such information under specified emergency circumstances; and (2) the recovery of civil damages by any person whose geolocation information is intercepted, disclosed, or intentionally used in violation of this Act.</p><p>Modifies the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to require a search warrant to acquire geolocation information.</p> <p> Amends the federal criminal code to include any geolocation information service within the definition of a &quot;covered entity&quot; for purposes of provisions prohibiting obtaining confidential phone records information from such an entity by fraud or related activity.</p> <p> Directs the United States Sentencing Commission to review the federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of fraud and related activity in connection with obtaining certain confidential phone records information. </p> <p>Prohibits acquiring geolocation information of a person for protective activities or law enforcement or intelligence purposes except pursuant to a warrant issued under the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>GPS Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to specify the circumstances in which a person may acquire geolocation information and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-03-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s639is/xml/BILLS-113s639is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-03-21</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
