<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2215</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:26:35Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:26:35Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-04-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-04-07T20:26:22Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-04-07</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S2196-2197)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-04-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001056</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cornyn, John [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Cornyn</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Treasury</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee leave</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internal Revenue Service (IRS)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax administration and collection, taxpayers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax-exempt organizations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-04-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-06-16T22:03:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Eliminating Improper and Abusive IRS Audits Act of 2014 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the maximum amount of civil damages for which Internal Revenue Service (IRS) officers or employees shall be liable for reckless, intentional, or negligent disregard of internal revenue laws and extend the period for bringing a claim for such damages; (2) increase the penalties against federal officers and employees for violations of internal revenue laws and for unauthorized inspection or disclosure of tax returns and return information; (3) extend the period in which taxpayer property that has been wrongfully levied upon may be returned and the period for bringing suit for a wrongful tax levy; (4) increase civil fines for unauthorized disclosures of tax return information; (5) prohibit the consideration by the IRS Office of Appeal on appeal of any issue that was not within the scope of the initial determination; (6) prohibit a tax lien against a taxpayer's principal residence unless a written determination is made that all other property of the taxpayer, if sold, is insufficient to pay the tax liability and the lien will not create an economic hardship for the taxpayer; (7) require the termination of an IRS employee for disproportionate scrutiny of an organization applying for tax-exempt status based on the ideology expressed in the name or purpose of the organization; (8) allow a declaratory judgment with respect to the initial or continuing classification of a tax-exempt social welfare organization; and (9) require the Inspector General for Tax Administration of the Department of the Treasury to review any IRS criteria for selection of tax returns for examination or audit, assessment or collection of deficiencies, criminal investigation or referral, refunds for amounts paid, or any heightened scrutiny or review to determine whether such criteria discriminates against taxpayers on the basis of race, religion, or political ideology and to consult with the IRS on recommended amendments to such criteria. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Eliminating Improper and Abusive IRS Audits Act of 2014</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Eliminating Improper and Abusive IRS Audits Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to protect taxpayers from improper audits by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Eliminating Improper and Abusive IRS Audits Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-04-07T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s2215is/xml/BILLS-113s2215is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-04-07</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S2196-2197)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
