<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3141</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:37:42Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:37:42Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-06-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 163, Number 112 (Thursday, June 29, 2017)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. LONG:H.R. 3141.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8--To make all Laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States or in anyDepartment of Officer thereof.Article I, Section 9--No Money shall be drawn from theTreasury, but in Consequence of Appropriations made by Law;and a regular Statement and Account of the Receipts andExpenditures of all public Money shall be published from timeto time.[Page H5378]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-06-29T14:03:30Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-06-29</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-06-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-06-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000576</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Long, Billy [R-MO-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>Billy</firstName>
        <lastName>Long</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MO</state>
        <district>7</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000460</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Farenthold, Blake [R-TX-27]</fullName>
        <firstName>Blake</firstName>
        <lastName>Farenthold</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>27</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-06-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marketing and advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax administration and collection, taxpayers</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-06-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-11-09T21:47:02Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill requires each communication funded by a federal agency that is an advertisement, or that provides information about any federal program, benefit, or service, to clearly state: (1) in the case of a printed communication, including mass mailings, signs, and billboards, that the communication is printed or published at taxpayer expense; and (2) in the case of a communication transmitted through radio, television, or the Internet, that the communication is produced or disseminated at taxpayer expense. Such notification must state that a communication is provided by the U.S. government, rather than at taxpayer expense, if the communication is funded entirely by user fees or by other sources that do not include federal funds.</p> <p>The bill requires any such printed communication to be of sufficient size to be clearly readable, to be contained in a printed box set apart from the other contents of the communication, and to be printed with a reasonable degree of color contrast between the background and the printed statement. The bill sets forth similar requirements for audio, video, and email communications.</p> <p>The Office of Management and Budget must develop and issue guidance on implementing the requirements of this bill. </p> <p>The bill prohibits judicial review of compliance with this bill. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To require a Federal agency to include language in certain educational and advertising materials indicating that such materials are produced and disseminated at taxpayer expense, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Taxpayer Transparency Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2017-06-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115hr3141ih/xml/BILLS-115hr3141ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-06-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
