<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>481</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:35:24Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:35:24Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-03-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-03-01T17:34:43Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-03-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001267</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bennet, Michael F. [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>Michael</firstName>
        <lastName>Bennet</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coal</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Colorado</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electric power generation and transmission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy revenues and royalties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mining</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public utilities and utility rates</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-03-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-10-17T19:58:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Thompson Divide Withdrawal and Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill withdraws the Thompson Divide Withdrawal and Protection Area in Colorado from: (1) entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>In exchange for the relinquishment of all of the North Thompson Divide leases or South Thompson Divide leases of a leaseholder, the Department of the Interior may issue to such leaseholder credits for bid, royalty, or rental payments due under federal oil and gas leases on federal land in Colorado. Upon relinquishment, such leases shall be permanently canceled and shall not be reissued. </p> <p>As a condition for relinquishing South Thompson Divide leases, a leaseholder must permanently relinquish, transfer, and otherwise convey to Interior all of its Wolf Creek Storage Field development rights, excluding any storage rights or related activities within the area. </p> <p>Interior shall: (1) complete, or shall collaborate with state agencies or institutions of higher education in Colorado to complete, an inventory of all significant methane emissions in the North Fork Valley, including emissions from active, inactive, and abandoned coal mines; (2) carry out a program to lease federal methane from such mines; and (3) enter into discussions to develop a program to facilitate the sale and delivery of such methane that has not been leased to at least one rural electric utility, municipal utility, or energy cooperative with service area boundaries within 100 miles of Paonia, Colorado, to demonstrate the feasibility, cost-effectiveness, and environmental benefits of producing electrical power from methane collected from coal mines. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Thompson Divide Withdrawal and Protection Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Thompson Divide Withdrawal and Protection Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the withdrawal and protection of certain Federal land in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Thompson Divide Withdrawal and Protection Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-03-01T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s481is/xml/BILLS-115s481is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-03-01</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
