<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2286</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:26:22Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:26:22Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-05-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-05-01T22:20:04Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Commonsense Contractor Compensation Act of 2013</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>2444</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-06-19</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Commonsense Contractor Compensation Act of 2013</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>1192</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-06-19</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000818</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Walsh, John E. [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Walsh</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Defense</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military procurement, research, weapons development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Service industries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wages and earnings</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-06-26T19:13:29Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Cutting Contractor Use and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2014 - Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Defense (DOD) to submit to the congressional defense committees, and make publicly available, an annual comprehensive analysis of the global inventory of DOD service contractors.</p> <p>Requires the Defense Contract Audit Agency, in conducting audits of defense contracts, to distinguish service contracts in its analysis, including by distinguishing the percentage of payment awarded for service elements on contracts containing both manufacturing and service elements. Directs the Agency to submit to the congressional defense committees, and make publicly available, an annual report on its findings.</p> <p>Directs the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology and Logistics to submit a plan to the congressional defense committees to improve the acquisition of services by DOD.</p> <p>Requires the Director of National Intelligence to submit to the congressional defense and intelligence committees an annual inventory of the service contractors used by each element of the intelligence community.</p> <p>Prohibits civilian or defense contracts from allowing compensation of contractor and subcontractor employees for a fiscal year to exceed the annual salary of the President (currently, $400,000). Allows an exception to such limitation for scientists, engineers, or other specialists who are needed to ensure that an executive agency has continued access to needed skills and capabilities. </p> <p>Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to submit an annual report to specified congressional committees on contractor compensation, including the number of contractor employees who were exempt in the preceding fiscal year from this Act's compensation limits. </p> <p>Prohibits the aggregate amount obligated and expended by DOD for service contracts in each fiscal year through FY2024 from exceeding the lesser of: (1) 67% of the aggregate amount expended for service contracts in FY2014, or (2) 67% of the amount appropriated for DOD for the current fiscal year that is available for service contracts. Makes the latter limitation inapplicable if the Secretary certifies to Congress in writing that DOD will not exceed the prior limitation.</p> <p>Prohibits the aggregate amount obligated and expended by DOD for service contracts in each fiscal year after FY2023 from exceeding the amount obligated or expended by DOD on service contracts in FY2002 (adjusted for inflation).</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Cutting Contractor Use and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2014</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Cutting Contractor Use and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for greater oversight of Department of Defense service contracts.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Cutting Contractor Use and Taxpayer Savings Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-05-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s2286is/xml/BILLS-113s2286is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-05-01</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
