<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6000</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:49Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:49Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 138 (Tuesday, September 13, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. SANFORD:H.R. 6000.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article 1, Section 8 of the United States Constitutionasserts that the Congress shall have power to lay and collecttaxes. This bill modifies the Internal Revenue Code of 1986to modify the rules relating to the taxation of mead andother agricultural wine.[Page H5436]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-09-13T14:00:17Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000051</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Sanford, Mark [R-SC-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Sanford</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>SC</state>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000469</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Tonko, Paul [D-NY-20]</fullName>
        <firstName>Paul</firstName>
        <lastName>Tonko</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <district>20</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-03-08T14:43:51Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Mead Equality And Definition Act of 2016 or the MEAD Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify rules regarding the taxation of mead (honey wine) and other agricultural wines. </p> <p>The bill repeals the limitations on adding wine spirits to an agricultural wine or using any coloring material, herbs, or other flavoring material (except hops in the case of honey wine) in the production. </p> <p>The Department of the Treasury must modify regulations for the production of agricultural wine to allow: (1) the use of spirits in the production of agricultural wine; and (2) additional ingredients to be added during the production of mead, including limited amounts of fruits, vegetables, spices, and other ingredients that are suitable for human food consumption and safe for use in an alcoholic beverage.</p> <p>In modifying the regulations, Treasury must also:</p> <ul> <li>eliminate limitations on the quantity of hops used in mead; </li> <li>specify certain requirements for the density of the honey and water mixture when additional ingredients are added to mead;</li> <li> limit the alcohol content of mead to 24% by volume; and</li> <li>allow an agricultural wine to be produced for research and development without an approved formula, as long as the wine is not marketed or sold prior to approval of the formula.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also: (1) specifies a tax rate of 22.6 cents per gallon for mead containing not more than 0.64 grams of carbon dioxide per hundred milliliters of mead, and (2) allows a credit against such tax on meads for small domestic producers. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>MEAD Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>MEAD Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>MEAD Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Mead Equality And Definition Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify rules relating to the taxation of mead and other agricultural wine, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-09-13T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr6000ih/xml/BILLS-114hr6000ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-13</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
