<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2484</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:25:06Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:25:06Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-06-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2014-12-08T22:49:36Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2014-09-17T18:30:00Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-06-17T22:25:12Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 113-315</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-315.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-12</actionDate>
        <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-315.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14900</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 622.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-06-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coast guard</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International law and treaties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judicial review and appeals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Northern Mariana Islands</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oceania</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-06-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-11-25T21:52:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act - Authorizes the Department of Commerce to promulgate regulations to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, which was adopted at Auckland, New Zealand, on November 14, 2009. (The Convention includes the objectives of ensuring the long term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and safeguarding the marine ecosystems in the Convention Area.) Applies this Act within the boundaries of any state bordering on the Convention Area if specified conditions are met.</p> <p> Requires the President to appoint the U.S. representative to the South Pacific Fisheries Commission. Establishes an advisory committee for the Commission.</p> <p> Requires Commerce to develop a memorandum of understanding with the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council to clarify the role of the Council with respect to participating in or working with U.S. delegations to international fishery organizations and making recommendations related to fishery resources in the Convention Area. </p> <p> Sets forth the Department of State's authority and responsibilities with respect to the Commission.</p> <p> Requires Commerce and the Department of Homeland Security (the department in which the Coast Guard is operating) to administer and enforce this Act, except to the extent otherwise provided for in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act. </p> <p>Sets forth prohibited fishing and shipping acts in the Convention Area.</p> <p> Establishes notification requirements commercial fishing vessels before entering or transiting the exclusive economic zone of the Convention Area, if the vessels do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-12-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-04-10T20:40:34Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act - Authorizes Department of Commerce to promulgate regulations to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, which was adopted at Auckland, New Zealand, on November 14, 2009. (The Convention includes the objectives of ensuring the long term conservation and sustainable use of fishery resources and safeguarding the marine ecosystems in the Convention Area.) </p> <p> (Sec. 3) Limits U.S. representation on the South Pacific Fisheries Commission to no more than three commissioners. Requires the President to appoint the representative to the Commission. Establishes an advisory committee for the Commission.</p> <p> Requires Commerce to develop a memorandum of understanding with the Western Pacific Regional Fishery Management Council to clarify the role of the Council with respect to participating in or working with U.S. delegations to international fishery organizations and making recommendations related to fishery resources in the Convention Area. </p> <p> (Sec. 4) Sets forth Department of State's authority and responsibilities with respect to the Commission, including authorizing the State Department to approve, disapprove, object to, or withdraw objections to bylaws and rules adopted by the Commission.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Authorizes Commerce to promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the U.S. international obligations under the South Pacific Fisheries Convention and this Act.</p> <p> Requires Commerce and Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to administer and enforce this Act, except to the extent otherwise provided for in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act. </p> <p>Gives the district courts of the United States exclusive jurisdiction over any case or controversy arising under this Act.</p> <p> (Sec. 7) Sets forth prohibited fishing and shipping acts in the Convention Area. <p>(Sec. 9) Requires Commerce to ensure participation in the Commission and its subsidiary bodies by the by American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to the same extent provided to the territories of other nations.</p> <p> (Sec. 10) Establishes notification requirements commercial fishing vessels before entering or transiting the exclusive economic zone of the Convention Area, if the vessels do not carry vessel monitoring systems capable of communicating with U.S. enforcement authorities.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations to Commerce and the State Department to carry out this Act and to pay for the United State's contribution to the Commission.</p> <p>Requires Commerce or the State Department to provide appropriate assistance to assist developing nations in meeting their obligations under the Convention.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to implement the Convention on the Conservation and Management of the High Seas Fishery Resources in the South Pacific Ocean, as adopted at Auckland on November 14, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>South Pacific Fisheries Convention Implementation Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2014-12-08T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s2484rs/xml/BILLS-113s2484rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-06-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s2484is/xml/BILLS-113s2484is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-12-12</actionDate>
      <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 113-315.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
