<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2912</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:24:20Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:24:20Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-08-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. CHAFFETZ:H.R. 2912.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Clause 1 of Section 8 of Article I of the Constitution: TheCongress shall have Power To lay and collect Taxes, Duties,Imposts and Excises, to pay the Debts and provide for thecommon Defence and general Welfare of the United States; butall Duties, Imposts and Excises shall be uniform throughoutthe United States;Clause 14 of Section 8 of Article I of the Constitution: Tomake Rules for the Government and Regulation of the land andnaval Forces;Clause 18 of Section 8 of Article I of the Constitution: Tomake all Laws which shall be necessary and proper forcarrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, and all otherPowers vested by this Constitution in the Government of theUnited States, or in any Department or Officer thereof.[Page H5345]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-08-01T14:05:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-08-01T14:05:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001076</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Chaffetz, Jason [R-UT-3]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jason</firstName>
        <lastName>Chaffetz</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <district>3</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001077</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Coffman, Mike [R-CO-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Coffman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-08-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000266</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Tierney, John F. [D-MA-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>TIERNEY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-08-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001175</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Speier, Jackie [D-CA-14]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jackie</firstName>
        <lastName>Speier</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>14</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2013-08-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Afghanistan</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Asia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Reconstruction and stabilization</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-11-06T17:21:12Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Afghanistan Suspension and Debarment Reform Act - Amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (the Act) to add to the powers of the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction (Inspector General), who is required to conduct, supervise, and coordinate audits and investigations of the treatment, handling, and expenditure of funds appropriated by the U.S. government, and of the programs, operations, and contracts carried out using such funds in Afghanistan, in order to prevent and detect waste, fraud, and abuse.</p> <p>Empowers the Inspector General to refer to the lead agency a potential covered case for suspension or debarment of a person from procurement or nonprocurement activities of the federal government. </p> <p>Defines a &quot;covered case&quot; as one involving a person that is an Afghan national or foreign national or foreign company operating in Afghanistan that has received in the past, is receiving, or may receive in the future, funds from any covered prime contract or subcontract.</p> <p>Requires the Inspector General to notify the Interagency Committee on Debarment and Suspension and Congress if such a referral is made. </p> <p>Requires the lead agency, after the referral of such a suspension or debarment case, to accept or decline the case. </p> <p>Requires the Interagency Committee, if the lead agency declines to accept a suspension or debarment case, or fails to respond to the referral, to determine whether the Inspector General shall act as the lead agency. </p> <p>Requires the lead agency, on the other hand, if it accepts a suspension or debarment case, to either suspend or debar the person that is the subject of the case or decline. </p> <p>Authorizes the Inspector General (or designee), if the Interagency Committee determines that the Inspector General may act as lead agency, to suspend or debar the person from federal procurement or nonprocurement activities.</p> <p>Allows the Inspector General (or designee), when exercising such authority, to grant an exception permitting a person otherwise debarred or suspended to submit an offer for or be awarded a particular contract, grant, or procurement or nonprocurement activity.</p> <p>Directs the Comptroller General (GAO), after the termination of the Office of Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction, to study the Inspector General authority and the process for determining a lead agency in a suspension or debarment case. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Afghanistan Suspension and Debarment Reform Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Afghanistan Suspension and Debarment Reform Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide authority for the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction to suspend and debar contractors under certain circumstances.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Afghanistan Suspension and Debarment Reform Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2013-08-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113hr2912ih/xml/BILLS-113hr2912ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-08-01</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
