<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3377</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-09-21T21:28:49Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000711</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Boxer, Barbara [D-CA]</fullName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <lastName>BOXER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001181</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Shaheen, Jeanne [D-NH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeanne</firstName>
        <lastName>Shaheen</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NH</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-09-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-12-05T19:04:43Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of State, in coordination with the Department of Defense (DOD), to seek to increase the participation of women receiving training under the International Military Education and Training program at U.S. military schools and training institutions, with the goal of doubling female participation globally by September 30, 2019.</p> <p>The State Department shall seek to increase the participation of women receiving training under its Anti-Terrorism Assistance (ATA) programs, with the goal of doubling the total women receiving such training by September 30, 2019, and make explicit in its mandate for ATA programs its priority to increase women's participation.</p> <p>State shall work with partner countries receiving peacekeeping training assistance to: (1) prioritize the integration, training, and deployment of qualified female peacekeepers in peace operations; (2) prioritize the employment, development, and integration of female peacekeeping trainers; and (3) double the number of qualified women deployed to peace operations within five years.</p> <p>State also shall: </p> <ul> <li> promote an increase in the recruitment, retention, and leadership roles of female personnel assigned to United Nations peacekeeping missions; </li> <li>establish female participation requirements for its police training programs and work with partner countries to ensure that women account for at least 10% of nominees for U.S.-funded police training programs;</li> <li>make explicit its priority to increase women's participation in the design and implementation of all police training programs;</li> <li>develop a plan for the monitoring and independent evaluation of programs, projects, and activities carried out under this bill; and </li> <li>designate officials to brief Congress regarding actions taken under this Act.</li> </ul>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to increase the participation of women in foreign security forces, specifically the military and police, with United States foreign assistance.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Enhancing Military and Police Operations through Women's Engagement and Recruitment Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-09-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3377is/xml/BILLS-114s3377is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-21</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
