<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1852</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:38:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:38:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-09-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-09-25T21:54:23Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Recognizing America's Children Act</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>1468</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-03-22</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-09-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-09-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000476</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tillis, Thomas [R-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Tillis</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName>Roland</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000575</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lankford, James [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Lankford</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-09-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-09-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Immigration</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Border security and unlawful immigration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Citizenship and naturalization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Justice</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigration status and procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Visas and passports</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Immigration</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-09-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2019-02-14T18:30:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Solution for Undocumented Children through Careers, Employment, Education, and Defending our Nation Act or the SUCCEED Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security to cancel the removal of otherwise inadmissible or deportable aliens who entered the United States as children and grant them conditional permanent resident status. The conditional permanent resident status of such aliens shall be valid for an initial period of five years if they came to the United States before the age of 16 and have lived in the United States continuously since June 15, 2012. Such aliens must demonstrate that they were younger than age 31 on June 15, 2012, and had no lawful status in the United States. </p> <p>The bill imposes other requirements upon such aliens, including educational attainments, good moral character, lack of criminal history, and compliance with tax responsibilities. The bill extends conditional permanent resident status for an additional five years if an alien continues to show good moral character, has no tax liabilities, is not receiving federal benefits, has graduated from college or attended a postsecondary school, or has served in the military. </p> <p>The bill permits alien children to apply for the removal of conditional status after 10 years and adjust to lawful permanent residence upon a showing that they have been a conditional permanent resident for at least 10 years, have demonstrated good moral character during that period, have met other age and residency requirement, and have not abandoned residence in the United States. An alien may apply for naturalization five years after adjustment of status to lawful permanent residence under the terms of this bill. </p> <p>Aliens who violate the requirements of this bill or commit certain crimes are subject to expedited removal without an immigration court hearing. </p> <p>Aliens with conditional or lawful permanent resident status under this bill may not sponsor family members, including spouses and children, to obtain legal status in the United States. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>SUCCEED Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>SUCCEED Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>SUCCEED Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Solution for Undocumented Children through Careers, Employment, Education, and Defending our Nation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status of certain aliens who are long-term United States residents and who entered the United States as children, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-09-25T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s1852is/xml/BILLS-115s1852is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-09-25</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
