<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1954</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:27:37Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:27:37Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-04-22</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 161, Number 59 (Wednesday, April 22, 2015)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. FINCHER:H.R. 1954.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8--To make all Laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by thisConstitution in the Government of the United States or in anyDepartment or Officer thereof.[Page H2418]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-04-22T14:05:40Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-22</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsag00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-22</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000458</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Fincher, Stephen Lee [R-TN-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Stephen</firstName>
        <lastName>Fincher</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TN</state>
        <middleName>Lee</middleName>
        <district>8</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Banking and financial institutions regulation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commodities markets</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commodity Futures Trading Commission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-04-22</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-05-13T18:31:00Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</b></p> <p> Directs the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to amend regulations regarding criteria qualifying certain registered commodity pool operators for exemption from requirements for specified risk disclosures, performance disclosures, periodic reporting, annual reporting, and recordkeeping.</p> <p>Alters one criterion for qualification for such exemptions currently granted to: (1) registered commodity pool operators who sell participations in a pool solely to qualified eligible persons in an offering which qualifies for exemption from the registration requirements of the Securities Act, and (2) certain banks registered as commodity pool operators in connection with a pool that is a collective trust fund whose securities are exempt from registration under the Securities Act.</p> <p>Repeals the current additional criterion for such banks that the securities must be offered or sold, without marketing to the public, solely to qualified eligible persons. Replaces such criterion with one stating simply that the securities must be sold solely to qualified eligible persons. (Thus, eliminates the requirement that such securities be offered or sold without marketing to the public, and so allows such marketing.)</p> <p>Repeals the current prerequisite for exemption of interests in a commodity pool from registration under the Securities Act of 1933 that such interests be offered and sold without marketing to the public in the United States. Requires such interests, instead, simply to be offered and sold pursuant to specified requirements for exempted transactions. (Thus, also eliminates the requirement that such interests be offered and sold without marketing to the public in the United States, and so allows such marketing.)</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To align exemptions for general solicitation of investment in commodity pools similar to the exemption provided for general solicitation of securities under the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Energize Emerging Opportunities Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2015-04-22T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr1954ih/xml/BILLS-114hr1954ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-04-22</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
