<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2008</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:29:56Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:56Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-08-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
        <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-08-06T17:41:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-08-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
            <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-08-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001176</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Merkley, Jeff [D-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <lastName>Merkley</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Child care and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commuting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment and training programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health care coverage and access</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing supply and affordability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pedestrians and bicycling</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public transit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Regional and metropolitan planning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Urban and suburban affairs and development</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-08-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-03-28T22:20:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</b></p> <p> This bill modifies transportation programs to establish a goal of achieving an interconnected transportation system that connects people to jobs, schools, and essential services; and to require more data and public input during the planning process. </p> <p>States and metropolitan planning organizations (MPOs) must permit the public to provide input during the development and implementation of transportation plans. </p> <p>(MPOs are federally required and funded organizations responsible for the regional transportation planning process in certain urban areas.) </p> <p>The bill revises the goals of the federal highway program to include achieving an interconnected transportation system which connects people to jobs, schools, and other essential services through a multimodal network. The Department of Transportation (DOT) may establish a performance measure for MPOs to measure transportation connectivity. </p> <p>DOT must establish the Connection to Opportunity Pilot Program for up to 10 MPOs to develop and implement projects to improve multimodal connectivity and increase connections for transportation-disadvantaged individuals and neighborhoods with limited transportation options. The participating MPOs must submit performance data to DOT, and DOT must use the data to evaluate the programs and consider developing a national indicator to measure multimodal connections to opportunities. </p> <p>DOT must create and maintain data sets and analysis tools to assist MPOs, states, and entities within DOT in carrying out performance management analyses. </p> <p>The bill permanently extends the authorization for the Transportation Alternatives Program, revises federal share requirements, and permits nonprofit organizations and certain MPOs to receive funding under the program. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to enhance transportation programs in order to achieve an interconnected transportation system which connects people to jobs, schools, and other essential services through a multimodal network, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Transportation, Access, and Opportunity Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-08-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2008is/xml/BILLS-114s2008is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-08-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
