<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2855</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:07Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:07Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-04-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sssb00</systemCode>
        <name>Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-04-26T22:11:01Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>SBIR and STTR Reauthorization and Improvement Act of 2016</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2812</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-12-20</actionDate>
          <text>By Senator Vitter from Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship filed written report under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/10/2016. Report No. 114-417.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sssb00</systemCode>
            <name>Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Peters, Gary C. [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Gary</firstName>
        <lastName>Peters</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Commerce</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority and disadvantaged businesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science and engineering education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology transfer and commercialization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women in business</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Commerce</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-04-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-08-15T20:32:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Small Business Innovation Research and Technology Transfer Inclusive Outreach Improvement Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to empower the Small Business Administration (SBA) to coordinate with participating federal agencies on efforts to increase outreach and awards under each of the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) programs to small business concerns owned and controlled by women and socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns.</p> <p>Each federal agency required to establish an SBIR or an STTR program shall enhance its program by extending an outreach program to small business concerns, especially those owned and controlled by women and socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns.</p> <p>The SBA shall modify its STTR policy directive to enhance these outreach efforts.</p> <p>The SBIR/STTR Reauthorization Act of 2011 is amended to require the Interagency SBIR/STTR Policy Committee to meet at least twice a year, and if it discusses outreach and technical assistance activities to increase the participation of underrepresented small business concerns to invite to the meeting a representative of the Minority Business Development Agency as well as relevant stakeholders that advance the interests of small business concerns owned and controlled by women and socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns.</p> <p>The SBA shall establish a Diversity and STEM Workforce Development Pilot Program under which a federal agency participating in the SBIR program or STTR program may make a $15,000 per fiscal year grant to one or more eligible entities for the costs of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics internships.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Small Business Innovation Research and Technology Transfer Inclusive Outreach Improvement Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Small Business Innovation Research and Technology Transfer Inclusive Outreach Improvement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to increase outreach for women and minority-owned businesses under the Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer programs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Small Business Innovation Research and Technology Transfer Inclusive Outreach Improvement Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-04-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2855is/xml/BILLS-114s2855is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-04-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
