<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>185</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-01-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 161, Number 2 (Wednesday, January 7, 2015)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. GOODLATTE:H.R. 185.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 1, Clause 1 of the United StatesConstitution, in that the legislation concerns the exerciseof legislative powers generally granted to Congress by thatsection, including the exercise of those powers whendelegated by Congress to the Executive; Article I, Section 8,Clauses 1 to 17, and Section 9, Clauses 1 to 2, 4, and 7 ofthe United States Constitution, in that the legislationconcerns the exercise of specific legislative powers grantedto Congress by those sections, including the exercise ofthose powers when delegated by Congress to the Executive;Article I, Section 8, clause 18 of the United StatesConstitution, in that the legislation exercises legislativepower granted to Congress by that clause ``to make all Lawswhich shall be necessary and proper for carrying intoExecution the foregoing Powers, and all other Powers vestedby this Constitution in the Government of the United States,or in any Department or Officer thereof;'' and Article III,Section 1, Clause 1, Sentence 1, Section 2, Clause 1, andSection 2, Clause 2, Sentence 2, of the Constitution, in thatthe legislation defines or affects judicial powers and casesthat are subject to legislation by Congess.[Page H104]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-01-16T15:57:34Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2015-01-12T14:08:00Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-01-07T15:01:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 37) to make technical corrections to the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, to enhance the ability of small and emerging growth companies to access capital through public and private markets, to reduce regulatory burdens, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 185) to reform the process by which Federal agencies analyze and formulate new regulations and guidance documents; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 240) making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2015, and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>27</number>
        <type>HRES</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
          <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
          <actionTime>14:31:24</actionTime>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:30:28</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:30:26</actionTime>
        <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 250 - 175 (Roll no. 28).</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <recordedVotes>
          <recordedVote>
            <rollNumber>28</rollNumber>
            <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll028.xml</url>
            <chamber>House</chamber>
            <congress>114</congress>
            <date>2015-01-13T22:30:26Z</date>
            <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
          </recordedVote>
        </recordedVotes>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:30:26</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed by recorded vote: 250 - 175 (Roll no. 28).</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <recordedVotes>
          <recordedVote>
            <rollNumber>28</rollNumber>
            <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll028.xml</url>
            <chamber>House</chamber>
            <congress>114</congress>
            <date>2015-01-13T22:30:26Z</date>
            <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
          </recordedVote>
        </recordedVotes>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:22:40</actionTime>
        <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 180 - 245 (Roll no. 27).</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H36110</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <recordedVotes>
          <recordedVote>
            <rollNumber>27</rollNumber>
            <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll027.xml</url>
            <chamber>House</chamber>
            <congress>114</congress>
            <date>2015-01-13T22:22:40Z</date>
            <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
          </recordedVote>
        </recordedVotes>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:15:03</actionTime>
        <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection. (consideration: CR H271)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8A000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:09:10</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rice (NY) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add a section to the bill prohibiting the application of any rules or guidance by the Act or amendments that prevent terrorism and crime; protect wages of workers; save tax dollars; provide assistance to small business; or prevent discrimination.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:08:28</actionTime>
        <text>Miss Rice (NY) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on the Judiciary. (consideration: CR H270-271; text: CR H270)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H36100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:08:01</actionTime>
        <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H34400</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>17:07:26</actionTime>
        <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 185.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32600</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:22:53</actionTime>
        <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier, and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:22:07</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Connolly amendment, the Chair put t he question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Connolly demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:14:48</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 27, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Connolly Part A amendment No. 4.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:14:09</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:06:58</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 27, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee Part A amendment No. 3.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:06:23</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Johnson (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Johnson (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:58:35</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 27, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Johnson (GA) Part A amendment No. 2.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:57:53</actionTime>
        <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McKinley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McKinely demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:46:10</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 27, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKinley Part A amendment No. 1.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:39:28</actionTime>
        <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 185.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:39:16</actionTime>
        <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lynn A. Westmoreland to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32400</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:39:14</actionTime>
        <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 27 and Rule XVIII.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H32020</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:39:01</actionTime>
        <text>All points of order against consideration of the bills are waived. H.R. 37 H.R. 185 shall be debatable for 1 hour, and H.R. 240 shall be debatable for 2 hours the previous question considered orderedwithout intervening motions except one motion to recommit. For H.R. 185, only those amendments printed in Part A of the report shall be in order. For H.R. 240, only those amendments printed in Part B of the report shall be in order.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:38:56</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 27. (consideration: CR H249-272; text of measure as introduced: CR H256-260)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>21:44:24</actionTime>
        <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 27 Reported to House. All points of order against consideration of the bills are waived. H.R. 37 H.R. 185 shall be debatable for 1 hour, and H.R. 240 shall be debatable for 2 hours the previous question considered ordered without intervening motions except one motion to recommit. For H.R. 185, only those amendments printed in Part A of the report shall be in order. For H.R. 240, only those amendments printed in Part B of the report shall be in order. in Part B of the report shall be in order.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H1L210</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju05</systemCode>
            <name>Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000289</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Goodlatte, Bob [R-VA-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>ROBERT</firstName>
        <lastName>GOODLATTE</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>W.</middleName>
        <district>6</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000258</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Peterson, Collin C. [D-MN-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>COLLIN</firstName>
        <lastName>PETERSON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <middleName>C.</middleName>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>21</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001179</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Marino, Tom [R-PA-10]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <lastName>Marino</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <district>10</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000250</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Sessions, Pete [R-TX-32]</fullName>
        <firstName>PETE</firstName>
        <lastName>SESSIONS</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>32</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000448</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Franks, Trent [R-AZ-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Trent</firstName>
        <lastName>Franks</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001195</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Jason [R-MO-8]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jason</firstName>
        <lastName>Smith</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MO</state>
        <district>8</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001093</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Collins, Doug [R-GA-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>Doug</firstName>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <district>9</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001059</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Hultgren, Randy [R-IL-14]</fullName>
        <firstName>Randy</firstName>
        <lastName>Hultgren</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <district>14</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000475</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Trott, David A. [R-MI-11]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Trott</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <district>11</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-09</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001087</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Crawford, Eric A. "Rick" [R-AR-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>Eric</firstName>
        <lastName>Crawford</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <middleName>A. "Rick"</middleName>
        <district>1</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000619</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Davis, Rodney [R-IL-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>Rodney</firstName>
        <lastName>Davis</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <district>13</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000588</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Pearce, Stevan [R-NM-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>Stevan</firstName>
        <lastName>Pearce</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001065</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Holding, George [R-NC-13]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>Holding</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <district>13</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000445</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Forbes, J. Randy [R-VA-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>J.</firstName>
        <lastName>Forbes</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>Randy</middleName>
        <district>4</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000184</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Noem, Kristi L. [R-SD-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kristi</firstName>
        <lastName>Noem</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>SD</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>0</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000363</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Kline, John [R-MN-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Kline</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001096</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Cramer, Kevin [R-ND-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kevin</firstName>
        <lastName>Cramer</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ND</state>
        <district>0</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000603</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rouzer, David [R-NC-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Rouzer</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>E000294</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Emmer, Tom [R-MN-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <lastName>Emmer</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000597</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rice, Tom [R-SC-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tom</firstName>
        <lastName>Rice</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>SC</state>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001048</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Culberson, John Abney [R-TX-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>CULBERSON</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <middleName>ABNEY</middleName>
        <district>7</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-01-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic performance and conditions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judicial review and appeals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Office of Management and Budget (OMB)</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-01-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-01-13T19:53:34Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Administrative Procedure Act to revise and expand the requirements for federal agency rulemaking by requiring agencies, in making a rule, to base all preliminary and final factual determinations on evidence and to consider the legal authority under which the rule may be proposed, the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with the rule, any reasonable alternatives for the rule, and the potential costs and benefits associated with such alternatives.</p> <p>The bill requires agencies to publish advance notice of proposed rulemaking in the Federal Register for major rules and for high-impact rules (rules having an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or $1 billion or more, respectively) and for negative-impact on jobs and wages rules and those that involve a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates. The notice must include a written statement identifying the nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule, the legal authority under which the rule may be proposed, the nature of and potential reasons to adopt a novel legal or policy position, and a solicitation for written data, views, or arguments from interested persons.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill: (1) sets forth criteria for issuing major guidance (agency guidance that is likely to lead to an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or more, a major increase in cost or prices, or significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or ability to compete) or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates; and (2) expands the scope of judicial review of agency rulemaking by allowing immediate review of rulemaking not in compliance with notice requirements and establishing a substantial evidence standard for affirming agency rulemaking decisions.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>36</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-04-13T19:11:37Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</strong> </p> <p> (Sec. 2) Defines "major rule" and "major guidance" for purposes of this Act as a rule or guidance that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) determines is likely to impose: (1)&nbsp;an annual cost on the economy of $100 million or more, adjusted annually for inflation; (2)&nbsp;a major increase in costs or prices; (3)&nbsp;significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of U.S. enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises; or (4) significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy.&nbsp; </p> <p>Defines: (1) "high-impact rule" as a rule that the Administrator determines is likely to have an annual cost on the economy of $1 billion or more, adjusted annually for inflation; and (2) &quot;negative-impact on jobs and wages rule&quot; as any rule likely to reduce employment or wages in certain economic sectors or industry areas by specified amounts over specified periods.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Revises procedures for rule making under the Administrative Procedure Act (APA) to require a federal agency, in the rule making process, to make all preliminary and final factual determinations based on evidence and to consider: (1) the legal authority under which a rule may be proposed; (2) the specific nature and significance of the problem the agency may address with a rule; (3) whether existing rules have created or contributed to the problem the agency may address with a rule and whether such rules may be amended or rescinded; (4) any reasonable alternatives for a new rule; and (5) the potential costs and benefits associated with potential alternative rules, including impacts on low-income populations.</p> <p>Revises rule making notice requirements to require an agency to: </p> <ul> <li> publish in the Federal Register&nbsp;advance notice of proposed rule making involving a major or high-impact rule, a negative impact on jobs and wages rule,&nbsp;or a rule that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates; </li> <li> consult with the Administrator before issuing a proposed rule and after the issuance of an advance notice of proposed rule making;</li> <li> provide interested persons an opportunity to participate in the rule making process; </li> <li> hold a hearing before the adoption of any high-impact rule; </li> <li> expand requirements for the adoption of a final rule, including requiring that the agency adopt a rule only on the basis of the best evidence and at the least cost; and </li> <li> grant any interested person the right to petition for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule.&nbsp; </li> </ul> <p>Specifies the minimum amount of information that must be included in an advance notice of a proposed rule making.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to issue guidelines to promote coordination, simplification, and harmonization of agency rules during the rule making process.</p> <p>Exempts from such revised procedures rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Imposes new requirements for issuing any major guidance or guidance that involves a novel legal or policy issue arising out of statutory mandates. Authorizes the Administrator to issue guidelines for agencies in issuing major guidance or other guidance.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Provides for electronic access to transcripts of testimony and exhibits and other papers filed in a rule making proceeding. </p> <p>Requires the record of decision in a rule making proceeding to include information from a hearing under the Information Quality Act or on a high-impact rule.</p> <p>Requires an agency to grant a petition for a hearing in the case of a major rule, unless the agency reasonably determines that a hearing would not advance consideration of the rule or would unreasonably delay completion of the rule making. Exempts from this requirement rule makings that concern monetary policy proposed or implemented by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Open Market Committee.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Provides that an agency's denial of an Information Quality Act petition, or a failure&nbsp;to grant or deny&nbsp;such petition within 90 days, is reviewable by a court as a final action.&nbsp; Allows immediate judicial review of interim rules, other than in cases involving national security interests, issued without compliance with the notice requirements of this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Revises standards for the scope of judicial review of agency rule making to prohibit a court from deferring to an agency's: (1) interpretation of a rule if the agency did not comply with APA requirements, (2) determination of the costs and benefits or other economic or risk assessment if the agency failed to conform to guidelines on such determinations and assessments established by the Administrator, (3) determinations made in the adoption of an interim rule, or (4) guidance.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Defines "substantial evidence" for purposes of evaluating agency adjudications and for rule making under APA as such relevant evidence as a reasonable mind might accept as adequate to support a conclusion in light of the record considered as a whole, taking into account whatever in the record fairly detracts from the weight of the evidence relied upon by the agency to support its decision.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) Provides that the amendments made by this Act to specified provisions of federal law shall not apply to any rule makings pending or completed on the enactment date of this Act. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To reform the process by which Federal agencies analyze and formulate new regulations and guidance documents.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>5</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>Amendment sought to exempt from the bill any rule or guidance pertaining to public health or safety.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment sought to exempt from the bill any rule or guidance pertaining to public health or safety.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2020-12-15T18:00:00Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the Connolly amendment (A004) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 248 (Roll no. 26).</text>
          <actionTime>17:07:14</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 26</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll26.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>C001078</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Connolly, Gerald E. [D-VA-11]</fullName>
            <firstName>Gerald</firstName>
            <lastName>Connolly</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>VA</state>
            <middleName>E.</middleName>
            <district>11</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2015-01-13T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>114</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>185</number>
          <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>8</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:07:14</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the Connolly amendment (A004) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 248 (Roll no. 26).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>26</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:07:14Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll026.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:14:46</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Connolly. (consideration: CR H266-267, H269-270; text: CR H266)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:07:14</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Connolly amendment (A004) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 248 (Roll no. 26).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>26</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:07:14Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll026.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:07:14</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>26</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:07:14Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll026.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:07:14</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>77000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>26</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:07:14Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll026.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:14:46</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Connolly.(consideration: CR H266-267, H269-270; text: CR H266)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>4</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>Amendment sought to exempt from the bill all rules promulgated by the Department of Homeland Security.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment sought to exempt from the bill all rules promulgated by the Department of Homeland Security.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2020-12-15T18:00:00Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 176 - 249 (Roll no. 25).</text>
          <actionTime>17:02:13</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 25</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll25.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>J000032</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Jackson Lee, Sheila [D-TX-18]</fullName>
            <firstName>SHEILA</firstName>
            <lastName>JACKSON LEE</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>TX</state>
            <district>18</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2015-01-13T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>114</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>185</number>
          <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>8</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:02:13</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 176 - 249 (Roll no. 25).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>25</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:02:13Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll025.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:06:55</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee. (consideration: CR H263-266, H268-269; text: CR H263-264)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:02:13</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson Lee amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 176 - 249 (Roll no. 25).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>25</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:02:13Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll025.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:02:13</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>25</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:02:13Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll025.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>17:02:13</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>77000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>25</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T22:02:13Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll025.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:06:55</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Jackson Lee.(consideration: CR H263-266, H268-269; text: CR H263-264)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>3</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part A of House Report 114-2 to exempt from H.R. 185 all rules or guidance that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines would result in net job creation.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment sought to exempt from the bill all rules or guidance that the Director of OMB determines would result in net job creation.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2020-12-15T18:00:00Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the Johnson (GA) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 247 (Roll no. 24).</text>
          <actionTime>16:57:57</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 24</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll24.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>J000288</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. Johnson, Henry C. "Hank," Jr. [D-GA-4]</fullName>
            <firstName>Henry</firstName>
            <lastName>Johnson</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>GA</state>
            <middleName>C. "Hank"</middleName>
            <district>4</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2015-01-13T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>114</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>185</number>
          <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>8</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:57:57</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the Johnson (GA) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 247 (Roll no. 24).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>24</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:57:57Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll024.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:58:32</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Johnson (GA). (consideration: CR H262-263, H268; text: CR H262)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:57:57</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Johnson (GA) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 247 (Roll no. 24).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>73000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>24</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:57:57Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll024.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:57:57</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>24</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:57:57Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll024.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:57:57</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>77000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>24</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:57:57Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll024.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:58:32</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Johnson (GA).(consideration: CR H262-263, H268; text: CR H262)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
      <amendment>
        <number>2</number>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in Part A of House Report 114-2 to ensure that the Agencies, when developing regulations, take into consideration and account for low-income populations. Furthermore, the Amendment provides that no particular class or race is excluded when it comes to looking at costs and benefits of the regulation.</description>
        <purpose>Amendment ensures that the Agencies, when developing regulations, must take into consideration and account for, low-income populations. Amendment also provides that no particular class or race is excluded when it comes to looking at costs and benefits of the regulation.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2020-12-15T18:00:00Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
          <text>On agreeing to the McKinley amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 254 - 168 (Roll no. 23).</text>
          <actionTime>16:50:22</actionTime>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>Roll no. 23</name>
              <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll23.xml</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>M001180</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Rep. McKinley, David B. [R-WV-1]</fullName>
            <firstName>David</firstName>
            <lastName>McKinley</lastName>
            <party>R</party>
            <state>WV</state>
            <middleName>B.</middleName>
            <district>1</district>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2015-01-13T05:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>114</congress>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <number>185</number>
          <title>Regulatory Accountability Act of 2015</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:29:14Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>8</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:50:22</actionTime>
              <text>On agreeing to the McKinley amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 254 - 168 (Roll no. 23).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H32111</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>23</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:50:22Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll023.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:46:06</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. McKinley. (consideration: CR H260-262, H267-268; text: CR H260)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>H3A100</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>2</code>
                <name>House floor actions</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:50:22</actionTime>
              <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>75000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>23</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:50:22Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll023.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:50:22</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the McKinley amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 254 - 168 (Roll no. 23).</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>72000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>23</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:50:22Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll023.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>16:50:22</actionTime>
              <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>76000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <recordedVotes>
                <recordedVote>
                  <rollNumber>23</rollNumber>
                  <chamber>House</chamber>
                  <congress>114</congress>
                  <date>2015-01-13T21:50:22Z</date>
                  <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
                  <url>https://clerk.house.gov/evs/2015/roll023.xml</url>
                </recordedVote>
              </recordedVotes>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <actionTime>15:46:06</actionTime>
              <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. McKinley.(consideration: CR H260-262, H267-268; text: CR H260)</text>
              <type>NotUsed</type>
              <actionCode>71500</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2015-01-13</actionDate>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Referred in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-01-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr185rfs/xml/BILLS-114hr185rfs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in House</type>
        <date>2015-01-13T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr185eh/xml/BILLS-114hr185eh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2015-01-07T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr185ih/xml/BILLS-114hr185ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-01-16</actionDate>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
