<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5000</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:31:36Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:31:36Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-04-20</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 162, Number 61 (Wednesday, April 20, 2016)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. GRAYSON:H.R. 5000.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, of the United States Constitution.[Page H1897]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed02</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2016-09-19T14:52:32Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-04-20T14:01:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Workplace Democracy Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>3690</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-03-23</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Workplace Democracy Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2142</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-10-06</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Clean Energy Worker Just Transition Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>2398</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2015-12-10</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed02</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
            <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000556</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Grayson, Alan [D-FL-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>Alan</firstName>
        <lastName>Grayson</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <district>9</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment discrimination and employee rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor-management relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Labor and Employment</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-04-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-05-16T18:53:46Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Employee Free Choice Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to require the National Labor Relations Board to certify, without an election, an individual or labor organization to be the exclusive representative of the employees in a unit appropriate for bargaining if a majority of the employees has signed valid authorizations designating the individual or labor organization specified in a properly filed petition as their bargaining representative, and no other individual or labor organization is currently certified or recognized as the exclusive representative of any of the employees in the unit.</p> <p>The Board shall develop guidelines and procedures for the designation by employees of a bargaining representative.</p> <p>Whenever collective bargaining is for the purpose of establishing an initial agreement involving a newly organized or certified employee representative, the requirements for bargaining collectively shall be modified. The parties shall meet to bargain collectively within 10 days after the employer receives a written request. The Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS) shall use its best efforts, by mediation and conciliation, to bring the parties to agreement if 90 days lapse without settlement of a dispute. If such efforts fail for 30 days, the FMCS shall refer the dispute to an arbitration panel, whose decision shall bind the parties for two years, unless the parties consent to a different time period.</p> <p> The preliminary investigation of charges involving employer discrimination or unfair labor practices while employees of that employer were seeking representation by a labor organization shall be made forthwith and given priority over all other cases except cases of like character in the office where the charge is filed or to which it is referred.</p> <p>The Board shall award an employee back pay and, in addition, twice that amount as liquidated damages if it finds that the employer has discriminated against the employee either during the period while the employer's employees were seeking representation by a labor organization, or during the period from the time a labor organization was recognized as a representative until the first collective bargaining contract between the employer and the representative was entered into.</p> <p> Any employer who willfully or repeatedly commits any unfair labor practice during these periods shall, in addition to any make-whole remedy ordered, be subject to a civil penalty of up to $20,000 for each violation. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Employee Free Choice Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Employee Free Choice Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the National Labor Relations Act to establish an efficient system to enable employees to form, join, or assist labor organizations, to provide for mandatory injunctions for unfair labor practices during organizing efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Employee Free Choice Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2016-04-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr5000ih/xml/BILLS-114hr5000ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-19</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
