<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>953</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:27:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:27:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-04-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-04-15T18:43:26Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>1815</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-06-08</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-04-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001041</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Heller, Dean [R-NV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Dean</firstName>
        <lastName>Heller</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000146</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reid, Harry [D-NV]</fullName>
        <firstName>HARRY</firstName>
        <lastName>REID</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2015-04-15</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nevada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>User charges and fees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-04-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-05-06T21:51:51Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</b></p> <p> Amends the Lincoln County Land Act of 2000 (the Act) to require implementation of a multispecies habitat conservation plan in Lincoln County, Nevada. </p> <p>Amends the Act and the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 to make certain amounts available for comprehensive, cost-effective, and multijurisdictional hazardous fuels reduction projects and wildfire prevention planning (particularly for pinyon-juniper dominated landscapes) and other rangeland and woodland restoration projects within the county, consistent with the Ely Resource Management Plan and subject to approval by the Department of the Interior. </p> <p>Requires establishment of cooperative agreements between the Bureau of Land Management and Lincoln County for certain county-provided law enforcement and planning related activities. </p> <p>Requires the use of a portion of proceeds from land sales under both Acts for the Lincoln County Regional Development Authority or any other county economic development organization. </p> <p>Excludes specified public land within certain utility corridors in Lincoln and Clark Counties, Nevada, from being withdrawn from public land, mining, and mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws. </p> <p>Amends the Pam White Wilderness Act to adjust the boundary of the Mt. Moriah Wilderness to include specified lands. Adjusts the boundary of the High Schells Wilderness to include and exclude specified lands. </p> <p>Amends the Nevada Wilderness Protection Act of 1989 to adjust the boundary of the Arc Dome Wilderness to exclude specified land. </p> <p>Amends the Mesquite Lands Act of 1988 to require the proceeds of the sales of certain parcels of land by Interior to the city of Mesquite, Nevada, to be made available for use for the development and implementation of a conservation plan to benefit fish and wildlife species of the Virgin River in Clark County (rather than, as currently, for development of a multispecies habitat conservation plan).</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to facilitate certain pinyon-juniper related projects in Lincoln County, Nevada, to modify the boundaries of certain wilderness areas in the State of Nevada, and to provide for the implementation of a conservation plan for the Virgin River, Nevada.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Eastern Nevada Land Implementation Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2015-04-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s953is/xml/BILLS-114s953is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-04-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
