<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4188</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:45:40Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:45:40Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2020-07-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg07</systemCode>
            <name>Water and Power Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2020-07-22T18:30:04Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2020-07-02T20:12:16Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-07-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg07</systemCode>
            <name>Water and Power Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-375.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-07-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-07-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001075</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Harris, Kamala D. [D-CA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Kamala</firstName>
        <lastName>Harris</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <middleName>D.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Water Resources Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2020-07-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2020-08-23T21:10:51Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Water for Tomorrow Act of 2020</b></p> <p>This bill provides assistance for water resources development and ecosystem protection and restoration projects in western states.</p> <p>Specifically, among other things, the bill requires the Department of the Interior to provide assistance to water supply projects that would contribute to a safe, adequate water supply for domestic, agricultural, environmental, municipal, or industrial use. Interior must also award grants to help disadvantaged communities with populations of 60,000 or less&nbsp;meet specified drinking water standards or&nbsp;address a significant decline in quantity or quality of drinking water. Further, the bill reauthorizes through FY2026 the&nbsp;rural water supply program,&nbsp;reauthorizes through FY2025 the cooperative watershed management program, permanently reauthorizes certain&nbsp;water management improvement grants,&nbsp;and modifies provisions related to&nbsp;funding for water recycling and reuse projects.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill requires Interior to award grants for habitat restoration projects that improve watershed health to entities with water or power delivery authority. Interior may also enter into agreements to fund aquatic ecosystem restoration and protection projects if they are likely to improve the quality of the environment by improving fish passage. Further, the bill requires the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service to develop, and update every three years, a plan to sustain the survival of critically important fisheries within western states during future periods of extended drought.</p> <p>The bill also requires Interior to incorporate information from emerging technologies for snowpack measurement when determining water supply allocations and to study the projected impact of climate change on the safety of Bureau of Reclamation dams. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Water for Tomorrow Act of 2020</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Water for Tomorrow Act of 2020</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Water for Tomorrow Act of 2020</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for drought preparedness and improved water supply reliability, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2020-07-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116s4188is/xml/BILLS-116s4188is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2020-07-22</actionDate>
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-375.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
