<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2802</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:25:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:25:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-09-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-09-15T18:22:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5589-5590)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reed, Jack [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Reed</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001230</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Baldwin, Tammy [D-WI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Tammy</firstName>
        <lastName>Baldwin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-09-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Academic performance and assessments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Adult education and literacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Census and government statistics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computers and information technology</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2014-11-18T20:14:28Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Strengthening Research in Adult Education Act - Amends the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 to revise the mission statement for the Institute of Education Sciences of the Department of Education to ensure access to, and opportunities for, adult education and literacy activities.</p> <p>Revises the composition of presidential appointees to the National Board for Education Sciences to include adult educators.</p> <p>Revises the mission statement for the Institute's National Center for Education Research (Research Center) to include improving the literacy and numeracy skills of individuals who need adult education. </p> <p>Revises also the Research Center's duties to include research on successful state and local adult education and literacy activities that:</p> <ul> <li> result in increased literacy, numeracy, and educational attainment for adult learners, or</li> <li>prepare students for postsecondary education or employment.</li> </ul> <p>Directs the Research Commissioner to support, through national research and development centers or through other means, research on adult education and digital literacy.</p> <p>Revises duties of the National Center for Education Statistics to require it to include in the statistical data on education in the United States it collects, analyzes, and disseminates data on access to, and opportunity for, adult education and literacy activities.</p> <p>Requires the National Center for Education and Regional Assistance to disseminate widely certain educational information with respect to educational practices that improve digital literacy.</p> <p>Amends the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 to revise the composition of regional advisory committees to include representatives of local or regional adult education providers.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Strengthening Research in Adult Education Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Research in Adult Education Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 and the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 to strengthen research in adult education.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Strengthening Research in Adult Education Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-09-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s2802is/xml/BILLS-113s2802is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-09-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
