<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3412</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:33:31Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:33:31Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-09-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-09-28T17:07:31Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2016</title>
        <congress>114</congress>
        <number>6269</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000133</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Markey, Edward J. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Edward</firstName>
        <lastName>Markey</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-10-19T15:34:01Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2016</b></p> <p>This bill bans food containers composed, in whole or in part, of bisphenol A (BPA). </p> <p>The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) may grant waivers to a facility for a particular product if the facility: (1) demonstrates that it is not technologically feasible to replace BPA in the container or to use a BPA-free container, and (2) submits to the FDA a plan and time line for removing BPA from the container. Products granted a waiver must include a warning on the label.</p> <p>The FDA must promote and facilitate the use of BPA replacements. BPA may not be replaced with substances that: (1) are known or likely human carcinogens; (2) have been found by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to be persistent, bioaccumulative, and toxic; (3) cause reproductive or developmental toxicity; or (4) are endocrine disrupting chemicals.</p> <p>The FDA must review substances that may be found in food, including food additives and food contact substances, and take remedial action if it does not determine that there is a reasonable certainty that no harm will result from aggregate exposure, taking into consideration potential adverse effects from low-dose exposure and the effects on vulnerable populations and populations with high exposure. </p> This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the manufacturer or supplier of a food contact substance to notify the FDA of the identity and intended use of the substance prior to its introduction into interstate commerce and that: (1) no adverse health effects result from low-dose exposures to the substance, and (2) the substance has not been shown to cause reproductive or developmental toxicity in humans or animals.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2016</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to ban the use of bisphenol A in food containers, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Ban Poisonous Additives Act of 2016</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-09-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s3412is/xml/BILLS-114s3412is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-09-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
