<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1943</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:27:03Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:27:03Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2014-01-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2014-01-16T20:58:28Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>IN STATE Act of 2014</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>3921</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2014-03-20</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2014-01-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001042</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hirono, Mazie K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mazie</firstName>
        <lastName>Hirono</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>K.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-01-16</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001194</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Schatz, Brian [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Brian</firstName>
        <lastName>Schatz</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2014-02-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Immigration</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Citizenship and naturalization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigration status and procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>User charges and fees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Visas and passports</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Immigration</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2014-01-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-04-09T14:19:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Investing in States to Achieve Tuition Equality for Dreamers Act of 2014 or the IN-STATE Act of 2014 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to allot grants to states to offer Dreamer students in-state tuition and expand their access to in-state financial aid.</p> <p>Defines a "Dreamer student" as an individual who:</p> <ul> <li>was under age 16 upon entering this country;</li> <li>has provided a list of each secondary school the individual attended in this country; and</li> <li>has earned a high school diploma or certain similar credentials, or is scheduled to complete the requirements for such a credential before the next academic year begins;</li> <li>has acquired a degree from an institution of higher education (IHE) or has successfully completed at least 2 years of a program for a bachelor's or higher degree in this country; or</li> <li>has served honorably in the uniformed services for at least 4 years. </li> </ul> <p>Directs the Secretary to provide for a hardship exception to either or both of the first two of such requirements.</p> <p>Requires grant applicants to assure the Secretary that they: (1) have made significant progress in establishing a preschool through postsecondary education (P-16) longitudinal data system; (2) will not discriminate against Dreamer students in awarding student aid or determining who is eligible for in-state tuition, if the student would otherwise be eligible for in-state financial aid as a state resident; and (3) will maintain, through FY 2023, at least their FY2013 level of support for their public IHEs.</p> <p>Allots grants to each state based on its proportion of resident Dreamer students who are enrolled at least half-time in postsecondary education.</p> <p>Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to collect a specified fee from recipients of F-1 visas, provided to nonimmigrant full-time students.</p> <p>Eliminates the prohibition on states offering unlawful aliens postsecondary benefits on the basis of their residence in the state that are more generous than those offered citizens or naturals of this country, without regard to their state residence.</p> <p>Allows individuals who have served honorably in the U.S. Armed Forces to be naturalized without having been lawfully admitted to this country for permanent residence.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Investing in States to Achieve Tuition Equality for Dreamers Act of 2014</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Investing in States to Achieve Tuition Equality for Dreamers Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Investing in States to Achieve Tuition Equality for Dreamers Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>IN-STATE for Dreamers Act of 2014</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to incentivize State support for postsecondary education and to promote increased access and affordability for higher education for students, including Dreamer students.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2014-01-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s1943is/xml/BILLS-113s1943is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2014-01-16</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
