<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3202</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-09T00:28:51Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-09T00:28:51Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2020-01-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2020-01-16T15:54:16Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-01-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2020-01-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001113</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cortez Masto, Catherine [D-NV]</fullName>
        <firstName>Catherine</firstName>
        <lastName>Cortez Masto</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2020-01-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2020-10-17T15:28:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>End Speculative Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 2020</b></p> <p>This bill specifies requirements for the leasing of oil and gas resources on federal lands. </p> <p>The Bureau of Land Management (BLM), with respect to certain federal land that is covered by a reasonably foreseeable development scenario (i.e., a long-term projection of oil and gas development) shall not offer the land for lease until such scenario includes an assessment of the land's oil and gas potential that specifically identifies the potential for all acres subject to decisions on availability for leasing.</p> <p>If certain federal land that is otherwise available for leasing of oil and gas resources is not covered by a reasonably foreseeable development scenario, the BLM shall complete such a scenario in accordance with the requirements and factors described in this bill. </p> <p>In general, the BLM shall not offer for lease certain federal land otherwise available for leasing of oil and gas resources if such land is designated in the applicable reasonably foreseeable development scenario as having low or no potential for the development of oil or gas resources. However, the bill provides for a variance process.</p> <p>With respect to each of these requirements, exceptions apply for federal land that is leased for the purpose of preventing oil or gas drainage or that meets specified requirements related to size and proximity to an oil- or gas-producing well.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>End Speculative Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 2020</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>End Speculative Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 2020</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>End Speculative Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 2020</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to discourage speculative oil and gas leasing and to promote enhanced multiple use management of public land and National Forest System land, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2020-01-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116s3202is/xml/BILLS-116s3202is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2020-01-16</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
