<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4625</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-01T13:49:42Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-01T13:49:42Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2019-10-08</introducedDate>
    <congress>116</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 165, Number 160 (Tuesday, October 8, 2019)][House]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href="http://www.gpo.gov">www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. LEVIN of California:H.R. 4625.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Clause 18 of Section 8 of Article I of the Constitution[Page H8101]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2019-11-13T16:13:15Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr10</systemCode>
            <name>Economic Opportunity Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Discharged from</name>
                <date>2019-10-16T19:57:41Z</date>
              </item>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2019-10-14T13:25:40Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2019-10-16T20:04:19Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2019-10-08T17:04:35Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Student Veteran Protection Act</title>
        <congress>116</congress>
        <number>4654</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2019-10-11</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Reserve and Guard GI Bill Housing Fairness Act</title>
        <congress>116</congress>
        <number>4312</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2019-09-24</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-13</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:26:21</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:26:18</actionTime>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H8746-8749)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:26:18</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H8746-8749)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:06:34</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4625.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:06:33</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H8746-8751)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionTime>16:06:20</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity Discharged.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr10</systemCode>
            <name>Economic Opportunity Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-08</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsvr00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2019-10-08</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000593</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Levin, Mike [D-CA-49]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Levin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>49</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001068</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Cohen, Steve [D-TN-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>Steve</firstName>
        <lastName>Cohen</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>TN</state>
        <district>9</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2019-11-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2019-11-08T16:05:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4625, Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/55833</url>
        <description>As ordered reported by the House Committee on Veterans’ Affairs on October 16, 2019</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12T22:07:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4625, Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/55843</url>
        <description>As Posted to the Website of the House Majority Leader, dated November 8, 2019</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2019-11-12T22:07:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 4625, Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/55843</url>
        <description>As Posted to the Website of the House Majority Leader, dated November 8, 2019</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marketing and advertising</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2019-10-08</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2020-04-14T20:22:35Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Protect the GI Bill Act</b></p> <p>This bill imposes requirements and restrictions on educational institutions participating in the educational assistance programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). </p> <p>The bill limits participation in VA educational assistance programs if an educational institution (1) does not perform specified actions, such as providing cost information to individuals prior to enrollment; (2) implements fraudulent recruiting techniques or pays inducements to secure enrollments; or (3) is the subject of a negative action by its accrediting agency. The state approving agency or the VA shall impose limitations by publishing a warning or temporarily prohibiting the pursuit of a course of education at an institution.</p> <p>The bill provides for waivers of certain requirements for a one-year period, but waivers may not be provided for more than two consecutive academic years.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits the VA from approving the enrollment of an eligible veteran or eligible person in any course offered by an institution engaged in substantial misrepresentation (e.g., misrepresenting the size, location, facilities, or equipment of the institution).</p> <p>Finally, the bill modifies the criteria that non-accredited courses must meet to be eligible for educational assistance. The bill adds requirements for (1) the educational institution offering the course to refrain from substantial misrepresentation; and (2) the state approving agency to review advertising, sales, or enrollment materials used by the institution.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>53</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2019-11-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2022-03-01T14:21:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Protect the GI Bill Act</b></p> <p>This bill makes various updates to the administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs' (VA) educational assistance programs.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) First, the bill specifies that educational assistance is payable for programs of education leading to a degree that is pursued on active duty if the active duty is for a period of more than 30 days.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The VA shall require each educational institution to submit monthly verification of each individual who is enrolled in a course or program of education and receiving educational assistance. Individuals must also submit a monthly verification of enrollment. If an individual fails to verify for two consecutive months, the VA may not make a monthly stipend payment until the individual submits such verification. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill expands the list of dependents that qualify as eligible dependents for purposes of transfer of education benefits under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program. Under the bill, an individual may transfer an entitlement to educational assistance to an eligible dependent or combination of eligible dependents.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill also expands the reasons for which a course of education may be disapproved in relation to VA education benefits. Specifically, a program offered by an educational institution that is at risk of losing accreditation shall not be deemed approved.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill requires the VA to notify a state approving agency when certain actions or events take place, such as final punitive action being taken against an educational institution. Additionally, the state approving agency must provide notice to the VA and other state approving agencies if it disapproves or suspends an educational institution.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) In order to approve an accredited program, the VA (or state approving agency) must find the educational institution is approved and participates in a federal student financial aid program (or has had such requirement waived).</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill requires certain non-accredited law programs to be accredited by a specialized accrediting agency in order to be approved for the administration of educational benefits. </p> <p>The bill permits the approval of certain non-accredited courses related to the practice of law if such courses are accredited by a specialized accrediting agency recognized by the Department of Education.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) The bill provides that an approved course that fails to comply with a risk-based survey requirement shall be immediately disapproved by the VA or state approving agency.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) The bill limits participation in VA educational assistance programs if an educational institution (1) does not perform specified actions, such as providing estimated cost information to individuals prior to enrollment; (2) implements deceptive recruiting techniques or pays inducements to secure enrollments; or (3) is the subject of a negative action by its accrediting agency. The state approving agency or the VA may impose limitations by publishing a warning or temporarily prohibiting the pursuit of a course of education at an institution.</p> <p>The bill provides for waivers of certain requirements for a one-year period, but waivers may not be provided for more than two consecutive academic years.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) The bill provides that overpayments made by an educational institution to a veteran or eligible person shall constitute a liability of the educational institution if the payment is made as a payment of established charges to educational institutions, advance payment of initial educational assistance or subsistence allowance, or a public-private contribution for additional education assistance.</p> <p>(Sec. 12) The bill also prohibits the VA or a state approving agency from approving the enrollment of an eligible veteran or eligible person in any course offered by an institution engaged in substantial misrepresentation (e.g., misrepresenting the size, location, facilities, or equipment of the institution).</p> <p>The bill modifies the criteria that non-accredited courses must meet to be eligible for educational assistance. The bill adds requirements for (1) the educational institution offering the course to refrain from substantial misrepresentation; (2) the state approving agency to review advertising, sales, or enrollment materials used by the institution; and (3) the state approving agency to verify that no federal department or agency has taken a punitive action against the school for misleading or deceptive practices.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) After a state or federal department or agency takes final punitive action against an educational institution for substantial misrepresentation, the bill authorizes the VA or state approving agency to (1) publish a warning or temporarily prohibit the pursuit of a course of education at an institution, or (2) disapprove each course offered by that institution.</p> <p>(Sec. 14) Under the bill, an individual enrolled in a course or program of education that closed or was discontinued who transfers fewer than 12 credits from such a program shall be deemed to not have received such credits and shall not have their entitlement to educational assistance charged during that period of enrollment.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <billTextVersionName>Engrossed in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>EH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to require that educational institutions abide by certain principles as a condition of approval for purposes of the educational assistance programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Engrossed in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>EH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <title>Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Protect the GI Bill Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Referred in Senate</type>
        <date>2019-11-13T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116hr4625rfs/xml/BILLS-116hr4625rfs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in House</type>
        <date>2019-11-12T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116hr4625eh/xml/BILLS-116hr4625eh.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2019-10-08T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-116hr4625ih/xml/BILLS-116hr4625ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2019-11-13</actionDate>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
