<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2626</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:31:46Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:31:46Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2016-03-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sssb00</systemCode>
        <name>Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2016-03-10T15:00:00Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2016-03-03T17:29:33Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sssb00</systemCode>
            <name>Small Business and Entrepreneurship Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-635.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2016-03-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Peters, Gary C. [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Gary</firstName>
        <lastName>Peters</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000934</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Moran, Jerry [R-KS]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jerry</firstName>
        <lastName>Moran</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KS</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2016-03-03</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accidents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aviation and airports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2016-03-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2016-05-25T18:02:32Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Higher Education Unmanned Aircraft Systems Modernization Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to authorize an institution of higher education to operate an unmanned aircraft system within the United States without the specific approval of, and without registering the system with, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) if:</p> <ul> <li>the institution has adopted a policy to ensure safe operation of such systems, which shall include the designation of a point of contact at the institution for review and approval of such operation and the requirement that such operation be conducted under the supervision of an operator in command; </li> <li>the point of contact has confirmed that the proposed operation is for educational or research purposes, is in accordance with applicable policies of the institution regarding safety, training or supervision requirements, privacy, and prior notice and permission, and will occur under the supervision of an operator in command;</li> <li>the system is operated not higher than 400 feet above ground level and in a manner that will not create a hazard to persons or property, is marked with the identification and contact information of the owner, does not survey, create a nuisance on, or overfly private property without the permission of the property owner, gives right of way to, and avoids flying in the proximity of, full-scale aircraft, and is operated at a site that is of sufficient distance from populated areas to protect the safety of persons and property; and </li> <li> the institution notifies and obtains permission, at least annually, from air traffic control or the airport manager (for small facilities) when the system will be operated within five statute miles of an airport around which the airspace is designated as class B or class C airspace, within two statute miles of any other airport or heliport, or within airspace designated as restricted or prohibited.</li> </ul> <p>If an unmanned aircraft system operated by an institution of higher education is involved in any incident resulting in personal injury or property damage (other than to the system, to property of the institution, or to individuals directly involved in the system's operation), the point of contact shall report the incident to the FAA within 10 days.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Higher Education Unmanned Aircraft Systems Modernization Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Higher Education Unmanned Aircraft Systems Modernization Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize the operation of unmanned aircraft systems by institutions of higher education for educational and research purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Higher Education Unmanned Aircraft Systems Modernization Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2016-03-03T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114s2626is/xml/BILLS-114s2626is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2016-03-10</actionDate>
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-635.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
