<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>431</number>
    <updateDate>2022-11-15T16:34:57Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-11-15T16:34:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2013-02-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>113</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2013-02-28T23:02:04Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Asia-South Pacific Trade Preferences Act</title>
        <congress>113</congress>
        <number>432</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1029)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000062</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Feinstein, Dianne [D-CA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Dianne</firstName>
        <lastName>Feinstein</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Asia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nepal</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tariffs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>U.S. and foreign investments</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2013-04-24T19:58:18Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Nepal Trade Preferences Act - Authorizes the President to give preferential treatment to certain articles imported directly from Nepal into the U.S. customs territory if that country meets certain requirements under the African Growth and Opportunity Act, including a market-based economy and the rule of law, the protection of human rights and internationally-recognized worker rights, elimination of trade barriers to the United States, and non-engagement in activities that undermine U.S. national security or foreign policy interests or support acts of international terrorism. Requires Nepal also to meet certain eligibility criteria for designation as a beneficiary developing country under the Trade Act of 1974.</p> <p>Authorizes certain import-sensitive articles (watches, electronic articles, steel articles, footwear and certain other apparel, and glass products) imported directly from Nepal to enter the U.S. customs territory duty-free if: (1) the article is the growth, product, or manufacture of Nepal; (2) the President determines, after receiving advice from the U.S. International Trade Commission (USITC), that the article is not import-sensitive; and (3) the sum of the cost or value of the materials produced in, and the manufacturing costs performed in, Nepal or the U.S. customs territory is at least 35% of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered. Limits to 15% of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered the cost or value of the materials produced in, and the manufacturing costs performed in, the U.S. customs territory, and attributed to the 35% requirement.</p> <p>Grants duty-free treatment to certain textile or apparel articles: (1) wholly assembled in Nepal, without regard to the country of origin of the yarn or fabric used to make them; and (2) imported directly from Nepal into the U.S. customs territory. </p> <p>Prescribes requirements for handloomed, handmade, folklore articles or ethnic printed fabrics.</p> <p>Terminates the extension of preferential treatment to Nepal after December 31, 2023. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Nepal Trade Preferences Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Nepal Trade Preferences Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Nepal Trade Preferences Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize preferential treatment for certain imports from Nepal, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2013-02-28T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-113s431is/xml/BILLS-113s431is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2013-02-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
