<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2953</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:30:35Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:30:35Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2015-07-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>114</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Congressional Record Volume 161, Number 104 (Tuesday, July 7, 2015)]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. CARNEY:H.R. 2953.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 18The Congress shall have Power * * * To make all Laws whichshall be necessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers, and all other Powers vested by theConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.Article I, Section 8, Clause 3The Congress shall have Power * * * To regulate Commercewith foreign Nations, and among the several States, and withthe Indian Tribes.[Page H4861]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
        <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2015-07-07T18:00:47Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-07</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsba00</systemCode>
            <name>Financial Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2015-07-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001083</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Carney, John C., Jr. [D-DE-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Carney</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>C.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and community development funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Low- and moderate-income housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public housing</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2015-07-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2015-09-14T16:17:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Housing Assistance Reform Act of 2015</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to increase the number of public housing agencies (PHAs) authorized to participate in the Moving to Work demonstration program by adding to it up to 60 high-performing, high-capacity PHAs, for a total of up to 300,000 housing vouchers and public housing units, over five years, to test and evaluate innovative models for improving economic self-sufficiency, mobility, academic performance, and other outcomes for tenants assisted by HUD.</p> <p>Selected PHAs may not receive more funding under low-income housing assistance, the Capital Fund, or the Operating Fund of the United States Housing Act of 1937 than they otherwise would have received without designation as a high performer under the public housing assessment system and the Section 8 (low-income housing assistance) management assessment program.</p> <p>If a PHA participating in the program before enactment of this Act has complied with the terms of its Moving to Work agreement, then HUD:</p> <ul> <li>must extend the PHA's agreement under the same terms in effect on the agreement's date of expiration, and</li> <li>may not alter the formula allocation for the agency's funding.</li> </ul> <p>There shall no longer be any limitation, under the Rental Assistance Demonstration specified in the Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2012 (as amended), on the number of PHA and certain other multifamily housing units receiving Public Housing Capital and Operating Funds assistance or low-income moderate rehabilitation program assistance that may be converted to tenant-based or project-based rental assistance units.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Housing Assistance Reform Act of 2015</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Housing Assistance Reform Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To expand the Moving to Work and Rental Assistance demonstration programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Housing Assistance Reform Act of 2015</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2015-07-07T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-114hr2953ih/xml/BILLS-114hr2953ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2015-07-07</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
