<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1145</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:36:27Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:36:27Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2017-05-17</introducedDate>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2017-05-17T15:00:46Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</title>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>2675</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-05-25</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-05-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-05-17</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000817</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warren, Elizabeth [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Elizabeth</firstName>
        <lastName>Warren</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>A.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000575</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lankford, James [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Lankford</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-05-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax deductions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legal fees and court costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Securities</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2017-05-17</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2017-06-10T13:21:09Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><strong>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill sets forth new requirements for the public disclosure of any covered settlement agreement entered into by a federal executive agency.&nbsp; The bill defines "covered settlement agreement" as a settlement agreement (including a consent decree) that: (1) is entered into by an executive agency, (2) relates to an alleged violation of federal civil or criminal law, and (3) requires the payment of at least $1 million by one or more non-federal persons (entities not within the federal government).</p> <p>Each executive agency must make publicly available on the agency website&nbsp;a list of each covered settlement agreement entered into by the agency, which shall include:&nbsp;(1) the names of the parties to the settlement&nbsp;agreement and the date of such agreement; (2) a description of the claims that were settled under the agreement; (3) the amount each party to the agreement is obligated to pay under the terms of the agreement and the total amounts required to be paid; and (4) for each settling party, the amount the settling party is obligated to pay that has been expressly specified as a civil penalty or fine and as not deductible for tax purposes. The bill requires: (1) such information to remain publicly available for not less than 5 years, beginning on the date of the agreement; and (2) a copy of a covered settlement agreement to remain publicly available for a period of not less than 1 year, beginning on the date of the agreement, or for at least 5 years for an agreement under which a non-federal person is required to pay not less than $50 million.</p> <p>The bill limits the disclosure of provisions of a covered settlement agreement that are subject to a confidentiality agreement. </p> <p>The issuer of securities subject to reporting requirements under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 must describe in required reports any claim of a tax deduction relating to a payment under a covered settlement agreement.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require adequate information regarding the tax treatment of payments under settlement agreements entered into by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Truth in Settlements Act of 2017</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2017-05-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-115s1145is/xml/BILLS-115s1145is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-05-17</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
